Hello Congress and welcome to this lecture.
So this lecture is going to be all about S-3.
It's s 3 1 0 1 and we're going to go through all the fundamentals of S-3.
And it's one of the very first services that AWOS launched.
So it can be a massive topic for the exam and it's really important that you understand how ESRI works
and that you understand the S-3 terminology.
So let's get started.
So what is S-3 so S-3 stands for simple storage service and it provides developers and I.T. teams with
secure durable highly scalable objects storage.
So the key here is that it's object's storage.
It's really for files images the pages it's not.
So operating systems and not for databases it's really easy to use with a simple webservices interface
and it allows you to store and retrieve any amount of data from anywhere on the web.
So S3 is a safe place to store your files.
It's object by storage only.
It's not.
BLOCK storage.
And the data is spread across multiple devices and multiple facilities.
So that means that there is an element of high availability or disaster recovery already built into
the AWOS service.
And what that means is that Amazon could lose one of their devices or one of their facilities and the
S3 service will still be available.
So a faulty device or a faulty datacenter or a faulty availability so it should not take down the S3
service so you should still be able to access your files in the event of a minor fall.
So let's have a look at some of the basics.
So S-3 is object based and that means it allows you to upload object files into the cloud.
The files can be from 0 0 bytes to 5 terabytes in size and there is unlimited storage.
So this means that you don't have to worry about allocating space or predicting how many terabytes of
space you're going to need in S3.
You could just go ahead and upload the files that you need to they will take care of the capacity management
and capacity planning on your behalf.
So you can just go ahead and upload the files that you need to.
So within as three files is stored in buckets and bucket is similar to a folder it's the name that I
ws uses for the location where you're storing your files and the night with the bucket is user defined
so you can set your own bucket name so just really say it as similar to Fodor and S3 has a universal
namespace.
And that means that names or bucket names must be unique globally and it's similar to a DNS or an Internet
address.
So let's take a look at an example.
So this is our example bucket called a cloud Garou and you'll see at the beginning we have HTP s and
then S3 EU West 1.
So that just denotes that it's the S3 service.
It tells us it's in the region EU West one.
And then after Amazon AWOS dot com we see Ford slash iCloud Garou and that is the name of our bucket.
So once again as this is an Internet address it must be unique.
You can't have another bucket with the same name even if it's in a different region.
It must be unique globally.
Finally when you upload a file into S3 you're going to receive an HTP 200 code.
If the upload was successful Now this is not a code that you're going to see on your browser on your
web page if you're uploading something using the AWOS console you will not say that HTP code you'll
only see this code if you're uploading using the API or the command line interface but it's just good
to know that that is the code that you see if it's a successful upload.
So let's take a look at the data consistency model for S3.
And we have two different approaches to data consistency within S-3.
Firstly for Puts of brand new objects when we say Put that means when you initially upload an objects
into S3 for the first time.
So for Puts of new objects we have read off to right consistency and this just means that as soon as
you add your objects into S-3 as soon as you upload your file the file is available to read.
So straight away you can access your file as soon as you've uploaded it into S-3.
However if you want to change a file if you are going to overwrite the file with a new version or if
you are going to delete that file it can actually take some time to propagate around S-3.
So it's not going to be immediate and this consistency model is cold if unsure consistency.
So just remember that when you add the new object into history you can read it immediately you can read
it straightaway.
But then if you wanted to make a modification or delete that file it can just take a little bit of time
to propagate.
So S3 is a simple key value store.
And what does that mean.
Well S3 is object based and objects consist of the following.
The key which is simply the name of the object or the file name and the value.
And this is really just the data which is made up of a sequence of bytes.
There's also a version of ID which is important for versioning and S-3 does support version control.
So you can you can keep multiple versions of the same file within S-3 and that allows you to really
just go back into previous versions if you wanted to.
There's also meta data and if you haven't heard that term before.
Better data just really means data about data.
And when you upload a file into S-3 you can add your own message data.
So for example you could add the name of the team that owns that file.
You could add the project that the file is related to.
Or any other data that's meaningful to you.
We also have some resources and this is really pocket specific configuration.
So we have things like bucket policies an access control lists and we're going to go through these in
a lot more detail later on in the course but bucket policies and access control lists are really just
ways to control access to the contents of your pocket.
There's also cross origin resource sharing also known as cause.
And again we're going to go through this in more detail.
We're actually going to have a lab on cross origin resource sharing later on.
And what this is is really setting up the capability for files that were located in one bucket to access
the files within another bucket and transfer acceleration is really just a service which allows you
to accelerate file transfer speeds when you're uploading lots of files into S-3.
So let's take a look at some of the basics of S-3.
So it's built for the ninety nine point ninety nine percent availability.
The S3 platform.
So what does that mean.
So availability refers simply to the uptime.
So the amount of time the service is actually available and when we say ninety nine point nine nine
percent availability what we really mean is that it's available.
The service is there.
It's accessible.
Ninety nine point ninety nine percent of the time solo it's designed for ninety nine point ninety nine
percent availability.
Amazon actually guarantee ninety nine point nine percent availability.
They also guarantee 11 nines durability S3.
So what does your ability mean.
Well this really corresponds to the amount of data that you can expect to lose over a given year.
So we want that your ability to be as close to 100 percent as possible.
So we don't lose all files say for example you add to store 10 million objects within S3 with 11 nines
your ability on average you could expect to incur a loss of a single object once every ten thousand
years.
So thats what they mean when they say that it's a really safe place to store your data with any environment
the best practice is to always have a backup of your data.
Don't just keep it in one place.
And for us three there's a number of things we can do.
For example we can enable version control.
So that means we keep multiple versions historical versions of the same file.
So you could roll back if you lost your file you could roll back to a previous version.
You can also put in safeguards to prevent accidental deletions so you can prevent certain uses from
deleting your files and you can also replicate your data.
There are different tiers of storage available to cater for different requirements or different types
of data that you might be storing.
There is lifecycle management so that allows you to set rules around moving your data between different
storage tears.
There's also versioning so allowing you to enable version control.
We have encryption.
So there's a few different ways that you can actually encrypt your data to protect it from unauthorized
access.
And this is something we're going to go through in much more detail later on in this section and you
can secure access to your data using Access Control lists and bucket policies.
And again that's something we're going to go through in more detail later.
And we've actually got a lab all about that as well.
So let's take a look at the different S3 storage tears or storage clauses.
So the regular S3 which is suitable for most workloads and that has the ninety nine point ninety nine
percent availability 11:09 durability and it stores the data redundantly across multiple devices and
in multiple facilities and it's also designed to sustain the loss of two facilities concurrently.
So this means the S3 can sustain for example a hardware failure a device failure but not just in one
location it can actually sustain that kind of failure across multiple facilities and it can actually
sustain the loss of two data centers or two facilities.
So it's really really high availability and it means that you don't need to worry about building in
high availability for your data.
So there's also S3 I which stands for infrequently accessed.
And this is for data that is accessed less frequently but still requires rapid access when needed.
So it's data that you don't need to access on a daily basis.
Maybe could be for data that you only need to access once a year or once a quarter you pay a lot of
faith in as three but you are charged every time you retrieve that data.
So you want to make sure it really is your infrequently access data.
Otherwise you could start to see some higher charges for it.
There's also S-3 one zone I which is the same as I.
However data is stored only in a single availability sign.
Now it's still the 11:9 billeting but it's only ninety nine point five percent availability.
So that means if they lose one availability zone that means you're going to lose access to your data.
So when the availability zone comes back online you should get access to the data but you would have
lost access for the time that that availability zone was off line and the cost is 20 percent less than
the regular S-3 I.
But just be aware that you don't have that same level of availability.
There's also reduced redundancy storage and this is designed to provide a lower level of durability
so you only have ninety nine point nine nine percent and ninety nine point nine nine percent availability
of objects over a given year.
So this is really used for data that could be easily recreated if you lost it.
It's not for your mission critical data it's not for data that's going to cause a problem and you can't
recreate it if it got lost.
So a good example of the kind of data that is a good candidate for reduced redundancy storage is thumbnails.
So for example imagine you had a load of images and you wanted a place to store thumbnails of those
images.
You could store the thumbnails in the reduced redundancy storage and store the original images somewhere
more durable such as the regular S3.
Now it's worth noting that reduce redundancy storage is not actually offered in some regions.
And we have also noticed that Amazon and now recommending that you do not use this storage class they're
actually recommending that you use the standard S3 offering and they have even adjusted the pricing
so that the standard class is now more cost effective than using that would use redundancy storage.
So there's a possibility that at some point in the future they might be looking to phase out reduce
redundancy storage as an offering.
But for now we still think it's good for you to be aware of reduce redundancy storage.
It may still come up in the exam.
So it's definitely worth knowing what is and what it's used for.
Finally there's Lycia and glitzier is used for archiving.
It's very very cheap in comparison to the other three offerings and it's really optimized for data that
is very infrequently accessed because it actually takes between three and five hours to restore your
data from glossier.
So you don't want to put data in there that you think that you're going to be accessing it on a frequent
or regular basis.
It's really much more suitable for archives maybe historical files that you're not going to access very
frequently so let's take a look at this table and this table really just compares the characteristics
of the different storage classes and the main thing to remember really is the standard S3 has the highest
ability and the highest availability with standard.
I remember it as a retrieval Fav for all objects for the ones I own.
I it's only one availability zones.
That means it's not going to be resilient to the loss of unavailability.
If we lose the azy that means we lose the service.
Violacea there's no real time access.
It takes four to five hours to access your data.
And for the reduced redundancy storage that has the lowest Europe in NC and the lowest availability
and it's really for files that you can recreate if they ever got lost and there is one additional as
three storage class I want to tell you about.
And it was announced at re-invents 2018.
So at the end of November 2018 and it's called S3 intelligent taring.
And this is really most suitable for data which has an unknown or unpredictable access pattern and there
are two different tiers with S-3 intelligent taring.
So they have a frequent access taring and an infrequent access as well.
And it will automatically move your data to the most cost effective tier based on how frequently you
access each object within your bucket.
And of course the frequently access to is a little bit more expensive than the infrequently accessed
here.
So it works out as more cost effective if you can keep it frequently accessed data or infrequently accessed
storage in the infrequent access tier.
So how does it work.
Well if an object is not accessed for 30 consecutive days then it gets moved automatically to the infrequent
access here.
But then as soon as an object which is in the infrequent access to is accessed it gets automatically
moved to the frequently accessed here and S-3 intelligent tiering has the same level of jury ability
and availability as you would expect for the normal S-3 infrequently accessed.
So you've got 11 nines your ability and ninety nine point nine percent availability over a given year.
And it's a really good way to optimize your cost.
There are no fees for accessing your data or for moving the data in between tears.
But they do charge you a really small monthly fee for monitoring and automation and it's zero point
zero zero to five dollars per 1000 objects.
So it's a really small monthly fee.
So that is S-3 intelligent tiering.
As I said it was announced in November 2018 but it's just really good to be aware of.
If you are storing lots of data in S3 and you have unpredictable access patterns then the S3 intelligent
taring is one to consider.
So let's take a look at what actually charge you for in S3.
So you get charged for the amount of storage in gigabytes the number of requests you do so a get request
or put to request a copy request etc..
And there's also a fee for storage management and this includes things like inventory analytics object
tags so you can actually tag your objects according to what project they relate to or what team they
relate to.
And that really just helps with cross charging if you are going to charge that department or that team
or that project for the S3 storage that they were using.
There's also data management pricing and this really refers to data transferred out of S-3 because it's
free to transfer your data into S3.
But they do charge you when you transfer data out.
So for example if you download a file from a story you will be charged for that you also get charged
for transfer acceleration and transfer acceleration is something we're going to be talking about in
a later lecture.
But just remember transfer acceleration is something that's used to accelerate your file transfer speeds.
When you upload files into S3 it uses something called Cloud front which we're going to go into in much
more detail in a later lecture but it uses comfort front to optimize those transfers so you get a really
good upload speed.
But it is something that they charge you for.
So let's have a look at the exam tips for S-3.
Remember the S-3 is object based.
So it allows you to upload files and object files only not operating systems and not databases.
The files can be from 0 bytes to five terabytes.
There's unlimited storage so you don't need to allocate storage and you don't need to worry if AWOS
is going to run out of storage.
The files are stored in buckets or folders S3 is a universal namespace so that means that the packet
names need to be unique globally.
And here's the example of S-3 packet You're all around.
So we see HTP s and then S-3 EU west one site that just lets us know that it's in S-3 and the region
is US 1 and then forward slash.
The end just tells us that that is the packet name.
Remember the 2 data consistency model for S3.
So we have read off the right consistency for Puts of new objects and eventual consistency for either
right puts into place.
So I remember that overwrites a change to a file or a deletion of a file can take some time to propagate.
Remember the different storage classes.
So we have the regular S-3 for immediately available frequently accessed and durable storage.
We have S-3 I which is for infrequently accessed files we have the run zone I which is the same as I.
However the data is stored in a single availability zone only then there's reduced redundancy storage.
So this is for data that is easy to reproduce such as thumbnails and there's a place here for the archive
data where it's acceptable to wait between 3 and 5 hours before accessing your data.
Remember the core fundamentals of unnecessary object.
So we have the key which is the name of the file the value which is the data stored in the file version
Id met the data which is data about data and that can be user defined tasks.
Then we have said resources which is the packet specific configuration.
So things like bucket policies access control lists all this we're going to go into much more detail
later on in the course.
We have the cross origin resource sharing and transfer acceleration and all those things we're going
to go in a much more detail we're going to do labs about all three of those.
So don't worry if it doesn't make sense to you right now successful uploads would generate and TTP 200
status code and that's only when you use the say ally or the API.
Not when you use the browser and finally make sure you read the S-3 AFAIK.
And we've given the link here but it's really worth reading that because it will really help consolidate
your knowledge and it's also a really good one to read just before going into the exam or the day before
the exam.
Just to refresh your memory.
So that's the end of this lecture and our next lecture is on S-3 security.
So if you've got time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.