And I Clockers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is just a really quick update.
All about S-3 performance.
So let's get started now in July 2018 Amazon announced a massive increase in S-3 performance and on
their Web site they state that they can support at least three thousand five hundred requests per second.
So that's uploading files and five thousand five hundred gets requests per second.
So retrieving your files and this new increase performance negates the previous guidance to randomize
your object names to achieve Foster performance.
And this means that logical and sequential naming patterns can now be used without any performance implication.
Now as you probably know the Amazon ecosystem changes on a daily basis.
And as you can imagine the certification exams can sometimes become a little outdated.
All out of sync with the latest updates.
So just be aware the impact is no longer need to avoid sequential naming of us three objects but you
may still see questions in the exam related to randomising key names as mentioned in the previous lecture
and I'm so going to say the exam eventually but it just can take some weeks or months for the exams
to reflect any new updates in the services so that is the end of this lecture.
It's just a really quick one to let you know about that performance update.
If you've got any questions or feedback please let us know.
If not feel free to move onto the next lecture.
Pinky.