Hello cloud gurus and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be a summary of S3.
So it's the end of this section.
Congratulations on making it so far.
This is just gonna be all summary of everything that we've learned about S3 including all of our exam
tips.
So let's get started.
Remember that S3 is object based.
So it allows you to upload your files images documents files can be from 0 bytes to 5 terabytes in size.
And there is unlimited storage.
You don't have to worry about capacity management or capacity plumbing.
They do all of that for you.
And Amazon just add storage arrays as and when they need it.
So you don't need to worry about capacity planning and the files are stored in buckets and you should
know by now when you see bucket.
Just think folder is three is a universal namespace with globally unique names.
And here's our example below showing HECS then is S3 and the region name.
Then after Amazon AWOL Stockholm it shows us the bucket name.
So in this example a cloud guru for the consistency model we have read after right.
Consistency for puts of brand new objects into S3.
However when we overwrite that file or we change it or we delete it and you try to access the same file
immediately you may still see the older version for a while or the UN deleted version.
So any changes or deletions are not immediate.
Instead they use a model called eventual consistency for overwrite put and delete.
We have multiple different storage tiers or storage classes for S3 beginning with the regular S3.
So that is durable immediately available and suitable for frequently accessed files.
Then we have S3 II which again is durable and immediately available however it's more suitable for infrequently
access files.
We then have S3 ones own ie a and this is the same as I.
However data is stored only in a single availability zone and this means the one zone ie a service is
not as resilient.
It doesn't have the same level of availability as you get for the regular S3.
So it's good for data where a lower level of availability is acceptable and you do pay 20 percent less
than the regular S3 for this service.
We then have the S3 reduce redundancy storage.
And remember this is for data that is easily reproducible.
For example thumbnails where you own the original image and you're storing it in a different location.
And if you were to lose the thumbnail data stored in reduced redundancy storage you would easily be
able to reproduce those files.
Now reduce redundancy storage used to be more cost effective than the regular S3.
However that has now changed and Amazon are now recommending that for most workloads we use the regular
S3.
However we do think it's worth knowing for the exam.
Finally we have Glacier which is used for archiving and is most suitable for situations where it's acceptable
to wait between 3 and 5 hours before accessing your storage.
So glacier is most appropriate to use for historical files archive data files that you don't need to
access very frequently and when you do access them you can wait between three to five hours.
Remember the core fundamentals of an S3 object so you have the key which is the name of the file.
The value which is the data contained within the file version I.D. metadata which is data about data
and then we have sub resources which are used to manage the bucket specific configuration.
For example bucket policies and access control lists which are used to control both of those are used
to control access to your buckets and the contents of your bucket cross origin resource sharing.
So remember that's when we enable the contents of one bucket to see the contents of another bucket or
more widely when we allow one resource to access another resource within AWB.
And there's also transfer acceleration and transfer acceleration simply speeds up the uploads of objects
into S3 utilizing the cloud front network of edge locations.
Remember the S3 is for object storage only so it's only for files not suitable for operating systems
not suitable for databases and successful uploads will generate the ATP 200 status code in terms of
security all newly created buckets are private.
So by default there is no public access to your buckets when you initially create them.
You can set up access control in your buckets using bucket policies and these are applied at a bucket
level.
So that means they apply to the bucket and the contents of the bucket.
You also have access control lists and these are applied on an object level so you can create an access
control list which only applies to an individual object and you can have different access control lists
applied to different objects within the same bucket.
And if you want to keep a record of all the different requests made to the S3 bucket you can do that
using access logs and these can be configured on the bucket and either written to the same bucket or
written into another bucket and these will capture all of the access requests made into your bucket
as three supports a number of different types of encryption.
So we have encryption in transit and that is via SSL or TALF and this is when any request made into
S3 is encrypted in transit or encrypted on the network and we can see that when we make a request into
a pocket using HECS and there is also encryption at rest.
And for encryption at rest we have either server side encryption or client side encryption and for server
side encryption.
There are three different options.
We have the SSA S3 and this is where each object is encrypted with a unique key using strong multi factor
encryption and the keys are managed within S3 and a W S manage this end to end.
So they do all of the encryption for you and decryption and SSA S3 is also sometimes called advanced
encryption standard 256 bit SSA KLM s is similar to SSA S3 but with some added benefits so you get the
separate permissions for an envelope key and this envelope key protects your data's encryption key giving
you added protection against unauthorized access to your objects within S3.
And this also gives you an audit trail telling you when keys were used and by whom and if you're playing
around with SC S3 SC came mess depending on what you're doing you might see some charges within your
account.
So just be aware of that and make sure that once you finish setting something up and once you understand
how it works just remember to go in and delete all those resources SNCC.
So this is the customer provided key where you manage your own key and a W S just take care of the encryption
and decryption process so they decrypt it for you when you want to read your files but ultimately the
key belongs to you and you have to manage the key so you have to manage its lifecycle when it expires.
You have to manage rotating the key yourself.
So just remember those three different types of server side encryption and remember the differences
between them and then you should be able to answer any question that they throw at you in the exam.
We also have client side encryption.
So this is where you encrypt the file on your own platform before you actually upload it into S3.
So you can encrypt it by any mechanism that you choose and the file is encrypted locally an S3 just
treats it as an encrypted disk.
And finally remember that we can use a pocket policy to prevent any unencrypted files from being uploaded
into S3.
So in the lab we created our policy which only allowed a request which included X AMC server side encryption
parameter within the request header.
And then when we tried to upload a file which did not include the correct parameter within that header
we were prevented from uploading the object.
So we saw that it failed.
Cross origin resource sharing or cause is used to enable cross origin access for your AWOL resources
for example an S3 hosted Web site accessing JavaScript or image files which are located in a completely
different S3 bucket and you should know that by default the resources in one bucket cannot access the
resources located in another.
And if we want to set this up we need to configure cross origin resource sharing on the bucket being
accessed and enable access for the origin or bucket attempting to access.
So remember we did this in the lab with our two buckets containing the index or HDL and the load page
to HCM.
And we set up access on that bucket containing load page to HDMI out to allow access for the origin
within which indexed or HMO was located.
And when we do that remember that we always need to use the S3 Web site are and not the regular bucket.
You are well and just to remind you we've got the two examples here.
So the first one highlighted in orange.
That is our S3 Web site U.R.L..
So it goes HDP then a cloud guru which is our bucket name.
And then the big clue here is three dash Web site.
And then our region a US one Amazon NWS dot com and then our regular bucket you are well which is the
HDP s and then our region name Amazon NWS dot com.
And finally the bucket name.
So just remember when you see that you are out and it says S3 dash website and then your region name
that is our S3 website you are all moving on to cloud front.
Remember the terminology for the different elements that make up cloud front.
So we have the edge location.
This is the location where the content is going to be caged.
And this is separate to an AWOL region or a W S AC.
We also have the origin and this is the location of all the files that the content delivery network
is going to distribute.
And remember this may be an S3 bucket.
It can also be an easy to instance or an elastic balancer or Route 53 distribution.
This is the name given to the content delivery network and this consists of a collection of edge locations
and of course when we did the lab and we created our content delivery network we created a distribution.
And when we tried to access our files we did so using the distribution domain name and we got two different
types of distribution.
We have the Web distribution and that's what we use for Web sites and that's the type of distribution
that we set up in the lab.
We also have Aarti MP which is Adobe's real time messaging protocol and this is used for flash or media
streaming.
And remember the edge locations are not just read only you can also write to them.
So you can also upload objects into the location and Amazon will handle the transfer of the object from
the location into your S3 Buckets and objects are kept in the cage for the time to live or the TTL and
the default time to live is 24 hours after that 24 hours the time to live expires and the objects are
then cleared from the cage.
And if your files are changing more frequently than every 24 hours you can clear those from the cage
manually.
It's called an invalidation.
And remember in the lab we could configure in validations on that in validations tab on an object basis
but you will be charged if you want to do this.
There are two main approaches for performance optimization within S3 for the get intensive workloads.
You simply use cloud from for example if you have many users logging onto your website or accessing
files located in your S3 bucket.
The easiest way to optimise that is to use cloud front.
However for mixed workloads.
So when you have a mix of get put list bucket get bucket the best way to optimise performance is to
avoid using sequential key names for your objects and instead use a random prefix like a hex hash at
the beginning of the key name.
And this just stops as three from storing all of your objects on the same physical partition.
So just see the example below for these object names.
We've added the random hex hash as a prefix to the object name.
And this will force S3 to store them on different physical partitions and just avoid the possibility
of IO contention that you can sometimes get when you have many files stored on the same partition and
many people trying to access at the same time.
And our final tip for the exam is to make sure you read the S3 AFAIK you as S3 was one of the first
services that was bought out by Amazon.
That can often be a lot of questions relating to S3.
So this is a really good one to know inside out.
So definitely make sure you read the FIA queue before going into the exam.
So that's the end of this lecture.
I hope you've enjoyed it and if you've got time please join us in the next lecture.
Thank you.