Help overclockers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about S-3 security.
So it's going to be a really really quick lecture.
We're just going to cover off some of the main access control mechanisms that you get with S-3.
So the different ways that we can allow access to you as three buckets.
And then after this lecture we're going to go straight into a lab.
So we're going to show you how to actually configure some of these access control mechanisms that we've
been talking about now by default all newly created pockets within S-3 are private and this means that
only the owner of the bucket gets access to the packet and its contents.
So only the owner can upload new files read files delete files etc. and there is no public access by
default.
But we might want to allow other accounts to access our objects within as three buckets.
We might want to make our bucket publicly accessible for example or we might have a certain user or
a set of users a group that users for which we want to enable access to put new objects or objects within
our three packet.
And the way that we can do that is using bucket policies and bucket policies are applied at a package
level.
So this means that the permissions granted by that policy apply to all of the objects within the bucket.
You can't attach a bucket policy to an individual object but the bucket policies are really good for
those situations where you have a group of files and they all need to be accessed by the same people.
Now bucket policies are written in J-Zone which is the javascript object notation language.
So it's based on Javascript but it's pretty human readable.
It consists of a list of key value pairs and they actually provide a policy generates too.
So that means that they make it really easy for you.
You don't have to start writing javascript.
You can use this policy generator to actually build out the policies that you need.
And this is something that we're going to take a look at in the next lab.
Moving on to access control lists.
So these are applied at an object level.
That means that we can apply different permissions for different objects within a bucket so we can define
which accounts or groups are granted access and also the type of access so read y or full control.
So we can go to a different type of access to different objects within the same bucket.
So it really gives you that fine grained access control.
And this is really good for situations where you do want to have different permissions for different
objects for different users and groups then Access Control List is the one to use.
And if you want to track the different access requests that are being made to your S-3 objects you can
configure access logs and these are Laux which will log all the different requests made to the S3 bucket
every time a user makes a request to upload a file or redefine orderly to file all of those activities
will get logged into the access log.
And this low can actually be written into another S3 packet.
So that covers all of the main mechanisms for access control within S3.
And don't worry if it doesn't make too much sense right now the best way to learn it really is to start
configuring some of this in the console.
And that's exactly what we're going to do next.
So if you have time please join us in the next lecture and we're going to be logging into the AWOS console
and actually configuring some of this access control.