Help bloggers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be all about S-3 access control
lists and policies and we're going to be creating our very first S-3 bucket and we're going to upload
a couple of files and we are going to have a play around with the access control lists which define
the access control to individual files and also S3 bucket policies which define your access control
and permissions on a bucket wide basis.
So if you've got time please join me in the AWOS console now.
So here I am in the console and you will find S-3.
It's funda storage.
So go ahead and click on S-3 and the first thing you're going to see is this dashboard.
And this is a dashboard.
It's a global dashboard and it's going to show you all the buckets across all regions.
So it will show you a global view and if you don't have any Esrey bucket's created yet you're not going
to see any.
But I already have one and it's located in the e you all into region.
So I'm just going to go ahead and create a new bucket when I create a new bucket.
Of course you're going to see that in this global view as well.
So I'm just going to go ahead and click on Create bucket and the first thing we need to do when we create
a bucket is give it a DNS compliant bucket name.
So this needs to be a globally unique name.
And of course you might find that your first choice of bucket is not available.
So I'm going to go ahead and see if I can create one now and I'm going to call it a cloud guru.
Dush Fay I are going to create my bucket in the Frankfort region so click on next and hey on the next
page it gives you a few different configuration options or properties.
So firstly they have versioning.
Now you can enable versioning on S3 by clicking that checkbox.
And this means it's going to keep all of the different versions of an object within the same bucket.
So this means that if you accidentally delete an object the previous version will still be there in
the bucket.
I'm not going to enable that now.
The next one is Server Access logging and this means that you can log all of the access requests into
your pocket.
Say you want to keep a record of all the different access requests happening on your bucket.
You want to do a security audit for example so you can really easily and I and you can also use tax
to track your project costs.
So these can be completely defined by you.
So for example I could add a tag of projects name on the name of my project is the Phoenix Project.
And if you're looking for something to read that is actually a really good novel called the Phoenix
Project and it's actually a novel about I-T and it's all about Devil.
So it's about a really dysfunctional company which is having a lot of problems delivering a new project.
And they finally see the light and move to a dev ops approach.
So they start using continuous integration and continuous deployment as well.
And it's actually a really good read.
Believe it or not so moving down the screen we can also enable object level logging and this will actually
record any object level API activity using Cloud trial.
They do charge an additional cost for it but it just means that you can log any activity that happens
on the S3 API and it's all going to be looked at using cloud trail.
You can also enable default encryption so by checking that box you have a choice between the two different
types of server side encryption which are offered in S3.
So you've got a 256 that's 256 bit encryption.
It's server side encryption and it will use AWOS as three manage Kazan's or so Oneidas s s e S3.
And don't worry because we are going to go through encryption in much more detail later on in the course.
And you've also got the option of using AWOS K M-S which is again server side encryption.
But this time it uses the K.M. as manage caes instead.
And that is known as SAAC KMOX but we're not going to enable encryption.
And then finally the last option is around cloud watch metrics.
So this will allow you to monitor the request in your pocket.
Again it is for an additional cost but it will give you some performance metrics specifically for S3.
If you are interested in seeing those metrics and they will all be talked easing flood watch.
So we are just going to stick to all of the defaults and hit next and move on to the public access settings.
So this is a fairly new feature of S3 So if you've used S3 before and you haven't seen the public access
settings feature before.
So these are additional settings which block public access and they enforce that buckets do not allow
public access to the data and by default it's completely private.
There is no public access a tool to your pocket.
And if you want to actually enable public access if you want to enable anonymous access to read or write
objects into your pocket then you will have to check these default boxes.
However to block all of the public access that is really the recommended setting and that is why they
have introduced these additional steps in order to actually enable public access.
And then at the bottom of the permission section there is the option to grant the S3 lock delivery group
right accesses to the bucket and that the one that you would need to enable if you actually want to
enable server access logging and server access logging will actually log all of the access requests
into your bucket.
So none of these are enabled by default.
So just going to keep Toller's that a false hit next.
And then this final screen that they show you it just gives you an overview of all the options that
we have selected.
So it just shows you your packet name and then all of the configuration options that we have selected.
So if you're happy with that then just go ahead and click Create bucket.
And hopefully that should successfully create your bucket.
So let's go into a bucket and you can actually create folders you can create different folders within
your pocket going to create a new folder called images and save and another folder called Notes on his
side.
So let's go into our images folder and upload our first file.
So just click on upload add files and I'm going to select an image from my local machine.
Click next and within this permissions section.
This is why you can configure the access control lists.
So remember access control as they are on a per file per object basis.
So of course by default we only have access for the owner of the file which is me but you can actually
go in and add other accounts and grant them read and write access to your objects and you can also grant
public read access as well.
But we're not going to do that.
Just going to go ahead and stick with the defaults and hit next and next.
And it's asking us to select which storage class we want to use.
So the default is the standard S3 and that's designed for frequently access data.
There is also these other options so we have the standard.
So this is the same jury ability as the standard S3 but it is designed for infrequently access data
and they do charge you every time you access your data.
There's also the one zone I remember that is the same as the standard.
But it is only in one availability zone and so that means the data is not as highly available as your
standard S3 option but it is a much more cost effective option than the standard.
It's about 20 percent cheaper and it's really great for data which is infrequently accessed but where
you also do not need high availability.
And then finally the last option is the reduced redundancy.
This is for frequently access data which is non critical actually lost the data because you would be
able to easily recreate it.
And of course it's not recommended anymore.
And in fact if you do select it they give you this message saying it's not recommended the standard
storage clause is more cost effective.
So we're going to stick with the standard clause.
You can also choose your encryption methods so you can protect your data at rest using server side encryption
and you got the two options using the S3 master key or the IWM.
K and S managed masticate as well.
So I'm just going to keep that to the default.
You can create meta data which is of course data about data so we can add something like Content-Type
for example and the content type is going to be a jpeg.
So I'm going to click on Save it for that and you can also add tags so you can add Department.
And it's going to be part of the development department.
So I'm going to go ahead and click next so my tag and click next.
And click upload so that it's a file uploaded.
If we click on the file we can try and access the file.
And there's actually two different ways of accessing the file.
First of all we can open the file and it's just a picture of me looking very happy holding one of our
brand new cloud gear T-shirts that we had delivered a few weeks ago.
We're going to go back to the console and then the second way of accessing this file is actually using
this HTP link.
So if I select this link and open it in a new files a tab we're actually going to get access denied.
And the reason we get access denied is because by default all three buckets are created without public
access.
So they deliberately disable public access by default on all packets.
When you first create them and of course when we try to access the files from the browser.
That's really the same as an anonymous access request.
So it's not using any AWOS credentials to actually determine whether we can access the phone or not.
It's actually treated as an anonymous access request because it's just coming through the browser.
So how do we make this file publicly available.
Well I'm going to try adding another file on try and make that publicly available.
And let's see how to do that.
So come back to the console.
Go back to our buckets going to upload a notes file this time so files
selects a text file.
Click next and I'm going to select grant public read access to this object and this is using the Access
Control list for that object.
So click on next next and upload.
Now you can see here we've actually had an error with trying to upload a public file so I'm going to
click on error.
Click on upload and see if we can get the message.
So it just says that's been forbidden.
And the reason this has been pathy Biton is because we are not allowed to upload a publicly accessible
file due to our packet policies.
So let's close that down and go back into our buckets go to permissions and it's going to be under this
public access settings and I'm going to edit the public access settings and I'm going to de-select all
of these protections which block new public I.S. else they block public access granted through public
ISO's and they block new public market policies and block public and cost account access.
If a bucket has bucket policies so I'm going to go ahead and save and they ask you to confirm and then
I'm going to go back to my bucket and try again to upload that file
grant public access it next next an upload so that I successfully upload it and we're going to click
on the file we can open it using the open button.
And of course when we use that button S3 is using the credentials that you logged into the console with.
So it's using your AWOS credentials to determine whether or not you are allowed access.
And in this case it knows the owner and it knows that I can access that file.
And then the second way of accessing is using this CPS link.
And I'm just going to open that up in a new tab and see if we can get access to that file.
Yes.
So we got access to the file.
We're not getting the access denied and that is because we updated our public access policy for the
entire three buckets.
And we also selected public access for the file itself which is managed underneath by an access control
list.
So let's just go back to our pockets go back to our images file and see if we can access this file using
using the browser.
And we still do have access denied.
So the reason we have access denied is even though we've updated our bucket policy to allow public access
to be defined on all files we have only configured public access on a file level using the Access Control
List for a text file.
So that means this file is still not publicly accessible.
So just remember really the access control list there an individual object level and they give you fine
grained access control to each different object within your buckets.
But let's take a closer look at the bucket policies.
So I'm going to come back to my bucket click permissions and bucket policies and we get this policy
at it's where you can go in and create your own policy using Jasen.
But they provide you this really good policy generator which allows you to really easily create bucket
policies without writing them from scratch basically.
So the first thing you need to do with this generator is you select the policy type.
So the type is going to be in S3 bucket policy.
The effect is going to be allow the principal.
So this is going to be the entity which you are allowing or denying access to.
So what is the entity that this policy is going to be applied to.
So for example this could be an identity access management user.
It could be another three buckets or another as three resource.
So in this case I'm just going to add another identity access management user.
So I'm going to come back to my management console.
I'm going to open that up in another in another tab and I'm going to go to identity access management
go to my users and I've actually already got a bunch of users already created.
So I'm going to select one of my users and I'm going to copy the I R and my user come back to the policy
generator and I'm going to add that user as my principal.
So it's going to be this user that we're applying this bucket policy to make sure that Amazon S3 service
is selected and then moving down we can select an action.
So I'm just going to select get it get bucket policy you can just select any action and the Amazon reseller
name down here is going to be the resource that we are employing the missions to.
So it's going to be the name or the Amazon resos name of our bucket.
So if we come back to the S3 management console they've helpfully included it up here on the policy
editor.
So I'm just going to copy that come back to a policy generator and paste that in.
So once we've done that we can just click that statement and then if we if we want to add additional
statements we can add additional statements if not we can just hit generate policy and that will generate
the Jason code to create that policy for us.
So if we now want to apply that policy to our buckets we just copy the Jason code come back to our policy
editor and we can paste it into the policy editor hit save and that will apply the bucket policy on
a bucket wide basis.
So that is the end of this lecture.
So we've created our first S3 bucket.
And remember a bucket is a container for all the files or objects that you upload into S3.
All files are private by default or bucket's the private by default and we can use Access Control lists
to set the permission on individual files but we use bucket policies to define permissions on a bucket
wide basis.
So that is the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.