Helicopters and welcome to this section of the course and in this section of the course we're going
to be talking all about the different methods that are available for S-3 encryption.
So all the different ways that you can in your data that you are storing in S3.
So let's get started.
So there are two different types of encryption.
So firstly there is encryption in transit and that really means encrypting the data that you are sending
to and from your packets.
So when you're uploading files from your PC into your pocket and also when you're if you're downloading
files from the bucket into your PC that's where we need to use encryption in transit.
And that is done using SSL Ortelius.
And for those who are not familiar t ls or transport layer security is really going to be replacing
SSL.
Sometimes the terms are used interchangeably so if you see SSL slashed TS You just know that that's
encryption in transit.
And typically that means we're using CPS to upload and download of files between the PC or between our
local system and the S3 bucket.
So moving on to encryption at rest and there are three different types of encryption at rest for server
side encryption.
Firstly we have S S E 3 which is the S3 managed caes and this means that each object is encrypted with
its own unique K using strong multi-factor encryption.
But as an additional step they also encrypt the key itself with the masticate which then they then regularly
rotate for you.
So take care of the case.
They manage the keys for you don't need to worry about managing your own case and it's all a 256 bit
so Advanced Encryption Standard 256 bit encryption and it's very easy to enable as we saw in the lab
previously previously you can just select your objects and select encryption and select the encryption
type you want to use within the properties of your object and you can do that when you're uploading
and you can also do it on existing objects within your packets.
Now the second method of encryption they offer is called S S E KMOX and this is with the s s a case
management service.
Once again I manage the keys for you but came as it comes with some additional benefits.
So firstly you get a separate permission for the use of an additional key called an envelope key.
And that is a key which actually encrypts your data is encryption key.
So it gives you that added level of protection against unauthorized access.
You also get an audit trail which records the use of your encryption keys so you can see when your key
has been used who used it and why.
So you get that you have any encryption or decryption related activities happening within your Esrey
bucket.
You also get the option to use your own key or you can use the default key which they provide which
is still unique to you.
You also have server side encryption with custom provided Keys also known as AC dash.
See and this is where AWOS managed the encryption and decryption activities but you manage your own
case.
So that means you're in charge of administering those caves or rotating them.
And the life cycle of those keys.
So really the most important thing to remember is that we have encryption in-transit transit encryption
at rest and the three different types of encryption at rest that are available.
And then lastly we have client side encryption which is why you encrypt the files yourself before you
upload them into S-3 so you can choose your own encryption methodology.
You can you can choose your own application to encrypt your files and you encrypt the files before uploading
them into S3.
So how can we enforce encryption for all the files that we upload into S3.
Well every time a file is uploaded or put request is initiated.
So this is what a put request looks like.
So the first line it just stays put so we know that it's a request and then it states the file name.
So in this example the file is called My file and it states the way that the file is going to be transmitted
into S3 So in this case it's going to go via HTP.
Next we have the name of the bucket.
So in this case it's called my bucket.
The date of the upload the method of authorization so in this case is using an authorization string.
Then the content type.
So in this case it's just plain text the content length so the length of the file in bytes.
And then the next section just shows us some meta data.
So just some user defined message data that's been included to describe the file.
So in this case it just states the author of the file and the author's name and then they expect 100
continue.
So expect 100 continue just tells S-3 not to send your request until it receives an acknowledgement.
So this means the S-3 can actually reject your message based on the contents of your header.
So if the message is rejected based on the contents of the header that means the body is the message
will not be sent.
Now if the file is going to be encrypted to upload time then there's a special parameter that gets included
within the request header and that parameter is called X I M.Z. server side encryption.
And there are two options currently available.
So there's one option available for the SSA S3 So the S3 managed case and that option is called abs
2:56.
So remember with the SS A S3 you've got a 256 bit encryption and then the other option cases for the
SS 3 k m s.
So that is the k m s managed KS.
So using the AWOS key management service
and when this parameter is included in the header of the request it simply tells S-3 to encrypt the
object at the time of upload and using the specified encryption method.
So this means it's really easy to enforce the use of server side encryption.
All you need to do is create a packet policy which denies any S-3 put request which does not include
this.
X I am server side encryption parameter within the request header.
So here we just have an example of the same request header but just including that server side encryption
parameter.
So we've just added it at the bottom of the header to let s 3 Know that we want to use SS as 3 or is
256 encryption at the time when this file is uploaded and then we'll just simply create that bucket
policy to inspect every S-3 header every S-3 put request to make sure the x and z server side encryption
parameter is included in every single header.
So let's take a look at some of our exam tips for S-3 encryption.
So just remember there are two different methods of encryption.
We have encryption in-transit and also encryption at rest.
So encryption in-transit encrypt the data over the network.
So between your PC and S3 and that is SSL Ortelius and typically it uses the HTP as protocol.
We also have encryption at rest.
So that is either server side encryption or client side encryption and we have the three server side
encryption options which are SSD S3.
So with S-3 managed KS SS aka a mess with Amazon managed case or using the case management case management
service and SSD see which is customer managed KS.
And then finally we have client side encryption.
So this is where you encrypt your files locally before uploading into S-3.
And just remember if you want to enforce the use of encryption for your files stored in S-3 use a bucket
policy to deny any request that does not include the X I server side encryption parameter within the
request header.
So that's the end of this lecture.
And as always the best way to learn is to actually start using it.
And that's exactly what we're going to be doing in the next lecture which is ALAP so if you've got time
please join me in the next lecture.