Helen Clark is welcome to this lecture.
So in this lecture this is going to be a lab.
And we are going to be setting up encryption on an as bucket so if you'd like to join me in the console
so let's get started.
So here we are in the AWOS console and the first thing that we're going to do in this lab is we're going
to create a new S3 packet then we're going to add a policy to enforce the use of server side encryption.
Then we're going to test that policy works.
So we're going to test it by attempting to upload a file without using the encryption option.
So first of all we need to select S-3 in the main console and we go to create bucket.
And we just create on your back here and I'm just going to keep the region as Frankfurt and click next.
And there are two ways to enable encryption so you can either enable it at the console which is the
easiest way and all you do is check the default encryption box and you can choose between the 256 which
is S3 managed Ks or the AWOS camis which is that K.M. is managed chaos.
And both of those are server side encryption.
But you can also enforce encryption on your S-3 packet by using an S3 bucket policy and for this lapse
that's exactly what we're going to do.
So we're not going to enable it.
So I'm just going to de-select that we're actually going to enable using a package policy.
So just go ahead and click next next and create bucket.
There we go.
So if we go into the pocket hit permissions and go to bucket policies.
So now we need to create the bucket policy that's going to enforce encryption on all files.
So let's go to policy generator.
And this is why we're going to build our policy.
So the type of policy is going to be an S3 bucket policy and the effect is going to be deny.
We're going to be denying requests which do you know enforce encryption.
So the principle will be stopped that will apply to any request keep the IWM service as Amazon as it
may and then for action just scroll down until you find out about object.
So it's what down here
that we put objects and just select that as resource name.
So that is the name of your pocket.
So if you just come back to your console screen copy the bucket I are an and at the end and then we
need to add a condition
so the condition is going to be string Oh.
So it's going to catch when the string does not a whole
Am I M.Z. server side encryption.
And then your family will pay the type of encryption that way of specifying.
So let's let's use K M-S such as just enter AWOS colon Kamis and then you hit that condition and then
go ahead and hit add statement and generate policy.
So this is the gyse on code that the policy generator has created for us.
So here you can see in the policy document we've got a policy ID a policy version and then the statement
which is the action guide that the policy is going to enforce.
So we've got statement ID and then the action which relates to the put of new objects so every time
we upload a new file then the effect will be denie for this resource for this bucket name so deny any
request to put new objects where the string does not equal x M.Z. server side encryption AWOS Calamus
and then Principal astore So that means anybody who tries to upload a file into this bucket without
using server side encryption is going to be denied.
So we need to copy this code that's been generated by the policy generator and go back to our console
and add in the code here
it's safe and OK and straight away we've seen an error message and I want to show you this message because
this is something that you see sometimes when you create new policies using the policy editor.
So the error that we've got here is saying action does not apply to resources in statement.
So we look at the resource section which is here where we've added our our Amazon resource name so it's
complaining that the action does not apply to this resource.
So this happens sometimes just because some services do not let you specify specific actions for individual
resources.
And in this case you need to usually need to add a wildcard to the resource element.
So that just means that the action will apply to all resources within that service.
Not just that bucket.
So everything within the bucket.
So if you do see this message you can normally resolve it just by adding a wild card.
So we'll do that now.
So we're just at forward slash and star and that should fix our problem.
Yep.
So it's accepted that policy now.
And we are ready to go ahead and test that policy is working correctly.
So go back to your pocket and we're going to try and upload an object scope to add files and I'm just
going to select a text file from my machine.
You can just select any file that you have on your local machine.
And click next next.
And if we scroll down on this set properties section will find the encryption failed here.
And we're just going to keep encryption to none.
So you've got the choice where you can either use encryption with an Esrey most a key or the camps managed
mosta key.
So you have the two options there but we're just going to keep it's anon and click next.
And then upload.
And we should see that that has actually filed so it's file to upload the object and what's at the bottom
you can see that we've got one error.
So if you click on the error and then click on upload it will give us the message and it just says that
this was a bit in action.
OK so let's try again and we're going to try and upload another file and this time we're going to use
encryption.
So just click on upload and you can just choose any file from your machine.
I'm just going to select one for my documents open next next and then scroll down to encryption.
I'm going to select I ws M-S and just select AWOS S3.
Then click on next and upload and then we all that should be successful.
So let's try and upload another file and use a different method of encryption.
So I'm just going to select another file from my documents.
Click next next.
Scroll down to the encryption section and I'm going to select using the Amazon as three most tickey
click next and upload.
So once again that should show you the same error message.
So if I click on the error message click on upload once again it shows me that that was forbidden.
So that is the end of this line.
So we've created our S-3 buckets.
We enforced the use of server side encryption.
And just remember there's two ways to do that so you can do it really easily on the console just using
the checkbooks or you can also enforce it using a policy.
And when we enforce server side encryption within S-3 This means the S3 will forbid any attempts to
upload a file without using the specified method of encryption.
So that is the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.