Hello cloud gurus and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be a lab.
And in this lab we are going to set up cross origin resource sharing also known as cause.
And this can come up in the exam so it's really important for you to know what it is.
So basically it's just a way of allowing code that is in one S3 pocket to access or reference code that
is in another S3 bucket.
So really we were just allowing one resource to access another resource and that's why it's called Cross
origin resource sharing.
So if you've got time please join me in the W console.
So here I am in the W W console and we're just gonna go down to S3 which is on the left hand side under
storage so we're going to create a new bucket and we're going to call it my index website and click
next and we're going to configure this as a public bucket.
So I'm going to uncheck all of the public access protection just select all of these boxes and click
next and then click Create bucket and then we go into that bucket and we go to properties and we hit
static website hosting.
So this allows you to host a static Web site from within S3.
So we go in and select that and we select use this bucket to host a website.
And when we use S3 to host a website they provide you with this website endpoint you are L and it's
this website endpoint that we use to access the website.
And when we configure cores between 1 S3 website and another the access request is linked to this end
point your url.
So it's this end point you are that we can figure the access for between the two S3 Buckets and you'll
see that later on.
So next it's going to ask you the name of your index and error or H2 AML documents.
So we have to actually explicitly type this in so we are indexed to each demo error.
Dot H T M O and hit save.
So then we go back to that S3 bucket.
So we have a few files that we've prepared which we're going to be using in this lab and we're just
gonna upload these files into our bucket.
So let's take a look at those.
So we've got indexed to each Timo here.
And don't worry these are all going to be available in the resources section of the course for you to
download.
So this is just a simple Web page which just says Welcome to the index page and then it just runs this
simple script which loads up the contents of another page.
And this is the page that we're going to be storing in another S3 bucket.
So it's just using this script to get that each Timo from the other S3 bucket.
So let's take a look at load page to HMO and again it's just a really very simple piece of HMO code
just displaying the page has successfully loaded telcos.
So when you load your indexed HMO what you should see on the screen is you should see the welcome message.
And then underneath you should see the message that says this page has successfully loaded cloud gurus.
So we're going to upload these three files into our S3 bucket
so we just go in and select all three of those files and upload.
And we want to make this a public access.
That's going to be part of a website so next and upload.
So if all our files have loaded successfully we should be able to access them as though they were a
Web site.
So let's go to properties and into static web site hosting and we're going to grab this static web hosting
U.R.L. and that should take us straight to the index page so you can see that it's loaded the index
page and it has also sourced the HMO from load page or HMO because it's displaying the second message
down here as well.
So right now all of these files are located in one single bucket.
But we want to have our load page located in a different bucket so that we can set up the cross origin
resource sharing.
So we're going to go back in to our original S3 bucket and we're going to delete that load page because
we don't want to in the
and we're going to create a new bucket so this one is going to be my cause test bucket
click Next uncheck all of the public access protection and click next and then click Create bucket.
Then we go back into that bucket hit properties select static web site hosting.
Use this bucket to host the Web site index dot HMO and error to each to mail and hit save.
So then we want to go back into our bucket and upload our load to each terminal file
next public read access and upload.
So let's just check that we can access our load page or HD him out using the Web site and point for
a bucket.
So in order to do that we go to properties on the bucket starting web hosting and we use this end point.
You are out and we need to specify the name of the file
OK so that's your website you are all for our load page here Bill.
So we just want to copy that because we need to update our index to HMO to know where to find load page
or HD Hero.
So we go back to our file and replace that load page HMO with the U or L for the correct location.
So hopefully that's clear.
We have index dot HMO in one bucket and it's referencing the load page or HMO which is located in another
bucket and it's referencing load page via the ATP end point address save.
And then we go back to our original index bucket.
We need to get rid of this old version.
So we're good and I'm just going to delete fixes quicker the quickest way to get rid of the old version
and upload the new version
we need to grant public read access hit next next and upload.
I expect it's only going to show as that first page.
So it's only going to show us that index to HMO and we shouldn't be allowed to access the contents of
our second bucket even though that bucket is publicly accessible.
So let's just give this a go now.
So if we go to properties static web hosting and click on your static web hosting and point you are
well.
So it only allows us to access indexed or HD him so it doesn't give us actor access to the contents
of the second bucket because we don't have calls set up.
And if you're a chrome user like me you can view the browser error messages by just going to view developer
and hit javascript console.
And this is going to show us the error messages associated with this page and straight away we can see
that our request has been blocked by the cause policy so no access control allow origin header is present
in the requested resource so it's failed to load the resource and the server has responded with a status
of 4 0 3.
So that's a really easy way to see the error messages in your browser but if you're not using Chrome
I can show you how it looks in Safari.
So here is the same web page loaded into safari and we just go into develop and show javascript console.
And I'm just going to reload my page and there we are.
The error messages have appeared below and you just get a similar error message.
So it's not allowed by Access Control origin request cannot load our page due to access control checks
and it has failed to load our resource.
And if you're using internet explorer then just load up the developer tools and find your javascript
errors and you should see a really similar error in there as well.
So it's not letting us access the load page or HMO because we don't have cores set up.
So that is exactly what we're going to go and do now.
So in order to configure cause we need to go and find our Web site address for indexed or HD CML because
that is the file which is trying to access our load page.
So let's go into properties static web hosting and we need to copy this end point address
then we go back into our cores test bucket go to permissions and you'll see the course configuration
button there.
So we select that and they provide it.
This example calls configuration Ed to help us get started.
And I've also provided this sample policy as a resource in the course as well so you can just download
it and modify it to add your own origin.
So the one thing that you need to add in here is the allowed origin so where it says start.
Delete that star and add in your new URL hit save.
If you've got anything wrong in the syntax then it will tell you.
But we've got no errors here.
That's fine.
So that should be everything that we need to do to enable the cross origin resource sharing.
So let's go ahead and test it.
There we go.
And it's work.
So we're using the my index website or S3 Web site you are all so if it isn't working for you it might
be because you're using the wrong you or L you're using the address of the file in S3 but you actually
need to use the end point Web site you are L.
So you should see welcome to the index page because this page has successfully loaded cloud gurus.
So hopefully you're seeing you're seeing that message so cross origin resource sharing is a really good
way to organize your Web site.
So for example you could store image files in one bucket JavaScript in another bucket plain HMO in another
bucket and then use cross origin resource sharing to allow the resources from one bucket to access the
resources for another bucket by default one bucket or resource cannot access another.
And for security reasons if universal access were allowed that would leave your resources open to attack
leave you open to information theft and cause is the safe mechanism to allow controlled access between
one resource and another so that's the end of this lab.
I hope you enjoyed it.
And if you got time please join me in the next lecture.