Hello caregivers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about cloud front which is Amazon's
content delivery network and this is a theoretical lecture.
It's just to introduce the main concepts so that you have a good understanding before we go ahead and
build our own cloud front distribution in the next lab.
So let's get started.
So what is a CD and well a CD and or a content delivery network is a system of distributed servers or
a network of distributed servers that deliver web pages on other web content to users based on the geographical
location of the user.
The origin of the web page and a content delivery server.
So what does that mean.
Well it's really a web service which speeds up the distribution of your static and dynamic web content.
So you think HMO javascript's image files.
So any web content.
And it's a much more efficient way for geographically distributed users to access your content.
So imagine you are running a Web site located in the UK and you have a lot of users based all around
the world.
So you've got users in USA South America Africa India and Australia.
And when a user purchases to your Web site their request is routed through many different networks to
reach your server and the number of network caps and the distance that a request needs to travel has
a significant impact on the performance and the responsiveness of your website and the network latency
is going to be different for each different location.
So it's not going to be consistent geographically.
So for those users who are further away they're going to experience worse performance they're going
to experience greater latency.
So for example for users based in Australia they might experience worst performance greater latency
or they might think that the web site seems less responsive and uses based in say India for example.
So this is where the use of a content delivery network comes in and we're going to use the same diagram
that we used for transfer acceleration.
So if you remember transfer acceleration utilizes cloud technology.
But there is a difference between the two.
And the main thing to remember is that cloud front is focused on content delivery.
So I think allowing more efficient leads and downloads whereas transfer acceleration is all about enabling
faster uploads into S3.
So once again imagine you are running your website from London and you have your users all geographically
dispersed all around the world.
So instead of each user accessing the files directly between their geographical location and London
instead we introduced this concept called Edge locations and an education is simply a collection of
servers which are in a geographically dispersed data centers and these applications are used by cloud
front to keep a case of copies of your object so copies of your DML files your your images your content
that you're serving.
And this means that instead of requesting content from your server located in London users can access
that content from the edge location.
So instead of making the request to the London server the user is making the request directly to the
edge location which is much closer geographically than the main server in London.
So once the request is made the location puts the request on to the server in London.
So it downloads the files and it Keisha's them locally.
So that means that next time they user or if another user comes along and wants to access the same object
they can then access that directly from the edge location.
So this provides a much faster response time.
It means that your requests are only going to that local edge location.
They're not going all the way to London.
It dramatically reduces the number of network hops for each of your requests which again improves the
performance time it gives you lower latency and higher transfer rights as well.
So objects at Kiesha and that case for a period of time and after that period of time is up.
It's called A Time to live after that time to live is up.
The object automatically cleared from the case.
Now you can click objects yourself for example if you had a new version of an object and the version
of an image or new version of a file you can actually go in there and clear that case yourself to make
sure that when your users try to access that file they get the latest version.
So you can clear the case yourself but you will be charged for doing that.
So let's take a look at some of the key cloud front terminology.
So education and this is the location where content is cased you can case content that you're trying
to access from the Web site or from S3.
But you can also write content into the edge location as well.
So it's a two way thing.
They are separate to an AWOS region or availability zone.
And actually there are a lot more locations than there are AWOS regions and availabilities.
Now origin.
So this is really just the origin of all the files that the content delivery network is going to distribute.
So it could be an S-3 it it could be an easy to instance running a website.
It could be an elastic load balance or it could be route 53 but usually more often than not is an S3
bucket or it's an easy to instance running a Web site distribution.
So this is the term given to the name of the content distribution network and that consists of a collection
of edgy locations and there are two types of distribution.
So firstly we have Web distribution so that's used just for Web sites.
So I think HTC pay HTP s and we also have ATI MP which is realtime messaging protocol and that is used
for streaming audio video and data over the Internet.
So I just think media streaming.
So cut from that can be used to deliver your entire web site including dynamic static streaming and
interactive content using a WSS global network of edge locations.
So that means requests for content they are automatically routed to your nearest edge location and content
gets delivered to you with the best possible performance.
So as we talked about it could be used to optimize performance for users.
So geographically distributed uses all accessing the same web site in London backed by S3.
So instead of sending requests to that Web site in London users will access their local edge location
and hopefully the Web site will be there.
And if it isn't then the location will use Amazon's network to grab the files that have been requested
and the next time the user tries to access them they will be caged within the education.
So platform is optimized to work with lots of other AWOS services.
So as we've already talked about E.C too.
So you could use easy to to run your own web site if you wanted to.
It's also optimized to work with elastic load balancing and 53.
And it also works seamlessly with any non AWOS origins.
So that means you could just really use your own server within your own data center and cloud front
would still work with that for the tudes cloud front distribution types.
We have the Web distribution used for web sites.
So that's HTP and HTP.
S for a Web distribution the origin or the place where your original files are stored can be either
an S3 packet or an h t t p h t t p s server.
You cannot serve Adobe Flash multimedia content from a Web distribution.
And for that you're going to need an ATI MP distribution.
So that allows you to stream media files using the Adobe media server and the Adobe realtime messaging
protocol.
So streaming audio video and data over the Internet and we can also use cloud front to accelerate the
transfer of files into S3 and that is called S3 transfer acceleration and transfer acceleration enables
fast easy and secure transfers of your files over long distances between your end users and an S3 bucket.
So this takes advantage of cloud fronts globally distributed educations.
And as the data arrives at an education it is then routed into S-3 over an optimized network.
Paul So its a much faster way for you to upload your files into S3.
So lets just have a look at an example.
So in this example we have our S3 packet located here in London and again we've got our users geographically
distributed.
And just imagine all these users need to upload a load of files into this three bucket.
So instead of uploading directly to the back in London which could take a long time for some of the
users who are furthest away they can upload that file into the cloud fund education and then from there
the education will transfer that file into the London bucket.
Using an optimized network so using the fast networks within AWOS.
So let's take a look at some of our exam tips.
Firstly remember the terminology the edge location and this is the location where your content is going
to be cased it seperate to an AWOS region or AWOS availability zone.
It's not the same thing.
And in fact we have many more applications than we do regions and availabilities owns the origin.
So remember that the location of where we are files the origin of all the files that the CDN is going
to be distributing and this might be a necessary bucket and we see two instance a load balance or route
53 distribution.
So this is the name given to the content delivery network and that consists of a collection of different
edge locations and we have two different types of distribution.
We have the Web distribution which is used for web sites and ATI MP which is used for media streaming
education.
And not just read only IAU can put an object to them and have that transferred into S3 locations are
also used by S-3 transfer acceleration to reduce latency for S-3 uploads and objects a case.
So that case for the lifetime of a time to live value.
And when that type of value expires then the object is wiped from the case and you can clear cased objects
at any time.
But you will be challenged.
So that's the end of the cloud front lecture and next lecture is going to be a lab and we are going
to be setting up our own cloud front content delivery network.
So if you've got time please join me in the next lecture.