Hello cloud gurus and welcome to this lecture and this is going to be a lab and we are going to create
our own CD and or content delivery network and in the west there in their terminology.
This is called a distribution.
So it's called a cloud front distribution and for the cloud from origin.
So this is the place where the original copies of your files or your content is located.
We're going to use an S3 bucket and you can have multiple origins per distribution.
You can also have an easy to instance elastic load balance.
You can even have a physical server on premise in your own data center.
But for the purpose of this lab we're just going to use S3 and to get started you just need to join
me in the AWOS console.
So here I am in the AWOS console and the first thing that we need to do is we need to create the origin.
So we're going to do that in S3.
So we go down to S-3 and click on S3 and then go to create bucket.
Now we're going to create a pocket in place that's the most furthest away from where we are.
So I'm located in London so I'm going to use a bucket in a region that is as far away as I can find
which is going to be somewhere in Australia.
So we're going to pick Sydney and we're going to call it my Sydney cloud front origin.
Go ahead and click next and click next.
And we're going to configure this as a public bucket so I'm going to uncheck all of the public access
protection just de-select all of these boxes and click next.
And then click Create bucket.
So the next thing we're going to do is add a file into the bucket or go into the bucket upload and we're
going to add an image file.
So we go into my images directory and we're going to select a picture of a fairly large image.
So three point four make.
So open up the image.
And the reason we want an image is so that we can actually see it loading so we can see it loading from
the other side of the world.
So click on next.
I'm going to give public access to this image.
We want to be able to access it over the Internet.
So click on public read access to this object click next.
Keep all the rest of the defaults the same and hit upload and you can see down here.
It started it's in progress so you can see the percentage progress down here.
It's not immediate because we're transferring it over the other side of the world over to Australia.
So there we are.
OK so that successful and we can click on that file come down to the link down here.
And hits on the link to access the file and we can see it just takes ages to load.
It's no instant like it would normally be if it was stored in a bucket that was local if I'd selected
London as my region for the S-3 bucket it would be pretty much instantaneous.
So this is where cloud front distributions come in.
So let's go ahead and set up our first cloud from distribution.
So if we go back to the services section and scroll down to networking because that's where we find
crowdfund under networking and content delivery.
So it's like cloud front unclick create distribution.
So you've got two different options here.
There's two different types of cloud front distribution.
We discussed earlier.
You've got the Web distribution which is for HMO CSSA ph in graphics.
Basically anything that could be distributed using a pay or a CPS.
And then we also have RCMP which is Adobe's Flash media server real time messaging parts protocol and
this is ready for streaming media is not for your basic web sites or static content.
It's just streaming media so you're not going to use an RTM distribution this time we're going to just
stick with the regular Web distribution.
So click on get started and then straightaway you see a whole load of different parameters so there's
loads of different settings for cloud front.
And don't worry because you don't need to memorize all of these for the exam you just really need to
know theoretically what is cloud from what is it used for how does it work at a high level and there's
a few options that you need to know about.
But I'm going to tell you about those as we go along.
So the first thing we need to do is to tell OUTFRONT what is the name of our origin and if we click
in here you'll get a choice.
So you'll see the option here and we can see the S3 packet that we created just a moment ago and if
we had load balances on our account you'd see the elastic load balances down here you'd be able to select
one of those if you wanted to use an AC to instance.
You should see that in here as well.
And if you wanted to use an on premise servers or your own web server located in your own data center
you could just add the IP address or the registered domain name of that server.
You could just add that in here under the origin domain name.
So we're just going to select the S3 bucket that we just created.
Origin path.
So this refers to different folders within your origin.
For example if you had different photos for images videos and HMO files you could put the folder names
onto this origin Paul but we don't have that.
So we're just going to leave that blank
image in our day.
So this is just a description so we can just keep that at the default
restrict access.
So this is an option that you would use if you wanted to restrict access and enforce ALL ACCESS to come
via cloud front.
So there would be no direct access directly into the three bucket for all users that want to access
the files.
They need to come through cloud front.
So we're going to click on yes for that and then straight away a few additional options appear.
So in order to set up your restricts bucket access we also need to have an origin access identity and
this open access identity is a special cloud for us.
And this is going to be given permission to access your three buckets.
So as we know by default no one can access the bucket apart from the bucket owner.
So in order to allow cloud front to access that bucket we need to set up some identity access management
to enable that.
And that's what they said.
So it's creating identity for cloud front to use to access your S-3 buckets.
So make sure you select Create new user identity.
So the next thing we need to do is actually grant the right permissions for this new user.
And if you forget to do this it will not work.
So this is a really important step.
For some reason they leave the default to no in which case you would have to go in yourself and update
the permissions for this user.
So we need to remember to click yes.
And then that will set up one of the bucket policy and access control that you need the new user then
moving down to default case behaviors that sings.
We have various different options here around HTP and AC CPS.
So you've got the choice to allow both HTP and CPS or you can redirect all HTP to CPS or you can allow
HTP only.
So we're going to go for redirect.
So any request that comes in is HTP it's going to get converted to CPS automatically and then they allow
methods.
So you've got get head get head options head options put post patch delay.
So the important thing to remember here is with cloud front it's not just about reading files accessing
files downloading files.
You can also put and post so you can also upload your files using the cloud front edge location and
then AWOS will manage the transfer of those files from the location into your S-3 pocket or into your
origin.
Moving down here we have the time to live or TTL and TTL is the minimum amount of time in seconds that
you want your objects to stay in the cloud front cage.
So it's basically how long is the object going to be cased for before it expires and then gets wiped
from the case.
And it's expressed in seconds so the maximum is 30 billion seconds which equates to 365 days.
But the Dufault is 86000.
And that equates to 24 hours.
Now the thing to be aware of here is that you might have files which get uploaded much more frequently
than 24 hours.
So for example if you had files that were getting updated two three four times a day or on an hourly
basis that time to live is not going to work for you and you're going to find that your files that are
held in the edge locations become out of date pretty quickly.
So in that case the thing you want to do is change this number here reduce it down.
Think about how frequently your data is changing and you want to set the time to live to a fraction
of the refresh frequency.
So maybe one half one third or one quarter or less depending on how important it is for your material
to be up to date.
And this option here code restrict viewer access use signs you arouse or signed cookies.
So this option allows you to choose whether you want cloud front to require users to access your content
using a signed you Arel or a signed cookie.
And the reason that you might want to do that is just imagine that you have a Web site and some of the
content on your Web site is paid for content.
So what you can do is restrict the access to that content only to users who have assigned you already.
The users cannot share you all because it's individual to them and you only released the signs you are
well.
So users who have actually paid to view the content and that is actually technology that we use here
at iCloud.
Because we have some content on our site which is took members only and we automatically generate this
signed Yeoville to enable them to access the paid for content.
So just remember in the exam if you get asked any questions around accessing content that you're selling
on a Web site and restricting that only to users who have paid for the content then the way to do that
is to use signed Europhiles or signed Cookie's.
And it's not something that we're going to Kawika here right now it's not part of this lab.
But you just need to really be aware of it and understand what it's used for.
Then moving down we also have a web application firewalls or WAF and this provides traffic filtering
for well-known attacks like sequel injection or cross-site scripting.
So this is going to protect you the application layer unlike confirmer network firewall protects you
at the network layer.
This actually protects you at the application layer and the web application firewall is tightly integrated
with crowdfund.
You can also add your own domain name so if you own your own registered domain name and you want to
use that as the elf cloud for distribution you can add that in here.
But we don't have one of those.
It's fine.
Once the cloud distribution has been created they will provide you with your own unique domain name.
It might not be very user friendly but going can give you an SSL certificates so we selected the option
to redirect all pay to HTP.
And that means we're going to need to use SSL certificates.
So we're just going to keep it so the option to use the default cloud certificate but there is also
an option to use your own custom SSL certificate and for that you'd need to store your certificate in
WS certificate manager or so you can store in.
But for the purposes of this lab we're just going to keep it to the DeFeo.
So moving down you also see the different ice GTP versions that are supported.
So we just keep it to the Dufault and IPD Sexta is a neighborhood by default.
So then just go ahead and create distribution and you get this message just about using cloud fences
of private content.
We can just ignore this.
And if you go to distribution's on your left you'll be able to say that your distribution creation is
in progress.
And unfortunately with Klout front it does take a while to get the distribution created.
It takes around 15 to 20 minutes and I think the reason for that is because it's provisioning to lots
of different edgy locations all around the world.
It's replicating your distribution set up to all of those locations and at the time of recording they've
got around a hundred edge locations located in over 25 countries.
So as you can imagine that's a lot of locations to push the configuration to.
So it's just one of the things in AWOS that just takes a little bit longer.
It's not instant So it's going to be about another 15 minutes.
And I think until we can get started again.
So it's a good time to take a break have a cup of tea.
I'm going to post the video now and hopefully in 15 minutes we should be ready to get started again.
So here we are back in the AWOS console and the cloud front distribution is now complete.
So you should see a state of enabled.
So let's go in and take a look at this distribution and this is our distribution.
Id
And this view just shows the general parameters that we've chosen for this distribution.
We've got our distribution already up here Amazon resource name and the domain name appears down here
and this to my name is really important because it's this domain name that we're going to use to access
the cloud fund distribution.
Let's have a look at some of the other tabs on this few.
So we have the origin and of course you can have multiple origins here you can create others.
So you could add an easy to instance that was hosting a web site you could add an elastic load balance
you could add any other S-3 buckets that you were serving content from and you could also add in the
details of a server that you have located in your own data center and behaviors.
We've got the path Patersons so many different folders that exist underneath the S3 bucket.
The name of your origin.
So again our S-3 bucket and our protocol policy so any requests that come in as HTP they're going to
get redirected as a CPS and error pages.
So you can create your own custom error response so it's going to display your custom error page.
Whenever there's an error code whenever the origin returns an HTP 400 or 500 status code under restrictions
you can actually prevent users in selected countries from accessing your content.
So you specify either a whitelist which is the countries that can access your content or a blacklist
which is a list of countries that cannot access your content.
So here we are we can either select whitelist or blacklist and we can list out the countries that we
want to what list.
So for example we can add them into here
we can add into the list of countries that we want to what list and that we want to make the content
available to all.
Similarly you can set it up as a blacklist and just make a list of all the countries that you want to
blacklist and by implication any country that you do not blacklist will get access.
Any country that you do not whitelist will not get access but we're not going to set that up right now
so let's go ahead and cancel and take a look at invalidations.
So invalidations is all about removing your files the case in the cloud front edge locations.
So for example if the file has changed the file has been updated but you've still got the old copy cased
in cloud front.
But you don't want to wait the time to live to expire to automatically play the old version out of the
case.
If you want to remove the object from the case you need to do an invalidation which invalidates the
object on the case and effectively clears that object from the case.
So it's a manual process.
You're going to have to go in and do it.
But just remember every time you do it you will be charged a fee.
So let's go back to a file and see if we can access it using cloud front.
So let's make things easier just by opening another tab so that we have two console windows and I want
to go back to S-3
and take a look at my file.
So we have all linked down here which is using the S-3 Internet.
You are.
And let's just click on the
say all files slowly slowly load but I don't want to be accessing the file in this way.
I want to force the users to access using cloud front only.
So I'm going to go back and I'm going to change the permissions on this file.
So we're changing the access control list on the file.
We're going to remove public access click on Save and now when we try to access that file it's still
there now because it's in the browser case but we're going to reload and we see the access denied message
because we've removed public access.
So how do we access it using cloud fonts.
Well we need to go back into our distribution hit the general tab and we to get our domain name so we
copy that to my name.
And we're going to use that as the prefix to our file name.
And I'm going to change it to CTP instead of HGT P.S. because if you remember but we selected the option
which will redirect any HTP requests to a shitty POS.
Let's just hit return and see if that works.
So the very first time you access a file using cloud front it's not going to be cased in your education
so your request will go to your local education
and if the file does not exist there is going to have to pull it down from the S3 bucket.
So that means you see a similar response time to accessing the bucket directly.
However subsequent attempts to access this follow from the same education should be much quicker because
the file will be cased locally at the edge location.
And one way you can try this is by trying to access the file using a different browser or using a different
device like a mobile phone or a tablet.
But let's try it now using a different browser.
So first of all I'm just going to copy that link
and then I'm going to launch another browser so I'm going to paste that you know into safari and see
how quickly we can access that file.
Yes.
So it comes up really really quickly.
It's case locally in the London location.
So we get access really very quickly.
So that is cloud front distribution and the main thing to remember is that it's possible to play your
case by invalidating objects.
So that will clear them from the case if you need to remove them from the case and you can't wait for
the time to live to expire.
But just remember you do get charged for it.
And remember that you can post files into edge locations.
It's not just for accessing files.
So you can also upload content
and finally to remember to delete all of this once you finish the lap because you do get charged.
So let's go back into the console and delete everything.
So the first thing that you need to do is click on your distribution click on disable click yes
and once again it does take up to 15 minutes because it's deleting that configuration from all the explications.
So as soon as the 15 minutes is up as soon as this is complete all you do is select the distribution
and then you'll be able to delete it.
And that's the end of this lab.
If you have any questions please let me know.
Otherwise if you've got time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.