Hello cloud gurus and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be about S-3 performance
optimization.
And it's just going to be a very short theoretical lecture covering the different mechanisms for performance
optimization within three.
Now S3 is designed to support Gary Jolles request rights by default.
However if you are routinely experiencing incredibly high utilization.
So for example if you're S3 buckets are consistently receiving over 100 put list delete or over 300
get requests per second then the awesome best practice guidelines.
Which will help you to optimize your S-3 performance.
And this guidance is based on the type of workload that you are running.
So for example folks get intensive workloads AWOS recommend to use cloud front.
Content delivery service to get the best performance.
And as we've seen before in the previous lecture cloud front case your most frequently Access objects
and it will significantly reduce latency feel get requests.
So how do we optimize for workloads that are not intensive.
Well for the mix request type workloads.
So for example a mix of get put delete or get Buckett the names that you actually use for your objects
can really impact performance for this type of workload.
And this is all to do with the way that S3 uses key names to determine which physical partition an object
is going to be stored in and the use of sequential names and so for example names that are prefixed
with a time stamp or an alphabetical sequence increases the likelihood of having multiple objects stored
within the same partition.
And for heavy workloads this can of course cause issues and contention because you're trying to access
files that are physically located within the same partition.
So in this case by using a random prefix to Yochi names instead of a sequential one you could actually
force S-3 to distribute your case across multiple partitions thus distributing the workload.
Let's have a look at an example.
And in this example the following sequential key names are not optimal.
So just imagine that you are uploading a large number of objects into S3 where you might be tempted
to use sequential numbers or dates as part of the key names your objects.
So in this example they're using the sequential dates as their Foden names.
And of course the Fodor name in that folder structure becomes part of the case name of your object.
So in this first example it's highly likely that all of these objects are going to get stored on the
same partition.
And just imagine you had hundreds and hundreds of objects and they were all getting stored on the same
partition.
Of course that's eventually going to cause contention when you if you have many many hundreds of requests
happening per second.
So for optimal performance the best practice advice is to introduce randomness into the game.
So in the second example we're still using that kind of data format for the folder name.
However a four character a hex hash has been added as a prefix to that name or in fact any random sequence
of characters could be used.
The point is just to add that element of randomness within that name.
And this is what is going to force S-3 to store all of these different objects on different partitions
so it spreads the workload across a number of different partitions and reduces the likelihood of a contention.
So what are our exam tips.
All you need to remember really is the two main approaches to performance optimization for S3 and forget
intensive workloads.
That is to use cloud front as we're used in the lab and you saw how much more quickly you could access
a file using the cloud from each location compared to accessing it directly from a very remote packet
and then for the mixed workloads avoid sequential names for S-3 objects instead use a random prefix
like a hex hash at the front of the case name to prevent multiple objects from being stored on the same
partition.
So that's the end of this lecture.
And the next lecture is going to be a summary of S-3 of everything that we've learned for the last three.
So if you've got time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.