Hello bloggers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to cover deploying docker containers
using Elastic Beanstalk so as you know you can use Elastic Beanstalk to deploy your web applications
without having to worry about provisioning any underlying infrastructure and as well as supporting applications
developed to using programming languages like Java dot net no J.S. Python etc. You can also deploy docker
containers using Elastic Beanstalk and if you remember docker containers are self-contained and they
include all of the configuration information and software that your web application requires to run.
So think any libraries system tools code and runtime environment as well.
So that means that once you've Docker your application it's going to run anywhere where docker containers
are supported.
Now when you deploy a docker container using Elastic Beanstalk Elastic Beanstalk handles all of the
capacity provisioning load balancing scaling and application health monitoring.
So it's a really really easy and quick way to get started with docker containers without having to worry
about provisioning any underlying infrastructure.
So when you deploy a docker container using Elastic Beanstalk you can either run a single docker container
on an easy to instance provisioned by Elastic Beanstalk or alternatively you can run multiple docker
containers and to do that you would use Elastic Beanstalk to build an ISIS cluster or elastic container
service cluster and then deploy multiple docker containers on each instance within the ECF cluster and
Elastic Beanstalk will handle all of that for you as well.
So when you're ready to deploy your code you Simply upload a zip file containing a bundle of your code
an elastic beanstalk will do the rest and when you need to upgrade your code.
So you want to upgrade your application to a new version.
It's one easy step in the console to upload a new version of your zip file and deploy your new code.
But really the best way to learn about how this all hangs together is to get your hands dirty.
So if you'd like to join me in the console now we're going to deploy a couple of versions of a docker
container using Elastic Beanstalk so here I am in the W W console and I'm just gonna head down to compute
and find Elastic Beanstalk.
Click on get started and first of all we need to give our new Elastic Beanstalk application a name and
I'm just gonna call it my doctor app we need to choose a platform and we've got a choice between a single
docker container which is going to be installed on a single easy to instance or a multi container Docker
so multiple instances of our docker container.
So I'm just gonna select the first one we're going to upload our own code and this code is available
for you in the resources section.
So I'm just going to hit upload choose file.
So we're going to go with Version 1 first and the zip file it just contains a docker file and an application
file as well.
And the docker file it just contains some instructions for building out our Docker image and then the
application Doc pi is the python code and it's just a simple website and the combination of the docker
file and the application Doc pi is gonna be used to create a really simple web application and for the
exam you won't be tested on how to write Python code.
The main thing that they're going to test you on is that you know how to deploy a docker container in
a plastic beanstalk.
So coming back to the console I'm going to select version one of our ZIP file it open and before you
upload just notice that it gives you this version label which is a unique name for this version of your
application code.
So once you've selected your file just hit upload and create application and it does take a couple of
minutes to spin everything up.
So just be patient.
And I'm just going to pause the video now until that has completed.
So now that has successfully completed and it took about I think it took about four minutes.
So hopefully after a few minutes you should have a similar result to me and you should see a big green
tech health OK and all the recent events appearing down here on the bottom of the screen.
So once that is already at the top of the screen you'll see and you are all like this.
And if you open that link in a new tab in your browser it's going to take you to a Web site which is
being served from your docker container.
So congratulations your docker container is now running an Elastic Beanstalk on your own dedicated environment
in the W.S. cloud so you can see how easy it is to get a docker application up and running using Elastic
Beanstalk.
And now we're going to go and upgrade our application to another version so come back to your Elastic
Beanstalk dashboard and we're going to hit upload and deploy select choose file and we're going to select
version two of our application and it's automatically going to apply a new version label.
So just go ahead and hit deploy
and Elastic Beanstalk is now updating our environment and it's that easy to update the code within your
Elastic Beanstalk environment.
So once again it's going to take a couple of minutes to complete.
So I'm just going to pause the video and wait a few minutes and see if that has completed.
Okay.
So that has now completed and it didn't actually take as long as the first time because it's only deploying
all code it's not actually going in and creating two instances.
And if that has been successful we can head back to our Web site hit refresh and there is a new version.
So great work everyone you just deployed.
Version two of your Docker application and one lost really cool thing that I wanted to show you is that
you can really easily revert back to previous versions so if you head back to the console and hit upload
and deploy you'll see this message at the top saying to deploy a previous version go to the application
versions page.
So if you click on application versions you'll see your previous version and your current version as
well.
So you can just select the previous version and go in and deploy that version if you want to roll back
to your previous version and once you've finished exploring the console you can really easily terminate
everything.
So if we go back to environments hit actions and you can just select delete application and hit delete
and that will just take care of deleting the entire Elastic Beanstalk environment for you.
So moving on to the exam tips for Elastic Beanstalk and docker if you're using Elastic Beanstalk remember
that you can deploy a docker container to a single easy to instance and you can also use Elastic Beanstalk
to deploy multiple Docker instances to an elastic container service cluster.
And if you want to deploy a docker application all you do is upload your code bundle to Elastic Beanstalk.
And if you want to upgrade your application to a new version it's really easy.
It's just one step in the console.
You just upload the next version of your code and Elastic Beanstalk will deploy that for you and it
will also manage previous versions of your code as well.
And as we did in the lab code can be uploaded directly from your local machine or it can also be uploaded
from an S3 bucket as well.
And alternatively you can also store your code in code commit you're not restricted to just storing
it on your local machine or in S3.
So it is possible to use code commit but if you want to do that you must administer Elastic Beanstalk
and your deployment using the Elastic Beanstalk come online interface.
And that's actually out of scope for the exam.
So you don't need to be able to use the Elastic Beanstalk Cielo but it is worth noting that you can
store your code in code commit and have that integrated with your Elastic Beanstalk environment.
So that is the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.