Hello talkers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is just a recap on all the additional resources
that you can use to help you prepare for your exam.
So we're going to be talking about the FAA cuz the white papers and the reinvent videos which are all
worth reviewing before you do the exam.
So first of all with the official AWOL FAA Qs and you can use these to find answers to commonly raised
questions about a W S services and they are written in a really concise way.
So it's just a really easy way to check your understanding or double check that you've remembered everything
correctly about a particular w s service.
We're also going to talk about the white papers that you can read and these contain a wealth of information
about a W as recommended architectures.
Some really good diagrams as well as general guidance and best practices.
And then finally we're going to cover some of the reinvent videos which are worth watching and these
often contain a lot of information about best practices deep dives as well as demos.
So let's take a look at the main cues that you should pay attention to.
For the developer associate and I've tried to group them together into loose categories.
So first of all we have the surveillance technologies.
So basically the main technologies that you would use to build service applications.
So think lambda API Gateway dynamo DP and elastic cache and also S3.
Secondly the development tools that you'd want to read up on or code commit code pipeline code deploy
and code build under security.
It's going to be identity access management Cockney toe and K M.S. for automation and monitoring.
Make sure you look at Elastic Beanstalk and cloud formation on the automation side.
And for monitoring look at cloud watch an x ray for containers you're going to need to know about elastic
container service an elastic container registry.
So definitely read through the FAA cues for those and for messaging and streaming it's Eskew us and
Kenneth this annual find all of the FAA cues on this page.
It's a W S dot Amazon dot com forward slash FAA kids and there's a link to this page in the resources
section of this lecture so you can basically just come to this page and find the FAA cute that you're
looking for.
So here's the lander thank you.
And you'll see it's just a really simple series of questions and answers and it's something that you
can really easily read through if you're having a break at work or if you've just finished listening
to a lambda lecture so moving on to the White Papers and here is a list of our favorite white papers.
And these are all well worth reading before you take the exam because they're full of a W as best practices
and sometimes they'll also just give you a new perspective on the same material.
And don't worry there are links to all of these white papers in the resources section of the course.
But for developer associate it's mainly white papers to do with continuous integration.
Blue green deployments dev ops processes.
There's also service architectures with Lambda.
There's a really good one which covers Docker on a W S as well as optimizing your architecture using
surplus containerized micro services on a W S and of course a w s security best practices and that one
is important for all of the associate level certifications.
Now you might be thinking please no more white papers and I know they can be a bit long and a bit of
a drag.
Read some of them or even 100 pages long.
But I do have a few tips for getting the most out of them.
So first of all when I go to read a white paper first of all I don't just start reading it like a novel.
It's definitely not bedtime reading.
Instead I just browse through the entire document paying attention to the structure of the document.
Any headings tables diagrams etc. and I just try to get a feel for the material and then only once I've
finished browsing the document I just revisit this.
Only the sections that I think are worth reading so I try not to spend too much time reading over stuff
that I already know really really well.
For example if you already know identity access management policies really really well then just skip
through that bit.
Don't read over material that you already know.
I also try to keep in mind what I expect to get out of the White Paper.
So for example if I'm reading a white paper on security best practices I try not to get too bogged down
in the background detail and you really have to have a laser focus on what you expect to get out of
the white paper.
And then finally I always take notes and I don't mean pages and pages of notes just a few pointers or
keywords that you can review later on.
So basically anything new or anything that's coming from a slightly different perspective or anything
that you're struggling to remember.
So I just note that down so that I can review it later on if I need to.
And finally if you hate reading there are loads of really good reinvent videos available on the Internet.
And these are really good ones to watch.
If you really can't stomach reading a white paper and there are so many of these available I've just
listed my favorite ones to look out for when you're studying for the developer associate.
So you've got become an I am policy master.
There's also one on continuous integration best practices moving to dev ops the Amazon way.
Getting started with Docker services architecture patterns and best practices and VPC fundamentals and
connectivity options and I've included links to all of these in the resources section of the course.
But of course you can always just head to YouTube and search for the technology that you're looking
for and you'll find loads of official reinvent videos available so I normally just head over to youtube
and search for a W.S. reinvent.
I and this will bring up all the relevant reinvent videos which are related to continuous integration.
So there's our continuous integration best practices.
There's also the IAM policy master that's coming up in this search as well for some reason VPC fundamentals
moving to dev ops deployment scenarios so you can see there's absolutely loads of official reinvent
videos and the great thing about YouTube is that you can watch everything on double speed if you want
to and these videos are sort of 40 to 50 minutes long so you can definitely get time to watch those
on your lunch hour.
So that is all the additional resources that I wanted to let you know about and they are all well worth
reviewing.
Before you go ahead and take the exam and don't worry there are links to everything in the resources
section of the course.
So that is the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.