Hello bloggers and welcome to this lecture.
And this is just a really quick summary of everything that we've covered in this chapter and it's all
based on student feedback and designed to help you get a few extra points in the exam.
Starting off with a W S CLIA pudgy nation.
Now if you're using the IWC CLIA and you see errors like timed out or errors relating to too many results
being returned then it's likely that you have an issue relating to too many results being returned to
your CLIA output and the way that you deal with that is you adjust the pageant portion of CLIA requests
to avoid errors being generated by too many results and you don't need to remember this command for
the exam.
The main thing that you need to remember is that we are changing the page size.
So just try and keep in mind that we're changing the page size to return fewer results per page.
And when we do this the command line still retrieves the full list of results but it performs a greater
number of API calls in the background and retrieves a smaller number of items with each call.
And that's going to avoid you getting the errors generated by too many results in each API call.
Moving on to the identity access management policy simulator and the policy simulator enables you to
test identity access management permissions before you commit them into production so you can use the
policy simulator to validate that the policy works as expected and you can also test policies attached
to existing users.
And that is really good for troubleshooting if you suspect that something within your NWS account is
not working as expected and you suspect that it's something to do with an identity access management
policy so you can just go into the simulator and test whether that action would be allowed by any policy
attached to your user group or role and the simulator will tell you whether that action would be allowed
or not.
Just remember that you can use the excuse us delay Q If you need to postpone the delivery of new messages
messages in your delay queue remain invisible for the duration of the delay period and it's zero by
default.
Up to 900 seconds or 15 minutes and you can use delay queues for large distributed applications which
might need to introduce a delay in processing in order to avoid errors in the application and for managing
large messages in rescuers.
Just remember our exam tips.
So if you have large messages up to 2 gig store them in S3 and in order to do that you're going to need
to have an S3 Buckets and you'll also need to use the w w SDK for Java as well as the escudos extended
client library for Java as well.
And just remember you can't do this using the regular a SC ally or the management console or the escudos
API.
Moving on can easiest shards and just remember the Cooney says client library is running on your consumers
and it's the easiest client library which creates a record processor for each Canisius shard which is
being consumed by your instance.
And when you increase the number of shots the carnitas client library will add more record processors
on your consumers.
And just remember that it's CPE utilization which should drive the quantity of consumer instances you
have not the number of shards in your Canisius stream.
So if you do increase the number of shards if you reach shard and increase the number of shards say
from 4 to 8 then it is not required to increase the quantity of consumer instances.
You should definitely base that on utilization not the number of shards.
And finally it's best practice to use an auto scaling group and base scaling decisions on the CPE you
load of your consumers.
Moving on to lambda and the lambda concurrent executions limit.
All you need to know for the exam is that a limit exists and you don't really need to remember the number.
I just think it's helpful to know that it's a thousand concurrent executions per second and of course
if you're running a service website a busy website like a cloud guru it's definitely likely that you're
going to hit the limit at some point.
And if you do hit the limit then you're going to start seeing invocations being rejected.
So you will see lambda functions failing to be launched and new invocations of lambda functions being
rejected and you are likely to see a 4 to 9 HDP status code and the remedy for this is just to request
a limit raised from a w s support which you can do from the console.
And there's also a reserved concurrency which you can apply.
And this guarantees a set number of concurrent executions are always available to your critical functions
so you can go in and set a reserve concurrency for example for 500 concurrent executions for a critical
function and or guarantee that there's always 500 concurrent executions available to that function.
Moving onto lambda versions and $ latest is always the last version of the code that you uploaded to
lambda and you can use lambda versioning and aliases to point your applications to a specific version.
If you don't want to use dollar latest for example if you had different versions of your code for development
test and production environments you can set up versioning and aliases to point to those different versions
of your code base.
And here is an example of an alias for our production system.
So the alias is called prod and it's in the form of an Amazon resource name.
So that's what your applications would use if they want to refer to that prot alias version of our code.
And if you want your applications to always use the latest version you would just use the IRS n with
dollar latest at the end and finally just remember that if your application is using an alias instead
of dollar latest then remember that it will not automatically use new code when you upload it.
So for example if your application is pointing to the prod alias it's going to continue to use the version
of Code referenced by the alias.
Even when you upload new code into lambda so if you've uploaded new code into lambda and you're wondering
why your application is still launching the old version of code it could well be that you're pointing
to an alias rather than using the dollar latest version.
Moving onto lambda and accessing resources in your private VPC.
Just remember it's possible to enable lambda to access resources in your private VPC but it is not enabled
by default.
And in order to set this up you're going to need to provide VPC config information to the function in
the form of a private subnet I.D. add a security group.
And remember that lambda uses this VPC information to set up elastic network interfaces using an IP
address from the private subnet slider range and then the security group allows your function to access
the resources in your VPC.
Moving all it to x ray high level configuration steps so x ray integrates with many w services like
dynamo D.B. lambda API Gateway etc..
So you really need the minimum amount of configuration in order to set these services up for x ray.
However you can also instrument your own applications to send data into x ray and applications could
be running on easy to an elastic beanstalk environments and also on your on premises systems located
in your own data center and also in a plastic container service.
So you do just need to be aware of the different ways of setting up x ray depending where you are running
your application and for elastic container service in particular you need to know that you have to run
the x ray daemon on its own Docker image running alongside your application because of course with Docker
and with a micro services based architecture a micro service generally takes care of one task only and
you wouldn't expect a docker container to be running more than one micro service so the x ray daemon
runs within its own Docker image running alongside your application and when it comes to configuring
x ray you're going to need three things.
So first of all you need the x ray SDK.
You also need the x ray Daemon to be running on your system.
So either on your easy to instance or you're on premises host and then the last step is that you need
to instrument your application using the x ray SDK to configure your application to send the required
data into x ray.
For example you might want to send data about incoming or outgoing HDTV requests to and from your application.
And finally remember that you can record application specific information in the form of key value pairs
which you define for example for a tic tac toe game.
You might want to record the game name or the game I.D. and its annotations which allows you to do that.
So just remember that name is called annotations and it allows you to add user defined key value pairs
to your x ray data which in turn allows you to filter index and search within x ray so it allows you
to group x ray results together.
And so in this example it would allow you to group the data based on the game name or the game I.D.
and finally moving on to elastic beanstalk and docker.
So when you're using elastic beanstalk you can deploy your docker container to a single easy to instance
and you can also deploy multiple docker containers to an elastic container service cluster and Elastic
Beanstalk will handle all of the infrastructure for you.
And if you remember in the lab all we had to do was upload our code and Elastic Beanstalk took care
of provisioning and easy to instance for our code to run on.
So to deploy a docker application just upload your code bundle to Elastic Beanstalk and when you want
to upgrade your application to a new version it's just one easy step in the console to upload and deploy
your new version and code can be uploaded directly from your local machine.
As we did in the lab or you can also supply the name of a public S3 bucket containing your code bundle
as well.
And finally you can also store your code in code commit.
But if you do that you must administer your elastic beanstalk environment using the Elastic Beanstalk
command line interface.
And don't worry too much about the Elastic Beanstalk CLIA because they're not going to test you on that
in the exam.
The important thing to note is that code commit integrates with Elastic Beanstalk and you can actually
store your code there as well as on your local machine and in a public S3 bucket so that is the end
of this lecture and is also at the end of this section of the course.
So if you have any questions or if you go and take the exam and you see any topics which we haven't
covered within the course please do let us know in the course forum so that we can update the course
and make it the best it can be.
So with that said thank you very much and we'll see you in the next lecture.