Hello bloggers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about Eskew.
Delay cues and also managing large messages in Eskew s.
So let's get started.
So what are rescuers delay cues.
Well these allow you to postpone the delivery of new messages in escudos so you can postpone the delivery
to a queue for a number of seconds.
And this means that any messages sent into the delay queue actually remain invisible to any consumers
of the queue for the duration of a delay period which you set and the default delay for a delay queue
is zero seconds and the maximum is nine hundred seconds which is 15 minutes.
So for standard excuse queues this doesn't affect the delivery or the visibility of any messages which
are already in the queue.
It's only going to affect new messages arriving in the queue.
However if it's a FIFO queue this is going to affect the delay of any message which is already in the
queue.
So when should you use a delay queue.
Well with large distributed applications you might need to introduce a delay in processing somewhere
along the line for your application.
You might even need to apply a delay to an entire queue of messages.
For example imagine an online retail application where you might want to introduce a delay of a few
seconds in order to allow for updates to a sales or stock control database before sending out notifications
to your customers confirming an online transaction.
So for delay queues the main thing that you need to know is what they are and what they can be used
for.
So just remember that they can be used to delay or postpone the delivery of new messages in escudos.
Moving on to managing large messages in escudos while the best practice for managing large escudos messages
is to actually use s three and when we say large ask us messages I mean messages which are over 256
killer bytes and up to two gigs in size.
So the main thing to remember is that you can use S3 to store these messages but in order to do that
there's a couple of things you're going to need to also configure.
So first of all you're going to need the Amazon escudos extended to client library for Java and this
is going to allow you to manage the messages when they're in S3 and you'll also need the W.S. SDK for
Java as well.
And that just provides an API for the S3 Buckets and object operations.
So it's that SDK which allows you to get and put and delete objects from the S3 Buckets.
So in order to use S3 to store your messages you're actually going to need both of those both the extended
client library and also the SDK for Java.
So the rescuers extended client library for Java.
It allows you to specify that messages are either always stored in S3 or only the messages over a certain
size.
For example only the messages over two hundred and fifty six kilobytes.
It also allows you to send a message referencing a message object which is stored in S3 and also get
an delete message objects from S3 now you don't need to know how to set this up for the exam.
The main thing that you need to know for the exam is that when you're dealing with large messages in
escudos it's really useful to be able to store them in S3.
And for that you're going to need the W.S. SDK for Java.
The Eskew has extended library for Java.
Of course you're going to need an S3 bucket as well and you can't just use the normal a WSOC Ally.
You can't do it using only the console.
The NWS management console or the ESC U.S. console you can't do this using just the escudos API or any
of the other a W S SDK.
So just remember the things that you're going to need to use in order to manage your large excuse messages.
So moving on to our exam tips.
Just remember that you can use the excuse us delay queue if you need to postpone the delivery of new
messages messages in your delay queue remain invisible for the duration of the delay period and it's
zero by default up to 900 seconds or 15 minutes and you can use delay queues for large distributed applications
which might need to introduce a delay in processing in order to avoid errors in the application and
for managing large messages in rescuers.
Just remember our exam tips.
So if you have large messages up to 2 gig store them in S3 and in order to do that you're going to need
to have an S3 Buckets and you'll also need to use the w w SDK for Java as well as the escudos extended
client library for Java as well.
And just remember you can't do this using the regular a W SC ally or the management console or the escudos
API so that is everything that you should need to know about delay queues and managing large messages
in escudos using S3.
If you have any questions please do let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.