Hello bloggers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about a W S C L I pudgy nation.
So what does that mean.
Well with CLIA Padgett nation you can actually control the number of items included in the output when
you run an A W S CLIA command and by default it's going to return a thousand items per API call and
they call that the page size.
So by default the WSJ CLIA uses a page size of 1000.
But what if you want to run a command which is going to return more than a thousand objects.
So for example if you ran a W S S3 API list objects on a bucket which contains over 2000 objects.
So for example if it contained 2500 objects then the CLIA is actually going to make three separate API
calls to S3 but then it's gonna display the entire output in one go.
So it's actually making those three API calls in the background.
However for some situations you might find that this default page size of 1000 is actually too high.
For example if you see errors when you're running list commands on a large number of resources.
For example if you had an S3 bucket with well over a thousand objects and you would join to list the
individual objects within the S3 bucket you might see something like a time out or timed out error because
the API calls have exceeded the maximum allowed time to fetch the required results.
So it's just taking too long to return at the number of results that you have.
So how do you fix this.
Well you can actually adjust the default page size when you run your command and you basically just
add this minus minus page size option to tell the CLIA to request a smaller number of items from each
API call.
So the CLIA will still retrieve the full list of objects but it's just going to perform a larger number
of API calls in the background so it makes multiple API calls to get your results and then retrieves
a smaller number of items with each call and then it will just return to you the full list of items.
So I've got a couple of commands to show you.
So the first one is this a W S S3 API.
List objects and then you specify the bucket name and then you can actually specify the page size at
the end.
And in this example we're setting the page size to 100 instead of a thousand.
So if you had an S3 Buckets which contained over a thousand items and you wanted to limit the page size
to 100 it would just end up making over 10 API calls to get the results and then it will just return
all of the results to you in one go.
And then there's this other option that you can use with the list objects command.
And it's called Max items and this allows you to return fewer items in the CLIA output.
So in the example command we've got a W S S3 API.
List objects and then we're setting the bucket to my bucket and then we're setting the max items to
100.
So in this case instead of returning all of the items in the bucket it's just going to return at the
first 100.
So now I'm just gonna show you how to use those commands in the terminal.
And don't worry you don't actually need to know how to use these commands for the exam.
I'm just showing you because it's fun and to give you that background.
So here I am in the terminal window and I don't have a bucket which has thousands of objects in it but
I do have one that's got about 20 objects so that should be enough to show you the commands and show
you how they work.
So first of all I'm going to use this S3 API list object's command and this is just going to list all
of the objects in my bucket.
So there we are.
That's all my objects and I've got around 20 or just over 20 objects in this bucket so that's my output.
And I'm now going to run that same command again and I'm going to use a page size of five and I'm gonna
use a really low page size because we've only got 20 items in the bucket so I'm just gonna hit that
command again.
And there we are.
You'll see that even though we have a page size of five it's actually still retrieving all 20 objects
from my bucket.
So it's running multiple API calls to retrieve the contents of my bucket but it just returns it all
in one go as though it was just running it in one single command and then the other command I wanted
to show you is using the max items option.
And here is the command.
So we're still running exactly the same AWOL S3 API list objects we're specifying the bucket name.
And then we just add the minus minus Max items on the end of that command.
And I'm just going to set the max items to 1 hit enter and there we are.
It just returns the first item it comes to.
So that is just another way or another option for dealing with this timeout error.
And don't worry you don't need to know how to use these commands for the exam.
I'm just showing you because it makes it a little bit more interesting and a little bit easier to understand.
So what are our exam tips for a W.S. CLIA pageant Asian.
You just need to remember that if you do see errors like timed out or errors relating to too many results
being returned to a CLIA command all you need to do is adjust the pageant portion of the CLIA results
and that will help avoid any errors getting generated by too many results.
And in order to do that you just add the minus minus page size and adjust your page size so that it's
below the default of 1000.
And when you do this the CLIA is still going to retrieve the full list.
It just performs a larger number of API calls in the background but it will still return the full set
of results.
So that is everything that you should need to know for the exam about CLIA pudgy nation and dealing
with timeout errors on the CLIA.
If you have any questions please let me know if not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.