Hello bloggers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about testing identity access management
permissions.
So how can you test your identity access management permissions.
Well there's this really great tool that you might not be aware of.
And it's called the I am policy simulator.
And this is a really cool feature which allows you to test the effects of identity access management
policies before you go ahead and commit them to production so you can use the I am policy simulator
to validate that a policy works as expected.
You can also use it to test policies which are already attached to existing users which is really great
for troubleshooting any issues where something's going wrong within a WAC and you suspect that it could
be identity access management related.
And let's face it if you've been working with a W S for a while oftentimes when something goes wrong
and it doesn't work as expected it can often be an authorization issue.
So can often be related to an identity access management policy not having the permissions that you
expect or not having enough permissions to do the things you're asking it to do and make the relevant
API calls.
So this is where the I am policy simulator comes in and you can access it using HD G.P.S. policy Sim
dot a w w or Amazon dot com and I'll also include a link in the resources section of the course as well
so you can just click on the link but I'm just going to show you it in action right now.
So here I am in the policy simulator so I'm gonna just start off in the user section and on the left
hand side you should see all the users which exist in your NWS account and if you've been working through
our labs or you've already been using a W S for a while you'll probably have a few different user accounts
to choose from.
But I'm just gonna go in and select this user called C.C. user which is one that we used earlier on
in the course for the code commit lab.
So I'm just gonna select that user and straightaway on the left hand side under I am policies it will
show you the policies which apply to this user.
So these are the policies that have been attached to my user.
And you can use the simulator to test whether a certain action is allowed or not by the policies attached
to the user.
So first of all I'm gonna go in and select a service and I'm going to select Athena because I think
this user it's got code commit full access and it's got access to the easy to contain a registry as
well for the elastic container service.
So it definitely doesn't have any permissions for Athena and I'm gonna go in and select an action just
select run query and then I'm gonna hit run that simulation.
And then under the results it should tell you whether the action that we've selected.
So that run a query for Athena so it should tell us whether that would be allowed or denied based on
these policies.
And it's showing us permission denied so implicitly denied because there are no matching statements
relating to that action.
So now I'm gonna clear my results.
And now let's try and simulate an action which should be allowed.
So this user has got code commit full access so allows you to do all of these different actions in relation
to code commit.
So I'm gonna change all service to code commit and I think they're in alphabetical order.
There is code commit select an action just going to select the very first action and hit run simulation
and straightaway you should see that has been allowed.
We have one matching statement so click here for details and we can see that it's in this code commit
full access policy we can show the statement and it will even find that statement for us there.
So you can see it's actually a really cool feature which allows you to simulate actions and it will
let you know whether those actions would be allowed or denied based on the policies attached to your
user.
I'm just going to hit back in the left hand side panel back again.
And you can see you can actually select groups or roles as well so you can go in and run those same
simulations.
Based on different groups so you select a group select a service and select an action and run a simulation
and you can do the same for roles as well.
So that is the I am policy simulator and it's definitely worth spending a few minutes having a play
around with it.
But as you can see it's pretty simple to use.
So let's move on and take a look at some of our exam tips.
So our exam tips for the I.M. policy simulator are you just really need to know what it is and what
you can use it for.
So it allows you to test identity access management permissions before going ahead and committing them
to production.
For example if he had some IBM permissions attached to a test user group or role you could go in and
use the simulator to test the permissions before adding those permissions to your production accounts.
You can also use it to validate that existing policies work as you expect and you can test policies
attached to existing users groups or roles.
And this is really good for troubleshooting and it just making sure that your policies work as expected.
And finally you can access it using this link.
So it's just HDP P.S. policy Sim dot a W S dot Amazon dot com.
So that is the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.