Hello loggers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about canisters shards.
Relative to consumers.
So this is going to be just a quick recap on cornices to begin with and hopefully you remember that
he says is a service which allows you to collect and process and analyze real time streaming data.
So for example that could be unstructured data like click stream data video or audio data application
logs etc..
And if you remember a consistent stream is made up of a set of multiple shots and each shard is a sequence
of data records each with their own unique sequence number and the data capacity of your stream is the
sum total of the capacity of all of its shots and each shard gives you five read transactions per second
up to a maximum of two megabytes per second and you also get 1000 right records per second up to a maximum
of one megabyte per second.
So as your data rate goes up as it increases then you will also need to increase the number of shards
to handle the increase in your data.
And when we increase the number of shards that is known as reshooting.
But what about the consumers.
And when we say consumers it really means the easy two instances which are consuming data from your
stream and on the consumer you've got the consistent client library and the carnitas client library
tracks the number of shards that exist in your stream.
And it also discovers when you shards are added so you increase the number of shots from four to six.
It's the closest client library which is going to detect that and respond accordingly.
So the genesis client library ensures that for every shard there is a record processor and it's the
record processors which actually process the data which is being streamed on your niece's stream and
the client library manages the number of record processors relative to the number of shards and consumers.
So if you only have one consumer instance then the carnitas client library is going to create all of
the record processors on that single consumer instance.
However if you have two or more consumer instances it's going to load balance across all of those consumer
instances and it will create an equal number of record processors on each instance.
So for example if you have two consumer instances it's going to load balance across those two and it
will create half the processors on one instance and half on the other.
But let's have a look at the diagram again and hopefully it will make a lot more sense.
So in this example we have one this data stream and we've got four shards in the stream and then the
right hand side you've got one consumer instances and that one consumer instance is processing all four
shards of the stream and therefore you have four record processors which are running on that single
consumer.
But what happens if we add another consumer instance.
So I say we add another one for fail over purposes.
So we've got two consumers and they're still processing four shards within a single canister stream
and you've got the easiest client libraries running on each of the consumer instances.
And you have to record processors running on each consumer and the easiest client library will handle
the load balancing of the load between the two consumers.
But what about scaling out the consumers.
Well with a can assist client library generally you should ensure that the number of instances does
not exceed the number of shots except of course for failure or standby purposes and you never need to
use multiple instances to handle the processing load of one Shahed and if you remember the processing
load of one shard it's only up to a maximum of two megabytes of reader transactions per second and one
megabyte of right transactions per second.
So you definitely are not going to need to have more than one easy to instance to process that small
amount of load per shard and of course one worker or one consumer can definitely process multiple shots
as we've seen in this diagram here where we have two consumers and each of them are processing two shots
each so it's definitely fine if the number of shots exceeds the number of instances and do not think
that just because you Rashaad and you add more shots to your canvases stream that that means that you
should add more instances because it definitely does not mean that.
And instead you should use CPO utilization as the factor that should drive the quantity of consumer
instances you have.
Definitely not the number of shots in your canisters stream and of course the best practice would be
to use an auto scaling group and base your scaling decisions on CPE load of your consumers.
So let's take another look at the diagram and this diagram just shows you what happens if we reshot.
So we started off with four shots in our stream and we've reshot it and there's now a total of six shots
in our canisters stream and we've still got two easy two instances which are the consumers.
So we want to load balance between those equally and we've increased the number of record processes.
So three on each of our consumers.
And of course that is all handled automatically by the Kansas client library.
You don't have to do anything yourself.
So let's move onto our exam tips for Kansas shards and fill the exam.
You do not need to know exactly how to set this up or anything like that you don't need to know it at
a low level detail.
You just really need to be aware that on your consumer instances it's the easiest client library that's
doing all of this work of managing the number of record processors and the easiest client library creates
a record processor for each shard which is being consumed by your instance.
And if you increase the number of shards so you reshot on your stream the easiest client library is
going to add more record processors on your consumers and it will split them equally between the number
of consumers that you have and then finally always use CPR utilization as the driver for increasing
the number of consumer instances you have.
Don't think that just because you'll be shopping you should increase the number of consumer instances.
And for best practice use and auto scanning group and based those automatic scaling decisions on CPR
you load on your consumers.
So that is everything that you should need to know about Canisius shards for the exam.
If you have any questions please do let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.