Hello tigers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to cover the lambda concurrent executions
limit.
Now for the exam it's not actually necessary to remember loads and loads of limits so they're not really
going to test you on what's the limit for this and what's the limit for that but for lambda you do need
to be aware that there is a concurrent execution limit and that means it's basically a limit on the
number of functions that can be run simultaneously within the same region.
So do just be aware that there is this concurrent execution limit and it's basically a safety feature
to limit the number of concurrent executions across all functions in a given region per account.
And the default is 1000 concurrent executions per region.
And if you do hit the limit then you will see an error message and the error message is too many requests
exception and you might also see this HBP status code of four to nine and 1000 concurrent executions.
It's only the default and you can actually request that they increase that limit so you will need to
contact a W US support but you can do that through the console and you can just request that the limit
is increased so just be aware that if you have many lambda functions and they're all running in the
same region and then you suddenly start seeing new invocation requests being rejected then it may well
be that you've hit your limit and actually at a cloud guru or daily usage is around six point five million
lambda invocations per day every time you log onto our platform and you launch a new course or you start
a new lecture in the background it's actually a lambda function which is making everything happen and
yet we have six point five million lambda invocations per day and we run out of one region at the moment
so it's all running from U.S. East 1.
So as you can imagine for a busy website it is definitely possible to hit that limit.
And as I said before you can just request an increase by submitting a request to the AWB support center
or alternatively you can also configure something called reserved concurrency.
And this guarantees that a set number of executions will always be available for any critical functions.
So for example if you had a whole load of different functions and some were highly critical whereas
others were not so important to your application or to your business you can reserve some concurrency
for those critical functions to make sure that there's always a set number of concurrent executions
available for those critical functions.
However do be aware that it also does act as a limit.
So for example if you set a reserved concurrency of 500 for a specific function that specific function
will never be able to go over 500 concurrent executions.
So onto our exam tips.
Basically all you need to know about concurrent executions is that there is a limit so the limit is
1000 concurrent executions per second.
And of course just imagine you're running a service website like a cloud guru.
It's very likely that you would hit that limit at some point.
And if you do hit that limit you will start to see invocations being rejected and you'll start to see
HDP status code 4 2 9.
And the remedy is either get the limit raised by AWP support or if you just have a few very critical
functions then you can set a reserved concurrency to guarantee that a set number of concurrent executions
are always available to your critical functions.
So that is everything that you should need to know about the lambda concurrent executions limit if you
have any questions please let me know if not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.