Hello kangaroos and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about lambda virgins.
So when you create a new lambda function there is only one version and they attach this label or this
alias to it and it's called latest And When you upload a new version of the code to Lambda then the
new version that you upload will become latest.
But you can actually create multiple versions of your function code and then use different aliases to
reference the different versions so you can refer to the specific version that you want to use within
your application.
Using an R N or Amazon resource name for example in a development environment you might want to maintain
a few different versions of the same function as you develop and test and change your code and an alias
is the way to do that.
So you can create different versions of the same function called for example development test production
etc. and an alias is just like a pointer to a specific version of the function code.
So in this example we have a developer on the left hand side and they are busy updating their code and
adding new code into an S3 bucket and within lambda we've got our version 1 2 which we've applied an
alias called prod.
And we've also got a version 2 which also happens to be the latest version of the code and that version
too has an alias of test so we can reference each of these aliases using the Amazon resource name.
And it's the Amazon resource name that we use to call the function.
So if we want to use the latest version of the code we can refer to it using the IRS and which ends
in latest.
Or we could also alternatively use the N which ends in test which uses the test alias.
But if we want it to use our version one of the code our production version then we use the IRS in it
which ends in prod.
But what happens if we add another version.
So let's say for example we upload another version of our code to Lambda.
Well when you upload new code to lambda and that new code is going to become the latest version but
we've still got our aliases for the prod and test versions.
So version 1 and version 2.
But if your application is using an alias to refer to the function then do remember to update the IRS
that you're using.
If you want to use the new code because if you're using the alias of test or prod then you're still
gonna be pointing to version one of its broad version too if its test so your application will continue
to use basically the original code or the previous version of the code and if you want your application
to use the latest version you need to make sure that it is referring to the IRS in using the label latest.
But the best way to understand all of this is if I show you what I mean in the console and you'll see
how easy it is to set up Virgin numbers and aliases as well and how easy it is to find these Amazon
resource names.
So here I am in the console and I'm just gonna head over to compute and Lambda create function and make
sure you've selected author from scratch I'm gonna give my function a name.
I'm going to call it my lambda make sure that the runtime is no J.S. 10 and click on Create function
and then once that's done just scroll down to the function code section and we're going to upload a
zip file and the zip files are going to be in the resources section of the course such as download them
to your local machine and select the first one and the first one is called V1 dot zip so upload that
one hit save and there's our function and it should site.
This is version 1 so we're then going to configure a test event gonna call it T1
it creates and test come up to the top and check the execution result.
So there we go.
Hello from lambda.
This is version 1 and just notice at the top of the page this is where you'll find the R N so the Amazon
resource name.
So that is the either end of our function and if we head down to qualifiers you'll find it's already
created this latest alias.
So if we select that one it will take us to the latest version of our code and it's like the version
that we've just uploaded.
So if we go and look at the function code there you go.
This is version 1 so it's already automatically been labeled as latest and there's a R N so now I'm
going to add another version and an alias so I'm gonna go into actions.
I'm not gonna publish a version based on this latest.
So it creates the snapshot of the code and configuration of the latest version.
So I'm gonna give it a description
and hit publish so there we go we've got version 1.
I also notice that version 1 it's got its own HRN So there we go.
Version 1 and we can also go in and create an alias.
So if you click on actions and create alias and we can give our alias a name and I'm gonna call this
one prod and give it a description
and then we select the version.
So is it gonna be the latest or is it gonna be our version one.
So let's make it out version one and hit create.
So that is our alias created.
And you can see the alias has got its own a R N so now what if we had a new version of our code that
we wanted to start testing with.
Well let's go back to our function down to the function code and upload a new zip file so this time
we're going to use version 2.0 zip hit save there's our version too and run a test again scroll up to
the top to see the results.
There we are.
Hello from lambda.
This is virgin 2.
And once again if you look at the top right hand side you'll find the end.
And if we want to look at the latest version click on the latest version scroll down to our function
code and you should see that it says version two down here.
So you'll see that the latest version has automatically updated to be pointing at the latest code that
we just uploaded.
And if we want to create a new version within lambda we can go to publish new version.
So this is gonna be our version number two.
And I'm gonna give it a description.
So this is a new version of our code which needs to be tested.
So that is our version too.
We can also go in and create an alias and I'm gonna make an alias of test an all test systems should
use this alias and it's gonna be version two and hit create and there is the origin of our test alias
and you can actually see all of the aliases down here and which version they are relating to.
And when it says unqualified up here it actually means that you're just using the initial portion of
the Irene up to the name of your function and you're not qualifying it with a dollar latest or.
Version 1 version 2 or any alias name it just means that you're only using the lambda function name
itself.
And when you use it on qualified you will default to using the dollar latest version so hopefully that'll
show you how easy it is to create inversions and aliases in lambda.
So moving on to our exam tips.
Just remember that the dollar latest is always the latest version of the code you've uploaded into lambda
and use lambda versioning and aliases to point your applications to a specific version.
If you don't want to use the dollar latest and remember if you don't use any alias at all and you just
use an unqualified R N so just ending in the function name not using prod or latest or whatever then
that will default to using the latest version.
And finally if your application is using an alias remember that it will not automatically use new code
when you upload it.
So if you are using an alias and you're uploading new code that you want your application to use then
just remember to update your application to point at the latest version of the code.
So that is everything that I wanted to tell you about lambda versions.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.