Hello tigers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to cover lambda and V.P. seas but
more specifically enabling lambda functions to access resources in your VPC.
So let's get started now.
As a developer you may well see a situation or a use case where you are developing a lambda function
and it needs to be able to communicate with or access resources which are inside a private VPC in a
private subnet with no access to the outside world.
For example imagine a service website running on lambda which needs to read or write data from an audio
database or alternatively a lambda function which goes in and shuts down a compromised easy to instance
in response to a security alert.
So those are just a couple of examples of situations where you may need to enable access to VPC resources
for your lambda functions.
So how can we enable this because by default your lambda function will not be able to access any resources
within a private VPC without some additional configuration.
So basically you need to allow the function to connect to the private subnet and Lambda will need the
following VPC configuration information so that it can go in and connect to resources in your VPC.
So first of all you're going to need to provide the private subnet I.D. where your resources are located.
You also need to provide a security group I.D. with specific access for the lambda function to allow
it to do what it needs to do and lambda is going to use this information to set up an elastic network
interface or an eye using an available IP address from the side a range of your private subnet and you
can add this VPC information to your lambda function using the command line and you just need to use
the VPC dash config parameter.
And here is an example of the command that you can use to do that.
So it's a W S lambda update function configuration.
And this is if you're updating an existing function so you need to then provide the name of your function.
And in this example the function is called My function.
And then finally at the end you provide the VPC config information.
So we provide the subnet I.D. and the security group I.D. as well and it's going to use the subnet I.D.
to identify a spare IP address to assign it to the elastic network interface for the lambda function
and it's gonna use the security group to allow it to access the private subnet and do what it needs
to do.
But let me show you in the console as well because it's actually really easy to do this in the console
too.
So here I am in the console and I'm just gonna head down to Lambda under compute click on Create function
make sure that auto from scratch is selected and we're just gonna provide a function name.
I'm just gonna call it VPC dash lambda and accept all of the other defaults.
Just click Create function.
So that is my function created.
And it is just the basic hello world function.
So I'm gonna just click on configure test events call my test event T1 click on Create and then we can
test it so it's just basically the hello from lambda demo function.
So if we scroll down past the function code you'll find this network section here and it's here where
you actually provide that VPC config information and you'll see that by default it's not allowed to
access any VPC by default.
And if we want to add that VPC information we just select this dropdown.
You can just select any VPC within your account for the region that you are operating in.
And the only one that I have is the default VPC.
So I'm just going to select that and then asks you to select at least one subnet and they actually recommend
that you select two subnets in two different Availability Zones for high availability.
So I'm going to select one in U.S. one be and then it's asking me to select a second one I'm going to
select a ust one see as well so that's my two subnets and it then asks you to select a security group.
So I need to select a security group from that subnet.
I'm just going to select the first one on the list and hit save.
Let's just check that if that's been successful.
Okay.
So we've had an error message up here saying your role does not have VPC permissions.
Now in order for this to work you need to have you need to make sure that the execution role assigned
to your lambda function has permissions to go in and create elastic network interfaces.
There are a bunch of VPC permissions that you need to include in your execution role.
So let's just calm down and take a look at our role.
So this is the existing execution role that it's created for us.
But I'm just going to tell it to create a new one from a W S policy templates and we're going to need
to give our new role a name.
So I'm just gonna call it VPC lambda role and hit save.
And hopefully that should have been successful if we come to the top.
No errors here and you should notice in the lambda design a view that we've now got permissions for
Amazon easy too.
So let's take a little closer look at that and we now have the permissions to create network him to
faces delete network interfaces and describe network interfaces.
So it's these actions that lambda needs to have access to in order to create the network interface that
it's going to use when it accesses resources in your VPC.
So hopefully that all makes a bit more sense now.
And of course you can just go in and go into functions select your function and then delete your function
when you've finished exploring that so hopefully that makes a bit more sense now.
And let's go and take a look at our exam tips so all we need to remember for the exam is that it's possible
to enable lambda to access resources which are inside your private VPC but it's not something that is
enabled by default.
And if you do want to enable it you need to provide this VPC config information to the function and
you can do it either using the command line but don't worry you don't need to remember or memorize the
command line command and you can also do it really easily using the console as well you just need to
select your VPC provide the private subnet I.D. and a security group I.D. as well.
And once again lambda uses that VPC information to set up an elastic network interface using an IP from
the private subnet side arrange and then the security group that you provided needs to allow your function
to access resources within the VPC.
So that is the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.