Hello.
And welcome to this lecture and this lecture is just gonna be a quick recap on x ray as well as a high
level overview of general configuration steps that you need to take to get it all working so hopefully
they should all be quite familiar to you.
If you remember that x ray gives you an end to end view of your distributed applications including service
or micro services based applications allowing you to check for performance bottlenecks as well as failures
in your system.
But the really great thing about x ray is that you can actually use it to monitor applications which
are running on easy to inelastic container service and also applications running in your own data center
as well as server list technologies like lambda dynamo D.B. and API gateway.
So in this diagram we've got an easy to instance and a plastic container service cluster running docker
containers and we've also got an on premises system in our own data center and they are all sending
data into x ray and the way that it all hangs together is that you have this a w w x ray SDK installed
on your system and the H.W. s x ray SDK sends the data to the x ray daemon which is also running on
your system and the x ray daemon actually buffers the segments in a queue and then it uploads them into
x ray in batches and the main point of this diagram is just really to show you that you need both the
x ray SDK and the x ray daemon on your systems in order to start sending data into x ray.
Now in terms of the high level configuration steps just remember that you need the x ray SDK and the
x ray daemon as well and you use the SDK to instrument your application to send the required data for
example data about incoming and outgoing HDTV requests that are being made to your Java application.
And when we say instrument is just the terminology that they use to describe configuring your application
to start sending data or traces into x ray and the high level configuration steps are as follows.
So first of all for on premises and easy to systems you're going to need to install the x ray daemon
directly on your easy to instance or on your on premises server if you're running Elastic Beanstalk
you can just install the x ray daemon once again on the easy two instances inside your Elastic Beanstalk
environments and if you're using docker containers an elastic container service then you'll need to
install the x ray daemon on its own docker container on your ECM cluster along side your application
so don't install the x ray daemon on the same docker container where your application is running it's
going to need to be in its own docker container so let's move on to annotations and indexing.
So what are annotations.
Well when instruments in your application you can actually record additional information about requests
or traces by using annotations and annotations are simply key value pairs and they actually get indexed
by x ray and you can use them with filter expressions so that you can go ahead and search for traces
which contain specific data.
And it allows you to group related traces together in the console for example you might want to add
an annotation of game name or game I.D. so that you can then filter on traces which contain that annotation.
So that is all you really need to know about x ray configuration.
And just remember that x ray it integrates with many AWB services like dynamo D.B. lambda API Gateway
etc. and you can also instrument your own applications to send data into x ray applications could be
running on easy to within Elastic Beanstalk environments on your on premises systems in your own data
center and also within Docker on a plastic container service.
And just remember if you are running your application on a plastic container service then run the x
ray daemon in its own Docker image and just have that running alongside your application and to get
started with x ray.
The three things that you will need are firstly the x ray SDK you'll also need the x ray daemon and
you also need to go ahead and instrument your application using the SDK to configure it to send the
required data into x ray.
So for example any data about incoming ATP requests to your application.
And finally if you also want to record application specific information in the form of key value pairs
then use annotations and you can use annotations to add user defined key value pairs to your x ray data
allowing you to filter index and search within x ray based on a key value pairs that you define.
So think something like game name or game I.D..
So that is the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.