You Clockers.
And welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about Doyne MIDP.
So it's going to be the introduction to dynamite ODP.
So let's get started.
So what is dynamite.
DP Well it's a fast and flexible no secret database and it's for applications that need consistent single
digit millisecond latency at any scale.
And it's a fully managed database and it supports both document and key value data models.
It has a really flexible data model.
So that means that you don't need to define your database schema upfront and it has really reliable
performance as well.
And all of these attributes make it a really good fit for mobile gaming and tech.
I O-Tay and many other applications and talking about e-bay is also Servilius.
It's fully managed and it can be configured to auto scale integrate really really well with Lamda and
it's a really popular choice for developers and architects who are designing Servilius applications
dynamo IDB tables are always backed by solid state disks or staes which helps to give you a consistently
fast performance for your reads and writes the underlying hardware supporting neodymium IDB instance
is always spread across three geographically distinct data centers.
So that means it avoids any single point of failure.
It's one of those locations becomes unavailable and there was a choice of two consistency models for
Dynamo ODP read operations.
So the first is eventually consistent rates and that is the default.
And the second is strongly consistent rates now with eventually consistent rates consistency across
all the copies of the data across the three locations is usually reached within a second.
And this means that repeating a read or reading a piece of data that you just written or changed should
return the updated data within a second.
The second option is code strongly consistent rates and with strongly consistent rate will always return
a result that reflects all the rights that received a successful response prior to the raid.
So that really means that all successful rights will be reflected consistently across all three locations.
Tied to my DP is made up of typos and items.
So when we say items think of a row of data in the table theres also attributes.
So when you spend you see attributes think of a column of data in a table it supports k value document
data structures.
And when you see key value the key is really the name of the data.
So for example user ID and then the value is the data.
So so the user id it so and for documents storage documents can be written in Jasen HMO or Eskimo So
let's take a look at an example of a dynamo D-B table and this is one that I've already created and
it's just a simple table containing data about lectures and each row in the table is an item in the
database or a record and each column in the table is an attribute of the item.
So let's take a look at one of these items and you can say that each item is made up of a series of
key value pairs.
So in this case the key is category or the subject matter of the lecture.
And then the value is going to be in the next key value pair.
It's language and the language is English and so on and so on.
And it's these key value pairs which appear in the database as attributes of the items in your table.
And the next thing we're going to talk about is primary case.
So how do we actually query the data in the table.
So I don't to IDB stores and retrieves data based on a primary key.
And it's this primary key that we use when we are querying the data.
And there are two types of primary key.
The first is a partition key on the partition key is a unique attribute.
So for example a user id a product ID an e-mail address etc..
And the reason why it's called a partition key is because the value of the partition key is input into
an internal hash function and the output of this hash function actually determines the partition or
the physical location where that data is going to be stored.
So if you are using a partition key as your primary key then no two items within your table can have
the same partition key because we can't store two items in the same physical location.
Now the second type of primary key is called a composite key.
And this is made up of a combination of a partition key and so.
So you would use this kind of composite K in a situation where the partition key was not necessarily
unique within your table.
So for example think about a table which is storing data about forum posts and you might be storing
attributes such as a user id the name of the forum the time they posted to the forum and the message
they posted in the form.
And in this example the primary key could be a composite key which was made out of a partition key which
should be the user id then a sort key which would be a timestamp of the post.
And in this case two items could have the same partition key because you could have the user posting
multiple times in multiple forms or multiple times in the same form.
So in order to identify the record or the item uniquely we need to use a combination of the user id
and the time they did that forum post.
Now all items with the same partition key start together and then they are sorted according to the value
of the Souci.
And once again this allows you to store multiple items using the same partition key.
So here's an example of a student's table.
And in the first record and within done in my day the record is called an item.
So within that first item we've got the unique ID of 1 9 7 5.
And in this case this could be partition K because we know it's a unique ID then we have a first name
surname and a phone number.
But think of it not the table where we might have a number of students and they might be taking multiple
courses.
So with our second example we have a student called Riyadh's aminals if he was to attend two different
courses then his unique user ID would not necessarily be a good primary key on its own because he might
appear in our database numerous times having attended multiple courses.
So in this case we need to use the composite key and we need to use a partition key along with a sort
key in order to give us that unique primary key access control to John MIDP is all managed but identity
access management and you can create an I am use within your account who has specific permissions to
access and create don't you IDB tables.
You can also create an identity crisis management role which enables you to obtain temporary access
keys that can then be used to access services like dynamite.
And you can also use a special identity access management condition to restrict access to only that
own records.
So let's take a look at that in a little bit more detail.
Imagine a mobile gaming application with millions of users and the users need to access the high scores
for each game that they're playing.
However Access needs to be restricted to ensure they can view anyone else's data.
So in the example here we have a table with attributes such as user ID game title and top score.
So a user is going to want to access their own record to view and update their own data but they don't
need to access anybody else's data.
So how can we make sure that user gets access to the data they need but doesn't see anyone else's data.
Well this can be done by adding a condition to an identity access management policy and this will allow
the user to access only items where the partition key value matches their user ID.
So if Kamila wants to check her high score when she looks into the application she can only access her
own scores in the database.
She cannot view anyone else's data.
She can't tamper with anyone else's scores and she cannot delete anyone else's data.
And here's an example of an identity crisis management policy which does just that.
So the first statement that the top is the statement identifier.
And this just gives the policy a unique identifying name underneath that we have the effect which is
to allow.
And then on the action.
This just defines the actions that the policy is going to allow.
So it's going to allow get item put item and update item underneath that.
It states the resource.
So this is the unique Amazon resource name for your dynamo D-B table and then highlighted here is the
condition clause and it's this highlighted conditions section which is really key to configuring this.
And this is the section with which configures it to allow users to access only the items where the partition
key value matches their user id so it states that for all values debate leading Cays or the partition
key that value needs to match the user ID that is requesting the data.
So effectively it allows users to access only the items where the partition key value matches their
user ID.
And then finally the domain name IDB attributes section defines the attributes that the policy applies
to.
So let's take a look at some of our exam tips for Dynamo ODP.
Well firstly it's a low latency no Siku database.
It consists of tables items and attributes.
And when we think of items think of rows in the database or database records alone we think of attributes
just think of columns in the table.
It supports both document and key value data models and supported document formats or chase on HCM.
An example there are two types of primary case.
Firstly the partition key and secondly a composite key which consists of a combination of a partition
key and suitcase and the partition key be something like a user ID or a product ID.
And then the Souci is usually a range.
It could be a timestamp or a date etc..
There are two consistency models within dynamite IDB strongly consistent which means that any riots
that occurred before the raid will be reflected in the raid and that will be consistent across all three
locations.
And also there is eventually consistent and with eventually consistent performance can be better.
However it can take up to one second Fanu rights or updates to be reflected in your read access to dynamite
debate is controlled by using identity access management policies and you can implement fine grained
access control using identity access management conditioned premises and it's the domain name ID be
leading case parameter which allows users to access only the items where the partition key matches their
user ID.
So that's the end of this lecture.
It was just a quick overview of dynamite Bay and in the next lecture we're going to go ahead and create
our own dynamite pay tables and populate them with some data as well.
So you have an opportunity to get your hands dirty with Dynamites Eby.
So if you have any questions please let me know.
Otherwise if you have time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.