Hello clunkers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to introduce dynamo D.B. TTL.
It's also known as dynamo D.B..
Time to Live.
And this is a topic that has been coming up in the exams recently based on student feedback.
So this lecture is going to just cover off TTL so you know exactly what it is for the exam.
So let's get started.
So what is dynamo DB TTL.
Well TTL or time to live.
It's an attribute which defines an expiry time for your data so you define an expiry time and expired
items are automatically marked for deletion and once an item has been marked for deletion that means
it's going to be deleted within the next 48 hours.
And this is really good for removing any irrelevant or old data.
So data that's no longer useful to your application.
So think session data event logs any temporary data so any data that's no longer useful to your application.
After a certain period of time and this is going to really help to reduce costs for storing data in
dynamo IDB because it automatically removes data which you no longer need.
So the data is no longer relevant.
So it just does that housekeeping for you and automatically deletes the data.
So let's take a look at how that actually works within dynamo ADP.
And I've got an example session data table here so we're just storing the user I.D. such an idea session
creation time and the time to live.
And then finally the session data itself and the first thing you're probably going to notice is that
time to live is expressed in a pretty strange format.
It's expressed in the epoch time format and if you haven't heard of that before it's also known as Unix
time and it's also known as politics time as well.
And epoch time or Unix time or politics time that is a numerical value and it represents the number
of seconds which have elapsed since twelve a.m. on January the 1st 1970.
So even before I was born in fact a long time before I was born and probably a long time before a lot
of you were born as well.
So that is just the way that Unix systems see time and that's how they express time as a numerical value.
Now in this example I'm setting the expiration time on item and I'm setting it for two hours after the
session originally began.
And don't worry you can just use one of these really useful translation websites.
And I've got one to show you I'm just going to head over there now.
So this is the website I normally use is just called epoch converter.
I'm sure you can find one just by Googling or use your favorite one and you can just go in and set the
day set the hour to what you want to and then just translate it into an epoch timestamp.
So that's the kind of thing you can use if you are defining your TTL.
And it's this epoch time number which actually allows dynamo DP to easily compare your time to live
to the current time right now.
And in this example the expiration of this item is set for two hours after the session originally began.
And so when the current time is greater than the TTL the item is going to be expired and it gets marked
for deletion and then within the next 48 hours it's actually going to be deleted.
So that's actually quite a long window between being marked for deletion and actually getting deleted.
So in order to cater for that you can actually filter out any expired items from your queries and scans.
But let's take a look at how this actually works within the dynamo DB console.
But first of all we're going to need to create our own dynamo db table and I prepared a couple of commands
that we're going to run.
And before we do that you just need to make sure of course that your NWS CLIA is configured with credentials
of a user who has the correct permissions to go ahead and create dynamo DB tables.
So the first thing I'm gonna do is I'm going to type AWOL as I am get hyphen user and this is just going
to tell us which user we have used when we configured the IWC and I saw when we ran a s configure.
This is the user credentials that I used originally.
So I'm just gonna come back to my console and just double check the credentials of that particular user.
So I'm gonna go to services and then I am gonna find my user so it was FE and I'm just going to check
that that user has the correct permissions.
So my users actually got administrator access but if you don't have any dynamo DP access you don't if
you didn't have administrator access on that account then you can just go ahead and add permissions.
Go to attach existing policies and then just search for Dynamo DP and you can add dynamo IDB full access
to that user and that will make sure that you have access and to use dynamo DP.
So once you're happy with that I'm going to come back to the console and I've actually prepared a couple
of commands that were going to run.
So we're going to run one command to firstly create on your table and then we're going to run another
command to populate the table.
So I'll show you those commands before we run them.
And these are going to be included in a text file in the resources of the course.
So you'll be able to just copy and paste these.
So the first command is this one.
And this actually creates our session data table.
So first of all it runs the CREATE TABLE command.
It provides a table name of session data and then it defines our primary key which it calls it the hash
key.
And that's just an alternative name that they use for the primary key or the partition key.
So we're going to define our hash key as being the user I.D. and the attribute type is going to be of
type number.
And then finally the last thing we'd stipulate in this command is the provision throughput read capacity
units of five and write capacity units of five.
So you just copy that command and don't worry you don't need to understand all of the different options.
You don't need to understand the donor IDB commands the CLIA commands for the exam.
They're not going to test you on that.
It's just the quickest way to create the table for the purposes of this lecture.
So then just come back to the console and I'm just going to paste that into my console hit enter and
hopefully if that's been successful you should see this kind of output summarizing what we've done in
diner IDB and then the next command we're going to run is going to perform a batch right item and this
is going to write a number of items into our new table and it takes as input.
This this request items file which is going to be a file called items not Jason.
And you're going to need to download this from the resources section of the course.
So if I show you items not Jason it's simply a Jason File which is going to create these items in our
session data table.
So the first thing it does is it stipulates the name of the table which is set session data and then
it defines a number of put requests and the items that we're actually going to put into that table.
So we've got our user I.D. it's going to be a number this number here is the actual user I.D. then we've
got the session creation time expiration time and a session I.D. as well.
So it just creates three different items which it's going to put into the table.
So if we come back to our command just going to copy and paste that
okay and if that's successful we can come back to a console or we can just check whether that table
got created successfully so come to services dynamo DP and make sure that you are in the correct region
where you have run a W S configure.
So on my system
I mean us e 1 so I just need to make sure that I am looking at the U.S. e one region which I am and
then if we go to tables and there is our session data table.
So if you click on the table click on items and that should be the items that we have just populated.
So if that has run successfully for you you should have three items in your table with a user I.D. creation
time expiry time and a session I.D..
And I've just set this expiry time to midnight tonight and today is the 6th of December.
So I have set the expiration time for these items to be the 6th of December at midnight.
So you might want to update this set it to midnight tonight for whatever date it is when you are watching
this lecture.
So if you want to do that once again just go back to the Epoch converter and you can create an epoch
timestamp using whatever date you want to.
So let's say February the 2nd 2019 you can just configure the date that you want and then grab the epoch
timestamp and you can set it to whatever hour minute and second you want as well and set whatever the
local time is for wherever you are located.
So feel free to go in and update at expiration time if you want to follow along on this lecture.
So once you're happy with all of that we can actually go ahead and stop playing around with the time
to live for these items.
So if you had two actions click on manage TTL and the first thing it's going to ask you to do is define
which attribute you are basing the time to live on and we are going to be using this expiration time
as are TTL attributes so you need to just type in the name of your attribute
and dynamo D.B. actually allows you to preview TTL before you actually go ahead and apply it so we can
first of all we can run a preview based on previewing items expiring by 330 on today's date.
So I'm just going to run preview and that's what we should expect to see.
We shouldn't expect to see any items expiring by three thirty today because all of these items are set
to expire at midnight tonight.
So let's just change that to December the 7th and midnight and we can run the preview again and there
we are.
It should catch all three of those items because they are due to expire at midnight.
So if you want to go ahead and configure that time to lift all of these items you can hit continue.
And then if we go back to overview you should see under the table details of the time to live attribute.
It's configured as the attribute that we defined earlier.
So the expiration time.
So that is dynamo DB.
TTL.
The main thing to remember is that you can use it to define expiration times for your data.
It will mark your data for expiration as soon as the current time is greater than the TTL.
The item will then be expired marked for deletion and then deleted within 48 hours.
And just remember you can filter out the expired items from your queries and scans so that you don't
see them when you query and scan your data.
So that is everything you need to know about TTL.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.