Helicopters and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about dynamo D-B streams and we've got
some student feedback recently that Dynamo IDB streams are coming up in the exam.
So this lecture is just to tell you everything that you need to know about tiny IDB streams.
So let's get started.
So what dynamo deep streams.
Well a dynamo D-B stream is a time ordered sequence or stream and it records any modifications made
to the items in your doited my D-B table.
So any time there's an insert update or delete operation it's going to record that in your dynamo D-B
stream.
So it records all of these actions as I log and the logs are encrypted at rest and they're stored for
24 hours only.
So that means after 24 hours it's going to start deleting those entries.
And typically don't to IDB streams.
They can be used for auditing or archiving of transactions.
Replaying any transactions to a different table but they're mainly used to trigger events based on a
particular change within the domain of AB table.
So they're really really good for service architectures.
You can use a dynamo ODP stream to trigger a lambda function for example or to trigger your application
to do something based on a change in the time to my db table and the streams are accessed using their
own dedicated endpoint.
So there's one end point to access that don't you IDB table itself and then there's a second separate
and point for the IDB Stream.
And by default the minimum amount of data you can record is the primary key of the item that is being
modified updated or deleted.
But you can also store before and after images.
So you can capture the state of the item before the change and the State of the item after the change
as well.
So let's take a look at a simple architecture for Dynamite D-B streams Samekh application at the top
and it uses the time to my GP API to speak to its dynamo IDB typos.
So it's got one end point for the time of IDB table.
And then there's a completely different type of Modibo streams API and a different end point for its
Doyne MIDP stream as well.
And just remember the event data is only held for 24 hours before they start deleting it.
Now the effects are recorded in near real time.
So once again that makes it really really good for service architectures and to build applications which
respond to changes in your data my D-B table applications can take actions based on the contents of
your streams.
Based on what's going on within your dynamite db table it makes a really good event source for lambda
so Alamdar will pull that item IDB stream and then can execute code launch functions based on events
happening within your daughter IDB stream.
So let's take a look at an example scenario using dynamite Eby streams to trigger a work flow.
And in this example we have an invoicing and payments system which is recording invoice data into a
diner IDB table.
And each time a new invoice entry is made into the dining IDB table there's a Lunda function which reads
the Dine IDB strain to check Finney's transactions.
And then when it sees a new event sends a notification using SS which in turn creates a message in an
ask us queue and you can then have your payments application polling that ask us queue processing the
message and it performs various tasks like generating a payment request adding an item to a customer's
bill etc. so you can say this is a really powerful way to generate triggers to lammed to trigger your
application to take actions based on the changing contents of your dynamo D-B table.
So let's take a look at the exam tips for dining IDB stream's.
Well just remember it's a time ordered sequence of some level modifications in your design and IDB tables.
So every time an item gets changed and you try to Modibo table it's going to record that in the IDB
stream the data is only stored for 24 hours.
And after that it's going to start getting deleted.
And it's a really good event source for lambda allowing you to create applications which can take actions
based on events happening within your time in my D-B table.
So that's the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank.