Hello caulkers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about the provisioned throughput
exceeded exception and exponential back off.
So let's get started.
Now the proficient throughput exceeded exception is one that you might see on your dynamo db table if
your request rate is too high.
For the read and write capacity provisioned on the dynamo IDB table.
So for example if your application is making too many requests into the dynamo D.B. table so too many.
Read and write requests for the table to handle based on its read and write capacity provision.
Now if you're using the W.S. SDK it's going to automatically retry the requests until they are successful.
However if you're not using the SDK you're going to have to configure your application to do one or
both of the following things.
So firstly you can reduce the request frequency so reduce the number of concurrent requests that are
being sent to the dynamo db table reduce the frequency of the requests that being sent to the table
and the second thing you can do is to implement exponential back off.
Now what is exponential.
Back off.
While many components in a network or in a given that system can generate errors due to being overloaded
by too many requests all coming in at the same time and that could be any component that you can think
of.
So maybe network switches DNS servers load balances etc. Pretty much any part of the network can experience
overloading due to too many concurrent requests and the usual way of dealing with this is to implement
retrials from the client application.
So for example for the client to keep on trying to send a request until it gets a response and all of
the AWB SSD case they all implement automatic re choice which simply send the request again until it
is successful.
But in addition to these simple retry is all AWOL.
SDK is also use exponential back off and with exponential back off.
This means that the requester will implement progressively longer waits between consecutive retrials
of a failed request after the first failed request it might wait for example 50 milliseconds before
trying again and then if that retry fails it then might wait 100 milliseconds until trying again and
then if that retry fails it might wait 200 milliseconds before trying again so it will continue like
that until the request is successful.
And this gives significantly improved flow control in the hope that at some point the traffic is going
to start flowing freely again and requests will start to be fulfilled again.
But if after about one minute this doesn't work it might be instead that your request size is actually
exceeding the throughput for your read and write capacity on the dynamo db table.
So in this case it may be worth investigating your provisioned throughput and if your workload is mainly
get requests you might be able to improve performance using either dynamo DP accelerator or Dax or using
elastic Ash.
However if it's mainly right requests that are causing the issue then maybe take a look at increasing
your right capacity for the dynamo DC table.
So what are exam tips.
Well if you see the provisioned throughput exceeded error this means that the number of requests into
your dynamo db table is too high.
Exponential back off can be used to improve the flow control by retrying the requests using progressively
longer waits.
However if your weight is getting up to around one minute it's definitely worth checking your read and
write capacity unit settings and seeing if they need to be adjusted.
And just remember that exponential back off it doesn't only apply to dynamo D.B. it's actually a feature
of every single AWP SDK and it applies to many services within a W S for example S3 Buckets.
If you're using cloud formation heavily and SPSS etc and if you're not using the IWC SDK then you're
going to need to handle this yourself in your application settings or in your application code.
So the way to do that is just to reduce the frequency of your requests and implement exponential back
off yourself.
So that is the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.