I Clockers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is the dynamo DP summary.
So it's everything we've learnt in the dynamite's B.S. So let's get started.
So Diana IDB as a low latency Marsico database consisting of tables items and attributes it supports
both document and key value data models and the supported document formats or Jason I asked him how
an X IMO and there's two types of primary key.
Firstly the petition K so that could be something like a user ID and a combination of a petition.
And Azuki which is called a composite key that might consist of a user ID plus also the data the account
was created
there were two consistent semi-autos.
So we have strongly consistent and eventually consistent and of course if you need the most up to date
data for your application configure it to use strongly consistent rates but by default it's eventually
consistent.
And this means that when you read data from the table it may not reflect the status of a recently completed
write operation but if you use strongly consistent then this will reflect all previous rights that was
successfully completed.
Access control is controlled using identity access management policies.
I remember in the lab we used an IBM service role with the dynamo DB A full access policy to allow easy
to instance to interact with Doyne MIDP.
And when we deleted that row the ACTU instance could no longer query the database.
Remember we can use fine grained access control using the identity access management condition parameter
and that is called IDB leading case.
And we can use that to allow users to access only the items where the partition key value matches their
own User ID indexes enable sause queries on specific data columns and give you a different view of your
data based on an alternative partition K or partition key and sought key combination.
But it's important to understand the differences between a local secondary index and a global secondary
index.
So just remember for the local secondary index this must be created when you create a table.
It has the same partition key as your table but a different sort key whereas the global secondary index
you can create that at any time either at table creation time or any time afterwards.
And it can have a different partition key as well as a different sort key you can use a query operation
to find items in the table using only the primary key attribute.
So you provide the primary key name and a distinct value to such file.
For example the primary key name of user ID and the value of the user ID.
For example 2 0 1.
Alternatively a scan operation examines every item in the table.
By default it returns all data attributes but you can use the projection expression parameter to refine
your results and from the com so you can use the filter function query results are always sorted by
the sort.
If there is one and that's sorted in ascending order.
So one two three four etc..
And you could set the scan index for that parameter to Folse if you want to reverse the order.
I remember this is for queries only it's not for scans even though it's very misleading.
They've called it scan index for.
Just remember it's only for queries and in general the query operation tends to be more efficient than
a scan.
If you want to improve the performance of queries and scans you can do that by setting a smaller page
size which uses up fewer read operations because it returns a smaller set of results.
You can also isolate your scan operations to specific tables and segregate him from your mission critical
traffic Alternatively you can try parallel scans rather than the default sequential scan.
However in general you should avoid using scan operations if you can instead design your tables so that
you can use the query get a patch get item IPs don't MIDP throughput is measured in capacity units.
I remember one right to capacity unit is equal to 1 1 kill about right per second one read capacity
unit is equal to one full kilobyte strongly consistent rate per second or two for kilobyte eventually
consistent reads per And
in order to calculate your write capacity requirements first calculate how many capacity units needed
for each.
Right.
So you would type the size of each item.
And in this case it's 512 bytes divided by 1 kilobytes for right capacity units Akos 0.5.
Run that up to the nearest whole number and H writes We need one right capacity unit per right operation
then multiply that by the number of rights you need per second.
So 1 times 100 equals one right to capacity units required for this example.
In order to calculate your real capacity requirements first calculate how many capacity units needed
for each raid.
So in order to read 83 about items per second you type the size of each item so three kilobytes.
Divide it by four kilobytes for the read capacity units.
So that equals point seventy five round up to the nearest whole number.
So each read we need one read capacity unit operation.
Multiply that by the number of raids per second.
So times 80 equals 80 real capacity units for strongly consistent rates.
However if eventual consistency is acceptable and your application is going to use eventual consistency
just divide the 80 by 2 which is 40.
So 40 read capacity units required for eventual consistency dynamite be accelerator audax provides in-memory
caching for Don MIDP tables improves the response times for eventually consistent reads only.
You point your JPI close to the docs cluster instead of your table and if the item you queering is in
the cash tax will return it.
Otherwise it will perform and eventually consistent get item operation to your dynamite db table and
its most suitable for read intensive applications.
Its not suitable for write intensive all applications that requires strongly consistent reads.
Moving onto elastic cache remember elastic cache is an in memory cache which sits between your application
and database and that could be tied to my DB database or any audio database.
There were two different caching strategies.
Lazy loading and right three Remember lazy loading only caches the data when it's requested and it means
elastic cache node failures are not fatal.
It just means you'll get lots of cash misses until the cash is built up again and you do get a Kashmir's
penalty.
So there's an overhead to the initial request query database and writing to the cache as well.
If the data is not in the cache already and you can avoid Stylo data by implementing a timeout lives
the other caching strategy is called right through and this writes data into the cache whenever there
is a change in the database.
This means the data is never style but there is a right penalty because each write involves a right
to the database and a right to the cache and an elastic cache node failure means that data is missing
in the cache until it's added or updated in the database and you do have the disadvantage of wasted
resources.
If most of the data in your database is never accessed so that is the end of this section.
Well done for completing this section and if you have any questions please let me know.
Otherwise please feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank ye.