Hello clunkers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is gonna be a lab all about dynamo DP in
this lab we're going to create some dynamo DP tables using some p HP scripts which we're going to run
on an easy to instance and this instance is going to have a role assigned to it to enable it to interact
with Dynamo DP.
So if you're ready to get started please join me in the console and the first thing that I'm going to
do is create an identity access management role for our easy to instance.
So go ahead and find identity access management under security or then see compliance and we're gonna
go and click on roles and create role and it's going to be a service role for easy to so click on easy
to then hit next.
And we're going to select a policy type so click in the search box and we're going to just search for
Dynamo DP.
And I'm going to select dynamo DP full access click on Next.
And we need to give our role a name.
So I'm just going to call it dynamo DP and click on Create role so that's our role down here created.
And the next thing we need to do is go back to the dashboard go back to services and click on easy to
and click on launch instance and select the Linux I am I and we're just going to stay with the T2 micro
click on Next.
Most of these defaults we can just keep as the defaults but there's a couple of things that we need
to change.
So first of all we need to select our I am role that we just created so select dynamo DP and then on
the advance details we've got a bash script or a bootstrap script to add in here which is a script that's
gonna be run when the instance starts for the very first time.
So that is in the resources section but I've just got it copied so I'm just going to paste it in now
and all this script does is it just first of all it tells us it's using the bash interpreter it then
does a young update minus Y it then installs Apache HP and get as well.
It starts Apache and it makes sure that Apache will continue to start on boot up and then it changes
directory to var dub dub dub HMO and then it creates just a really simple test website.
And then finally it clones some code that we already have located in this get hub location.
So under get hub dot com a kangaroo dynamo DP.
So once you have cut and paste that and you'll just find this in the resources section of the course
you just copy and paste it in there then just hit on add storage next add tags and we're going to add
a tag tag we're going to add is name and then we're going to just call this one dynamo DP dynamo DBC
to click on Next and you want to select a security group which has both ATP and SS H.
So I've got this one here that I created for different lab and it allows ATP access via port 80 and
also SS H access.
So I'm going to select that one.
However if you don't have one you can go ahead and create a new security group.
Just click that button here but we don't need to do that.
I'm just going to select the one I already have here and then click on review and launch and then click
on launch and select an existing key pair for your region.
So I'm in the London Region so and I already have a key pair for London.
So I'm going to select that one again.
If you don't have one you can just click on Create new keeper and it will create one for you that you
can download.
I'm just gonna use the one that I already have and then click on launch instances.
And that might take a while so I'm just going to post the video now and come back when that has completed
and now here we are on the easy to dashboard and my instance has been launched.
So I just select the instance scroll down and find the public IP copy that's a clipboard.
And now I'm going to go to my terminal window
and I'm gonna type SS H minus I.
And then the name of my keeper.
Easy to dash user at.
And then paste in the IP address of your easy to instance and hit enter.
And then we are inside the easy to instance.
So the first thing I'm gonna do is pseudo as you then seedy for dub dub dub HMO and hit Ellis and we
can see that a new directory has been created.
The Dynamo D.B. directory has been cloned from our get repository and there's also this test Doc P HP
file which is our Web page so the next thing that we need to do is we need to install the SDK for HP
and when we do that there's a couple of commands that we need to run.
First of all we need to get composer and then we need to use composer to install the latest version
of the SDK.
So I'm just gonna show you a web page which has those commands in it.
So this is the web page with the documentation for installing the w w SDK for P HP and the recommended
way for installing the SDK is to use composer which is a tool that manages and installs the dependencies
for installing HP.
So if we scroll down there is a link to the command line installation for compose it for Linux.
So we're installing this on our easy to instance so it's going to be the Linux installation.
So I'm just going to open up in a new tab and it gives us these four different commands that we need
to run to download the composer installer verify it then run the installer and then finally remove it.
And don't worry I'm going to add a text file with all of the commands that you need to run in order
to install composer and install CHP.
So that's going to be in the resources of the lecture.
So I'm just gonna start off by copying that first command and the first thing I'm going to do is type
pseudo askew and then I'm going to paste that command into my terminal window and a few students have
reported issues with their T2 micro server running out of memory when going through these steps to install
composer AMP BHP and unfortunately we haven't been able to replicate the problem on our side so we can't
really explain why that might be happening.
However if you do experience memory issues when trying to run this set of commands I've added a work
around that one of our students who experience the issue has kindly provided which just creates a swap
file and it should hopefully fix any memory issues that you are experiencing.
Just go ahead and run these three commands and they are in the resources section of the course and then
you should be able to continue.
So now I'm gonna come back to my Web page and grab the second command and paste that copy our third
command and paste then copy the fourth command
and paste.
Just gonna clear the screen come back to our page and so we've downloaded and installed composer.
So the next thing that we need to do is run this command as well.
And this is just going to install HP.
So grab that and paste that into a window.
And it does.
Just take a few seconds but if it's successful you should see a similar response to this.
So now that has completed let's just run less and we're going to change directory into the dynamo DP
directory and you can see there's two different files in here two different BHP files.
So there's one called create tables and that's that file is that script is going to create a bunch of
tables in our dynamo DP.
And the second one is called upload data and that's going to upload some data into those tables.
Now the first thing that we need to do is we just need to make an update into this create tables dot
BHP to make sure that we're installing our tables in the correct region.
So I'm just going to open that up now
and you'll want to come down where you see this section here where it specifies the region and at the
moment mine is set to EU West 1.
So what you need to do is replace that with whatever region you're working from so whichever region
you're running the easy to instance in.
That's the region that you want to specify here.
So if I come back to my console I'm in London.
So that means I'm going to have to change my region because London is a ust to too.
Actually you can see it down here as well you west to a.
So that's for the availability zone but the region is EU West too.
So that means I need to go back and change that in my BHP file so I'm going to come across here and
replace that with two and then save and then we are done with that file and now we also need to make
the same update in the upload data dot BHP
and again scroll down until you find region and come across and just replace that with your desired
region and save.
And now we are done with those two files.
So it's really important to make sure you change the region and you change it in both files otherwise
the lab will not work and the next thing we're going to do is come back to our console window and I'm
gonna go into dynamo DP now and just show you this is the splash screen that you should see if you don't
have any dynamo DB tables created already.
So that moment we've got nothing here.
So I'm gonna go back into my AC to instance go and find the public IP for that instance select for instance
and just copy that to clipboard then I'm going to open a new tab on my browser paste the IP in on your
browser tab and then just hit slash dynamo DP and then the name of create tables dot BHP
and then hit enter so this is just gonna run that BHP script to create some tables within dynamo DP
for us and it just takes a few moments to complete okay and we just got the response now just saying
it's created a table for the product catalog forum thread and reply.
So it's created four tables for us and now the next thing we need to do is we need to run that BHP script
to upload data into our tables.
So just come back to your browser window and we can just modify it and delete the create tables and
just replace that with upload data and then just hit enter.
So it's adding data into the product catalogue forum and reply table now.
So it says that's finished so let's go back into the console and see what it's put in the tables for
us.
So come back to services and dynamo DP
click on tables and you can say is created these four different tables for us.
So let's take a look at the product catalog table for example click on items
and we can see the upload data.
HP has populated our table with a load of different items and we've got here a product I.D. a price
category title type brand color etc..
I just noticed that not all items have every single attribute and that's one of the great things about
dynamo DP is that you don't have to have everything.
It's very flexible.
Not every item has to have the same type or number of attributes.
And just notice here that you can either query and you can query based on a product I.D. for example
and we can enter a value here.
So for example if I enter valued I enter 1 0 2 here click on Start search it will search for an item
in our table with the product catalog ideas of 1 0 2 and then you can also run a scan as well which
will just show us everything in the table if we click on spot search for that it will just show us absolutely
everything in the table and there's just one more thing that I want to show you which is how to interact
with our database using the command line.
So I'm gonna come back to my terminal window now.
So I'm back in my terminal session on my easy to instance and I can actually use the AWB US command
line interface to query the database programmatically.
And remember we created the identity access management role to give this instance dynamo DP full access
so it should be able to connect to our database and make queries.
Now I already have the command in my clipboard so I'm just going to paste it now and this command simply
uses the AWB CLIA to talk to dynamo DP and to run a get item operation on the table name called product
catalog and the region is going to be EU West too because that's where my dynamo DB table is located
and the key is specified here.
So that's the partition key and the partition key is an I.D. and the value is the numerical value and
the value is 2 0 5 so I'm searching the diagram IDB table for product with the product I.D. of 2 0 5.
So I'm going to hit enter and that has queried the table and it's brought up that product item and this
is all enabled by the identity access management role which has given us full access to dining IDB.
So if I go back to the console and go into services and then back into identity access management and
I'm going to go into that role the tiny IDB Ro and I'm going to delete that permission
and I'm actually going to delete the roll
so now that role doesn't exist for our easy to instance anymore.
So let's go back to the instance and see if we can still run that database command.
So I'm just going to hit up arrow and try and run the command again.
There you go.
So the security token included in the request is invalid and it's not letting us access our table.
So just remember if you want your easy two instances to be able to access your dynamo DB tables to be
able to query them and insert items into them they need to have that identity access management service
role to allow them access to the database
so that it's dynamo DP.
And we just created some tables and populated them with some data so that you're able to now manipulate
that data and run queries and searches etc. and this will really help you as you progressed through
this section of the course and it will really help you to get a little bit more familiar with Dynamo
DP and how it all works.
So that is the end of this lecture hopefully that all worked for you if you have any questions please
let me know.
If not please feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.