Hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be all about dynamite.
DP index's So let's get started.
So what is an index.
Well in stinko databases an index is a data structure which allows you to perform really fast queries
on specific columns within a table and you can select the columns that you're interested in that you
want to include in that index.
And then you run your searches against that index rather than on the entire data set.
So it really makes your queries much more efficient.
And in talking about DP There are two types of index supported to help speed up your dynamo IDB queries.
Now don't try IDB.
Of course it's not a sequel database but it does still have this index feature and Entine of ODP.
There are two types of index that are supported which will both help speed up your dynamo DB queries.
So firstly we have the local secondary index and also the global secondary index.
So let's take a look at these in a little bit more detail.
Now a local secondary index is an index that can only be created when you are creating your table.
So you cannot add remove or modify it later and it has the same partition key as your original table
but it does have a different sort key.
And that's what gives you the different view on your data because your data is going to be organized
according to an alternative sort.
Any queries that are based on this sort key that you run against the local secondary index are then
much faster than they would be if you were using the mind table.
So for example in a customer table where you're storing all information about your customers their e-mail
address all of that all the purchases they've made all their contact details et cetera you might have
a local secondary index which uses the main partition of user ID and then uses a different sort caid
to your main table.
So you might use a sort key like account creation date.
Now for global secondary indexes these are much much more flexible so you can create the global secondary
index whenever you like.
So you can either create it when you create your table or you can add it later on and it allows you
to choose a different partition key as well as a different sort key to your main table.
So that gives you a completely different view of the data.
And of course it speeds up any queries that are relating to this alternative partition.
And so key.
So for example in our customer table we might want to create a global secondary index using a different
partition of email address and then use a sort of last log in date.
So what are exam tips for the dynamite IDB indexes.
Well firstly indexes overall enable much faster queries but only on very specific data columns that
give you a different view with your data based on an alternative partition key or an alternative partition
key and an automotive Souci.
And it's really important to understand the differences between these two types of index.
So just remember for the local secondary index it must be created when you create your table and it
uses the same partition but a different sort key.
And for the global secondary index you can create it anytime either at table creation or afterwards.
And it can have a different position key as well as a different sort key.
So that's the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not please feel free to move on to the next section.