Hello Clockers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about dynamo D-B scan and query API
calls.
So there's two different ways of getting your information out of the database.
We have scans and queries and this lecture is just going to discuss the differences between the two
of those.
So let's get started.
So what is a query.
Well a query operation finds items in your table based on the primary key attribute and also a distinct
value to search for.
For example if you're looking for an item where the user ID is equal to one thé you're going to query
that dynamite D-B table based on the primary key of user ID and the value will be to 1 2 and that will
select all the attributes for that item.
So for example if you were storing the first name surname email etc all those attributes would come
up in that query
and you can use an optional so key name and value to refine the results.
If you have multiple results for example if your so key is a timestamp you can refine the query to select
only the items with a timestamp of the last seven days.
So for example you might want to create the last time a user logged into a form the last time they posted
in a forum that kind of thing now by default a query returns all the attributes for the items.
But you can use the projection expression parameter if you want the query to only return specific attributes
that you're looking for.
For example if you only wanted to see the user id and email address rather than all the attributes for
that item in the table results are always sorted by the sort key if they're numeric they're sorted in
numeric order and that by default is in ascending order.
So one two three four and if that ASCII characters they are also sorted by default in ascending order
and you can reverse the order by setting the scan index forward parameter to foce this only applies
to queries.
And unfortunately they've called it scan index forward but it does only apply to queries.
So just remember that if you see any questions relating to scan index forward parameter it's relating
to queries and not scan and it's to reverse the order of the results from your query.
By default all queries are eventually consistent but you can set them to each Strone consistent but
you need to explicitly set the query to be strongly consistent.
So moving on to scans is a scan well a scan operation examines every single item in the table and by
default it returns all the data attributes.
Once again you can use the projection expression parameter to refine your scan results to return only
the attributes you're looking for.
And you can also filter the results of the scan once it's been done but it's a lot easier to understand
the difference between scans and queries.
If I actually show you in the console so I'm going to move to the console now so I can show you exactly
what I mean.
So here I am in the console and I'm in the dynamite B.S. and I'm going to go to my typos.
And these are the titles that we set up if you did the previous lab already you you'll be able to try
this yourself on your own tables.
So first of all I'm going to go to the product catalogue table and click on items and these are all
the items in my product catalog table.
So first of all I'm going to run a query I'm going to select query here and I can query on the partition
the key for this table the partition key is the ID.
So it's the product ID and it's this attribute in this column and I can query based on one of these
attribute IDs.
I can create based on the partition key.
It's a numerical value.
And I can enter a value here that I want to search for.
So I'm going to search for 2 0 2 and click on Start Search and it's found my likes and with the ID 2
0 2.
So now let's compare that to a scan operation.
So if I select scan instead and click on Start Search it gives me the entire table and if I want to
refine these results I need to add a filter.
So I'm going to add a filter here and I'm going to filter on price so I can filter on any of these attributes
here.
So I'm going to filter on price and it's the numerical values are change that number and you get a lot
of choices.
So I can search for items of a specific price or greater than less than.
So I'm going to search for items greater than 100.
Click on search and it will apply that filter.
But the thing to remember with the scan is it's not doing it's not searching the database it's first
dumping the data the entire table and then it's applying a filter on top of that to show as only the
results that we're looking for.
So what should we use a query or a scan.
Well a query is much more efficient than a scan because the scan dumps the entire table then filters
out the unwanted values to provide the desired results.
And this adds the extra step of removing the data that you don't want and as the type of grows the scan
operation takes longer and longer and a scan operation on a large table can actually use up the provision
throughput for a large table in just one single operation.
And there are some ways to improve performance so you can reduce the impact of a query or scan by setting
a smaller page size which uses fewer read operations.
For example you can set the page size to return 40 items.
And this means that you will end up with a larger number of small operations which will allow other
requests to succeed without throttling the database.
But in general you should try and avoid using scan operations if you can instead design your tables
in a way that you can use the query get a patch get item API.
And the second option is that you can use parallel scans.
So by default a scan operation process is data sequentially and it returns it in one megabyte increments
before moving on to retrieve the next one to make about data.
And it can only scan one partition as time.
However you can configure it to my DP to use parallel scans instead by logically dividing a table or
index into segments and then scanning each segment in parallel.
And this could work really well.
If your database is not already really busy however it's best to avoid parallel scans if your table
or index is already incurring heavy read why activity from other applications because the parallel scans
could well impact the other applications.
So what our scan and queery exam tips.
Well just remember a query operation finds items in the table using only the primary key attribute and
you need to provide a distinct value to search for.
So remember when I searched in the table for a product ID of 2 0 2.
And then the query operation found that product for me a scan operation examines every item in the table
by default it returns all the data about Chhobi.
But you can use the projection expression parameter to refine the results and you can also use the filter
like I did earlier.
So I use that filter.
So I use the filter to refine the results to products which had a price greater than 100 query results
are always sorted by the Sauti.
If there is one there sort it by default in ascending order and you can use the scan index for parameter
to false to reverse the order for queries I need and remember a query operation is generally more efficient
than a scan.
Reduce the impact of your query or scan by setting a smaller page size which uses fewer reader operations
and for scans You can also try to isolate scan operations to specific tables.
Alternatively try out parallel scans rather than the default sequential scan.
However in general avoid using scan operations if you can and design your type was in a way that can
use Querrey get or patch get item IPs.
So that is the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not please feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.