Hello Cokers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about dynamite D-B provisioned throughput
and proficient throughput is the mechanism that we use to define the capacity and performance requirements
in Don MIDP.
So let's get started.
So does deep a previsions Reaper is measured in capacity units and when you create your table assuming
you're not using auto scaling you need to specify your requirements in terms of reach capacity units
and right capacity units and one right capacity unit is equal to 1 1 kilobyte per second.
And one real capacity unit is equal to 1 strongly consistent read of four kilobytes per seconds or two
eventually consistent rates of four kilobytes per second and eventually consistent reads all the default.
So let's have a look at an example configuration.
So think of a table with five read capacity units and five right capacity units configured.
And this configuration will be able to perform 5 4 kilobytes strongly consistent rates which equals
20 kilobytes per second.
It will be able to perform twice as many eventually consistent rates per second.
So that would be 40 kilobytes per second.
And it will be able to perform 5 1 kilobyte bytes per second which equals five kilobytes per second.
Now if your application reads or writes large items is going to consume more capacity units and it will
cost you more as well because the price goes up the more read and write capacity units you are provisioning.
So lets have a look at how we calculate the requirements how we work out how many read or write capacity
units you're going to need full application.
So I imagine you have an application and it needs to read 80 items or table rows per second.
And each item is three kilobytes in size and you need strongly consistent rates.
First of all you need to calculate how many read capacity units are needed for each rate.
So the way we do that is we take the size of each item and divide it by four kilobytes.
So 3 divided by four is 0.75.
Round that up to the nearest whole number.
So h Reid is going to need one read capacity unit per read operation and then we simply multiply that
by the number of rates per second.
So in this case 80 rates per second.
So thats going to be 80 read capacity units required for strongly consistent rates but what about eventually
consistent rates.
Well you do exactly the same calculation.
However as this is eventually consistent rates and you get to 4 kilobyte rates per second with eventually
consistent which is double the three strongly consistent.
Just take your calculations for the strongly consistent rates and you can just divide it by two.
So we take the size of each item divided by four kilobytes three divided by four point seventy five
rounded up to the nearest whole number is 1.
Then multiply that by the number of raids per second is 80.
Divide it by two because you get double the three put provincially consistent.
So that means you only need 40 read capacity units for eventually consistent reads.
For this example but what's about right capacity units.
Well just imagine you want to write 100 items per second in your table and H item is 512 bytes in size.
So firstly you would calculate how many capacity units are needed for each.
Right.
So the size of each item divided by 1 kilobyte for right capacity units so that's 512 bytes divided
by 1 kilobytes equals zero point five round that up to the nearest whole number.
So each rights will need one right writes capacity unit per write operation and then multiply that by
the number of rights per second.
So that's 100 white capacity units required in this example.
So let's have a look at some of our exam tips.
So it's really important to understand read and write capacity units.
And it's important to know how to do those calculations as well because if you do get asked in the exam
it will be really easy marks if you know how to do the calculation.
So just remember provisional throughput is measured in capacity units one right capacity unit is 1 1
kilobyte right per second.
One read capacity unit is one for kilobyte strongly consistent rate or two for kilobyte eventually consistent
reads per second.
So that is the end of this lecture.
As I said it's really important to understand how to do those calculations.
So it's definitely worth doing our quizzes and doing our tests and making sure that you fully understand
how to do those relations.
But if you have any questions please let me know.
If not please feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank ye.