Helen pluckers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about the dynamo D-B on demand capacity
pricing option.
So let's get started at re-invents 2018.
They introduced a new pricing option for Dynamite e-bay.
So in addition to the provisioned throughput model which we've already talked about where you specify
your read and write capacity units they have also introduced this on demand capacity pricing model as
well.
So with on demand capacity charges will apply for reading writing and storing your data but the difference
is with on demand.
You don't need to specify your capacity requirements so you don't need to specify your read and write
capacity unit requirements.
Time in my database will instantly scale up and down based on the activity of your application.
So based on the number of reads and writes that your application is making to the database and this
is going to be really great for unpredictable workloads.
So for example if you don't know the capacity requirements of your application if your application traffic
is difficult to predict or your workload has large spikes which are short lived or if it's a brand new
application where the workload is not really very well understood.
And it's also really good if you only want to pay for what you use when you use it.
So a pay per request model and this is going to be great for service stocks which have that pay per
use pricing model.
So I know what you're thinking which pricing model should I use.
Well the workloads where you have unpredictable application traffic you don't know what the workload
is going to look like if you want a pay per use model.
So for example if the rest of your stack is service and you're paying per use for everything else or
if you have spiky and short lived peaks then under those circumstances you should go for the on demand
capacity.
However if you have predictable application traffic you can easily forecast your read and write capacity
requirements or if your application traffic is consistent or it's increasing gradually.
Then under those circumstances it's more cost effective to use the provision to capacity and you can
actually change your Deiner IDB table from provisioned capacity to on demand once per day.
So they actually let you switch between the two pricing models.
Now this new on demand option it was only introduced right at the end of November.
So it was announced at re-invents 2018 and they do wait at least six months before introducing a new
feature into the exams.
And in practice it can be much longer than six months before they actually update the exams.
So right now we don't think this is going to feature in the exam in any detail but it's just good to
be aware of when you are designing your dining ID the tables.
So that's the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank ye.