Hello Clockers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is called TOYNE MIDP accelerator and it's
also known as tax.
So let's get started.
So what is daks Well dynamite D-B accelerator or tax is a fully managed clustered in-memory cache for
doin MIDP and it really gives you a massive performance improvement for your dynamo D-B tables but only
for read performance.
And they claim that it can deliver up to 10 times read performance.
That really is significant.
So it gives you micro-second performance.
And for millions of requests per second.
So it's ideal for read heavy and also bursty read workloads for example auction applications gaming
applications and retail sites specifically during Black Friday promotions or at Christmas time or any
time when they have a special promotion on.
So for example just think of a retail Web site and they're running a big promotion.
They've got all their product catalog data in Dynamo DP of course while those promotions are on and
while there's really good bargains to be had a lot of people are going to be wanting to look at their
Web site.
Look all the information about their products and decide which products they're going to buy.
So in that situation I don't know IDB would get really hit really hard.
There will be many many read operations and that's a really good example of when you could use tax to
improve the read performance for all of those different cores.
So how does it work.
Well DAX is right through caching service and this means that data is written to the cache as well as
the back backend store at the same time.
So that means that any time the dining Modibo table gets updated you add a new item or you modify an
item as well as writing that change into its own MIDP.
It also gets written to tax as well.
It also allows you to point your IP Miko's at the tax cluster.
So instead of having your application query doin MIDP it will try and query the tax cluster first and
if the item you're looking for is in the cash.
And that's a cash hit tax will then return the result to the application however if the item is not
available and that's the Kashmir's then tax performs and eventually consistent get autem operation against
Doyne MIDP.
So it gets the item out of dynamite pain it writes into its cash.
And it also hands it back to the application side retrieval of data from daks reduces the rate load
on your Dhanam IDB typos and in some cases you might even be able to reduce the provision to read capacity
on your tables.
So that means you can save some money on your Dhanam IDB bill.
But what is it not suitable for.
Well it caters for eventually consistent rates only.
So it's not going to be suitable for applications that require a strongly consistent raids.
So if your application really requires strongly consistent rates tax is not going to be a benefit in
that situation.
It's also not really suitable for write intensive applications.
So you're not going to get a benefit from using daks because it only helps with Reed operations.
Also applications that don't perform that many read operations are not really going to see a benefit
from configuring daks and the same goes for applications that don't require a microsecond response times.
There's no point in configuring it if you don't need that low latency.
So what are our exam tips.
Well just remember Duc's provides in-memory caching.
So dine in my db tables improves the response times for eventually consistent reads only you point your
API calls at the docs cluster instead of your table.
If the item you're querying is on the cash tax will return it.
Otherwise it is going to perform and eventually consistent get item operation to your dynamo D-B table
and it is not suitable for write intensive applications or applications that require strongly consistent
rates.
So that's the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not please feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.