Hello Clockers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about elastic hash and elastic Cassy's
in-memory caching and it can sit in front of any kind of audio database.
And also it can be used in front of Dynamo D-B as well.
So let's get started.
So what is elastic cash.
Well is in-memory cash in the cloud.
And it's used to improve performance of web applications allowing you to retrieve information from fast
in memory cache rather than slower disk based databases.
It sits between your application and the database.
For example an application frequently requesting products specific information for your best selling
products.
So for the best selling products the application is frequently requesting the same information and by
caching that it just makes the subsequent requests for that information much much faster because they
don't have to go to the database and retrieve it from the disk.
When we get data out of the cache it's much much faster.
And it also takes the load of your databases and it's really good if your database is particularly read
heavy.
And also if the data is not changing very frequently so some of the benefits are that it improves performance
for the real heavy workloads for example social networking gaming media sharing and Kunai Porto's frequently
access data is stored in memory for low latency access which improves the overall performance of your
application.
And it's also really good for compute heavy workloads.
So for example recommendation engines because it can be used to store results of your IO intensive database
queries and also the output of compute intensive calculations.
And there were two types of elastic cash as memcached and Reddy's and memcached is really widely adopted.
It's multi-threaded as well.
So it's really good if your applications are multi-threaded.
However there's no multi azy capabilities so it's not clustered.
It's only standalone if AWOS loses that Elastica service you're going to lose everything that's stored
in your cash.
And there's also Ready's which is it's open source and it's an in memory key value store.
So when we say key value the key is normally the name and the value is the actual data stored.
It supports more complex data structures like sorted sets and lists and crucially it also supports master
slave replication and multi Asie across Asie redundancy.
So this is a better choice if you if it's really important not to lose the data that's been cached.
If so if elastic cache went down if they lost the cache node went down and you lose the data your application
loses the data stored in it in the cache.
If that's going to be a problem then Reddy's would be preferable because you got the Motegi cross-site
redundancy.
Now there are two caching strategies available lazy loading and right three now lazy loading it loads
the data into the cache only when necessary.
So when a request is made if the data is in the cache the cache will return the data to the application.
But if it's not in the cache or has expired elastic cache then returns now and then your application
fetches the data from the database and it writes the data received into the cache.
So that is going to be available next time.
Now the advantages of this or that are the requested data is cached.
So that means it avoids filling up the cache with useless data that never gets requested.
It also means that a node failure is not going to be fatal.
So if your elastic hash node fails and you bring up a new one it just means that new node is going to
have an empty cache and it's going to have a lot of cash misuse initially.
Some of the disadvantages of lazy loading are that there is a cache miss penalty.
So if you want to retrieve some data from a nasty cache and it's not in the cache you have a cache miss.
So you've made the initial request.
You don't have to query to the database anyway.
And then finally you need to write the data into the cache for next time.
So there is that additional The head of the initial request query to database and writing the data to
the cache.
Additionally with lazy loading the data can become stale.
So if data is only updated when it's a cache miss it can therefore become out of date and it doesn't
automatically update if data in the database changes so how do we do this day or Deiter.
Well within elastic cash we can add a time to live or TTL to our data.
And this specifies the number of seconds until the key or the data expires to avoid keeping Stylo data
in the cache.
Lazy loading will then treat an expired key as a Kashmir's and this will cause the application to go
and retrieve the data from the database and then subsequently write that data into the cache with a
new TTL and depending on how frequently your data changes it doesn't eliminate our data but it does
help to avoid it.
Now another caching strategy is called right through caching and this adds or updates data to the cache
when data is written to the database and the advantage of this is the data in the cache is never stale.
However it does involve a light penalty because every right involves a right to the cache as well as
a right to the database.
However users are generally more tolerant of additional latency when updating data than they are of
when retrieving it.
So maybe we could say that right penalty is not such a big disadvantage.
If a node files on a new one is spun up data is missing until added or updated in the database.
Although we can mitigate that by implementing lazy loading as well in conjunction with write three.
However one of the main disadvantages of the write three strategy is that you end up with wasted resources.
If most of your data is never read.
So if you have a database where a few records or a few items in your database are very frequently accessed
and then most of the vast majority of the data in your database is hardly ever read.
It wouldn't make sense to use the right through caching strategy.
And you might be wondering what is the difference between DACs and elastic hash because they both provide
in memory caching both the supported vidanta might be.
But just remember that Dax is the one that is optimized for only for use with doyenne MIDP.
It was specifically developed just for IDB undocks only supports the right through caching strategy.
It doesn't let you use any other caching strategy like lazy loading for example.
So if your application is using dynamo IDB and it needs to use an in memory cache and you need to use
lazy loading you can't use Dyaks and in that instance you would select elastic cache.
But generally speaking fits on the Mighty Ducks is the one to use an elastic cache is the one to use
for Adhya.
So what the elastic cache exam tips.
Well just remember it's an in-memory cache.
It sits between your application and database.
It uses two different caching strategies.
We have lazy loading and right three lazy loading only caches the data when it's requested and an elastic
cast node failure is not nice or you just get lots of cash misses with lazy loading.
There is a cache missed penalty.
So your initial request query database and writing to the cache with lazy loading.
And you could avoid it stale data by implementing a time to live on your data.
The right three strategy bytes data into the cache whenever there's a change to the database that data
is never style.
However there's a right penalty because each write involves or writes to the cache and an elastic hash
known failure means that the data is going to be missing until added or updated in the database.
And you've got wasted resources.
Unfortunately if most of your data is never used so that is the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.