Hello Cocker's and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is just going to be a really quick lecture
introducing dynamo ODP transactions.
So what kind of IDB transactions while this is something that was introduced at re-invents 2018.
So in late November 2018 and Diana IDB transactions or to support mission critical applications which
need an all or nothing approach to that database transactions and you may have heard the term acid before
in relation to database transactions.
An asset is really is just an acronym it's used to describe the ideal properties of a database transaction
on those properties all that each transaction should be a Tolmach so that guarantees that the transaction
is treated as a single unit.
So basically it's all or nothing and it cannot be partially completed the transaction must also be consistent.
And that just means that it must be a valid transaction.
It must leave the database in a valid state and that just simply prevents any database corruption or
data integrity issues.
Transactions must be isolated and that just means that there's no dependency between different transactions.
They could either be completed in parallel or sequentially the effect of the transaction is going to
be the same.
And finally the transactions must be durable.
And this just means that when a transaction has been committed it's going to remain committed even after
a system failure or a power loss.
So once it has been committed that means it's going to be written to disk rather than being held in
memory.
So the main idea is that transactions which possess these qualities can be treated as a single operation
on the data and the jury ability of the operation is guaranteed in the event of a system or power failure.
And this is really great for mission critical systems.
So for example if you think about a financial transaction if you are transferring money between one
account and another that kind of transaction it might involve multiple steps.
So for example checking there are sufficient funds in the spending account then debiting the account.
And then finally crediting the receiving account and doing that all as one single transaction and for
that kind of transaction you really want to as an all or nothing transaction you wouldn't want that
kind of transaction to be partially completed.
And of course you want it to be durable across system files.
So if the system rebates or the application restarts you want that transaction to still be in the system
after a reboot or a restart.
So let's see how that could really work in practice in DONE MY MY.
Imagine you are developing a game where each player can purchase items using virtual coins.
You might have two different tables so for example we've got a play table here including the player
id any inventory they have so any items they've already purchased.
And how many coins they have.
We then have an item's table with all the items available to purchase a price whether they are available
true or false and who they are owned by.
So you could use IDB transactions to run a single atomic transaction.
So if my player wants to purchase for example one of the items in the table you can actually create
a IDB transaction which will check that an item is available.
If I wanted to purchase that Barry I could have gone to my D-B check whether the item is available.
So yes it is the availability is true.
It can then check whether I have enough coins to purchase the item.
And then if those two conditions are satisfied the item can then be marked as owned by me and then kind
of in my inventory as well.
And that can all be accomplished using a single dynamo IDB transaction.
So you can say that this is a really powerful new feature which allows you to implement complex business
logic into a single atomic transaction.
And as I said this was only announced at reinvent 2018 so the end of November 2018 and we don't expect
it's going to appear in the exam for least another six months or so after the announcement.
It's just really good to be aware of when you are designing your own Doyne IDB tables but we don't expect
it to appear in the exam straightaway.
So that is the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank ye.