OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture.
So this lecture is on cloud watch and cloud watch is basically is one of the most important services
that you need to understand inside out when going to sit your exam.
So we're going to look at cloud watch and how we can do monitoring and reporting.
So start with cloud which is basically it's monitoring service to monitor your AWOS resources as well
as the applications that you run on well yes and cloud watch can monitor things like computer monitors
things like your auto Schelling groups your elastic load balances route 53 health checks.
You can do storage and content delivery so abs volume storage gateway cloud from cetra can also monitor
things like your database and analytics so these are things like dynamite Bay or less cache nodes are
instances where lastic that produce job flows redshift et cetera and it can also monitor other things
such as this and estop access and eschewed ops works.
Cloud watch logs estimated charges on your AWOS bills et cetera.
So the most fundamental important thing to understand going into your exam is what it monitors by default
when it comes to E.S. to and then what you need custom metrics for.
So by default it meannesses these things called Host level metrics and they consist of basically four
different things three different things from a physical point of view and then a status check.
So the three different things.
You network and disk so components are things like CPQ utilization or network throughput or disk IO
for example.
And then it can also monitor the actual health of both the PC to host as well as the PC to instance.
These are known as status checks.
What it can't monitor is things.
So if you think about it holistically it can see its disk as a whole as a physical piece of hardware.
What it can't see is the individual.
Let's say we go down to the individual virtual disk it see how much storage space is left or is still
available.
It can't see Ram utilization can't see things like that.
What it can see is the C.P utilization.
It can see things like the network utilization and the overall disk activity so the overall disk throughput
but that's where it stops.
And then it can also do things like your status checks.
So anything else that falls out of CPQ network disk will status check is a custom metric.
So things like Ram utilization for example how much memory is your easy to instance currently utilizing
all of which has provision to it.
And so that is what we call a custom metric and we will have a lab coming up which will show you how
to monitor this.
We're going to use a postscript to go in and configure it on R-S.C. to it since then we're going to
start pushing this these metrics to cloud watch.
So just remember going into your exam if it's not CPQ network or disk or the actual status of the PC
to hardware.
Sorry the easy to host as well as the PC to instance then it's going to be a custom metric and you will
be tested on this through out the exam.
Also it's really important to understand how long cloud watch metrics are stored.
You can retrieve data using the get metrics statistic API or by using third party tools offered by AWOS
partners and you can store your lock data in cloud watch logs for as long as you want by default Lovelock's
logs will store you'll log data indefinitely so you can change the retention for low group at any time.
You could just say ok for my age obeys I only want you know data for the next.
For the last two weeks.
But for my you see two instances I want to go all the way back to six months so you can change it but
by default it is logged indefinitely and you can also retrieve data from any terminated E.S. to or less
load balance instance after its terminations do bear that in mind as well in terms of metric granularity
it really depends on the AWOS service many metrics.
For many default services a one minute but it could also be three minutes or five minutes depending
on the service.
Now you will get a you get basically normal monitoring and detailed monitoring normal monitoring is
every five minutes detailed monitoring is ever a one minute and custom metrics so things like Ram utilization
which we'll see coming up the minimum granularity that you can have is one minute.
Now one important thing to note here is if you have just your default cloud watch settings on for say
AC 2 you're only ever going to get five minute data points.
That's even if you do have a script that's pushing data to cloud watch every one minute cloud watch
will actually aggregate that over the five minutes.
And again we're going to see that in the lab coming up terms of alarms you can create an alarm to monitor
any Amazon Cloud watch metrics in your account and this can include easy to CPQ utilization elastic
load balance and latency or even the charges on your AWOS bill and you can set the appropriate thresholds
in which to trigger the alarms and also what kind of action should be taken if an alarm state is reached
and we're going to cover this off in a subsequent lecture.
But you could just tell it to an S and S notification saying oh look up the owner of a $10 Oh my NWS
account for this month.
Or you could even have it trigger lambda function which goes through and just starts deleting all your
infrastructure it's entirely up to you.
But Cloud watch alarms can basically trigger an action to be taken which you would go in and configure.
And yeah it's really really powerful stuff.
So onto my exam tips just remember what cloud watches it's a monitoring service to monitor your AWOS
resources as well as applications that you run on AWOS your host liberal metrics oyes consist of Seip
you network disk and your status check if it's asking you about a metric outside of this such as Ram
utilization or even the amount of storage space left on a virtual hard disk.
You're going to need custom metrics or ram utilization is a custom metric.
I remember that full custom metrics the minimum granularity is one minute.
So moving on terminated instances you can retrieve data from any terminated AC two or elastic load balancing
instance after its termination and cloud watch Loeb's by default a stored indefinitely.
And then finally just remember with your metric granularity So you have one minute for detailed monitoring
and five minutes for standard monitoring.
You may get some scenario based questions just asking you for two minute monitoring.
And how would you achieve that.
Well you're going to need to use detailed monitoring rather than standard monitoring.
And one thing I didn't really cover off in this lecture.
But one thing you should definitely be aware of is that cloud watch can be used on premise as well.
It's not restricted to just AWOS resources.
You can definitely use this inside your or your own data center and you can have the metrics being reported
back to your cloud watch dashboard you know inside AWOS from your own data center and the way you do
this is you need to download and install the SS agent.
Then once that's installed you need to download and install the cloud watch agent.
So that is it the dyslexic guys in the next lecture we're going to go ahead and start getting our hands
dirty with cloud.
So if you've got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.