Say hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture we're going to look at how we can monitor
too with custom metrics.
And as you all know I hate death by PowerPoint so we are going to dive in and start getting practical
right from the start.
In this course the very first thing I just want to remind you of is what you learned in the last lesson
and that's that highest level metrics consist of you network disk and the status check.
So basically any easy to instance using cloud what you can go in and you could monitor C.P monitored
network you could monitor disk usage and by disk usage I just mean like disk IO I don't mean the available
hard disk space left on a virtual hard disk drive.
And you can also monitor the status of the individual virtual machines.
Now what you couldn't monitor by using host level metrics is Ram utilization or even as I just said
storage of your virtual disks.
These are all done using custom metrics and we got to learn how to install a custom metric on our easy
to instance in this lab.
One other thing I just want to point out is that custom metrics the minimum granularity is one minute
we are going to look at the difference between standard monitoring and detailed monitoring.
As I said in the last less than standard monitoring is every five minutes detailed monitoring is every
one minute I'm actually going to create a custom trick that's going to push out stuff to cloud watch
every minute and we'll see whether or not we can pick that up using standard monitoring or whether or
not we use detailed monitoring.
So this is a lab you will need to look into the AWOS console.
OK.
So here I am in the AWOS console the first thing I want you to look at is the region.
I'm in Northern Virginia.
I would recommend using Northern Virginia for the rest of this course.
The very reason behind that is it's USDA one that's basically where ABS roll out every single new service
so it always has all services available.
The one bad thing about us is one is that it is the region that goes down the most.
So maybe if you are running production workloads in the United States you might want to use US West
one or at least have some redundancy around us one.
So that being said the very first thing we're going to do is we want to use a provision in H-2 to instance
and we want to send metrics up to cloud what we need to send some custom metrics such as Ram utilization
in order to do that.
We're going to need permissions to talk to cloud watch.
So we're going to need to go over to identity access management first.
So you can find I am here on the security identity and compliance.
Go ahead and click on it.
You're going to get this dashboard.
I have used this account the other courses.
That's why you're going to see things like preexisting roles and users and groups just ignore that.
Go ahead and go over to roles.
We're going to create a new role we call this road cloud watch in here the service that's going to use
this row is easy to use so we're going to use the to is going to use this road to talk to cloud watch.
Go ahead and hit next and here as we create our role we need to apply a policy to the row.
So what we want to do is go and do a search for cloud watch and we're just going to there's a whole
bunch of different cloud watch here.
I'm going to just do cloud watchful Lexis.
That is against lease privilege.
You definitely don't need full access to cloud watch to report ram utilization.
But I'm just doing this as a demo to make things simple.
So go ahead and click on cloud watch full access and go and hit next the roles name.
I'm just going to call it cloud watch and then E.S. too.
So I know exactly what it does and I'm going to go ahead and create the row.
We've now created all we can see it in here if you want to go ahead and have a look at the actual policies.
It's kind of a pretty basic Jason which is basically just saying action and then cloud watch.
And then the effect allow resource everything etc. etc..
So what we want to do now is go over to services and we're going to click on E.S. too and we're going
to go in and provision our easy to instance.
So we're going to go ahead and launch an instance I'm going to use the Amazon Linux 2 am I.
And I'm going to leave everything as default in here.
I'm going to add in my role so cloud watch easy to do.
And then in here I'm going to run a bootstrap script to show you right now.
So here is our bootstrap script and hopefully this looks familiar to you if you've got no experience
bootstrap scripts please go back and do the solutions architect associate course in here.
This is why the way bootstrap scripts always start.
So we start with a shebang which is just the number sign followed by an exclamation mark followed by
forward slash been for a slash Bash and that's just the path to our interpreter and our interpreter
basically just takes these commands and runs them at root level when the two instance ferse boots up.
So straight away we're updating the AC to instance with all the latest security patches.
And here we are installing a whole bunch of different pills services then changing the root directory
over to easy to use with then downloading our cloud watch monitoring scripts and unzipping it deleting
the zip file.
And that's all that this bootstrap script does.
So actually copy this into your clipboard and here these are the commands that we're going to run for
the rest of this lab but we're not actually going to run them in the boot script so of commented them
out but you will need these commands later.
So like I said copy this into a boat and switch over to your web browser.
And I'm just going to pasted in here and I'm going to go ahead and hit next to add our storage gang
to leave that as default and add some tags.
I'm just going to call it the name of this easy to instance.
I'm just going to call it easy to cloud watch cloud watch go ahead and hit next to configure my security
group.
Now if you are using brand new account for this course go ahead and create a new security group or might
just do that.
Or call it my web DMZ my web DMZ and use the same security group name as my description.
And then I'm going to go in and add some rules to S-sh we want them to the world.
I'm also going to allow TTP and allow that open to the world and hey can see the IP for an IP V-6.
Again if this is all new to you and you've never done this before.
Make sure you go back and do the solutions architect associate or developer associate course we do assume
that you've already done all this in the previous course so you have some experience with AWOS.
So essentially we're just opening S-sh and hates TDP up to the world.
Let's go ahead and hit review and launch and I'm going to go ahead and hit launch.
I don't actually have a existing keypad that I've saved on this computer.
I'm going to create a new key pair are just going to call it my PC two key pair.
OK.
So we go.
I go ahead and hit download.
And that has downloaded that key pair.
And I'm going to go ahead and launch my instance.
Now this will take a couple of minutes to provision.
So I'm just going to pause the video and wait until this is up and running and I have already got my
public IP address.
I will copy that into my clipboard and once it is up and running I'm going to S-sh in to my A.C. to
instance.
Now again we do show you how to do this in the developer associate.
And these solutions architect associate course certainly for Windows users if you're using a party if
you don't know how to S-sh in to an easy to instance I do recommend you go watch those courses also.
Alternatively you could just click in here and good actions and hit connect.
And Amazon will give you instructions on how to connect using potty just by clicking on that link.
So hopefully everyone knows how to S-sh in to an easy to instance if you don't go back and do these
solutions architect associate course.
So this is the two instances now up and running.
Like I said I'm just going to copy this into my clipboard and I'm going to go over to my terminal window.
Windows uses you should go over to putty.
OK.
So I'm in my downloads directory.
The first thing I need to do is change my case so I created a new key.
I just need to change the permissions.
It was called My easy to keep it up.
PM And so I changed the permissions on that to 400.
I can now use this key and to connect to my easy to instance.
All I need to do is type in S-sh.
Easy to hide the user at.
And then the IP address and then the identity and then my E.S. two key pair my two key pair P M and
go ahead and hit enter.
It would then say do you want to show you want to continue connecting here.
Yes.
And there we go.
Now connected into my instance if you're using party again it's slightly different.
If you haven't if you don't know how to do it go ahead.
More solutions architect so she calls.
We show you how to do it in them.
So what I'm going to do now is going to elevate my privileges to root and we're going to clear the screen.
And I'm just going to type in l s and we can see this directory is there.
That's what my bootstraps script has unzipped and installed and I go over to that directory so you see
the AWOS scripts dot man and type in LS.
I can see I've got two files in here so I've got the get instant stats and I've got to put instant stats.
So before we do anything with these files I want to head back over to the AWOS console.
OK so I'm back in the AWOS console going to click on services and then what I want to do is I want to
go down to cloud watch cloud which is under our management tools and I click in here and if you haven't
used cloud watch before it's going to come up something very similar to this.
Go ahead and click on the browse metrics in the metrics summary.
Now you can see here that I have actually used cloud watch before used it for a whole bunch of things
including API gateway lammed etc..
You probably won't see anything in here other than easy to click on E.S. to.
You can see here you've got your per instance metrics now per instance metrics adjust things like your
network in your CPQ disk and then your status check.
So these are the ones that come by default.
These are your you know your metrics that come with the cloud watch come with an easy to instance these
not custom metrics.
So to make that very very clear.
So I'd go back and go to browse and then click on E.C to we cannot see anything in here other than our
per instance metrics.
Let's go back over to our terminal window.
Come back in the terminal window and the first thing I want to do is I want to go ahead and I'm going
to run a put instance command but I'm going to do this.
The bogusly So we're not actually going to put anything into cloud watch we're just going to go ahead
and test it.
So if we Alt-Tab over to our text file we can see the command dizzied.
Yeah.
So we're doing put.
Instance and we're going to put in our memory utilization.
We're going to do use the switches verify and then the Birse.
So just copy that into your clipboard go back over to terminal and paste that in and go ahead and hit
enter.
And if your role is working and the command is working and you've been started to the correct directory
you should see this verification completed successfully.
No actual metrics were sent to cloud watch.
And we can actually verify that by just going back here and refreshing the screen again you going to
see just per instance metrics you're not going to see anything else.
Well let's go ahead and actually send some data to cloud watch so to do that we're going to use this
command here.
And basically we're going to send down memory utilization data memory use data and all memory of available
data.
So we're going to put this into cloud watch for the very first time.
So copy that into your clipboard go back to your terminal window and go ahead and paste that in and
go ahead and hit enter and you'll be able to see here it says successfully reported metrics to cloud
watch.
And here's our reference ID.
Now if we actually go back over to our terminal window and hit refresh it might not happen straight
away.
It can it can take up to five minutes because right now we don't have detailed monitoring turned on
we've got standard monitoring turned on.
So it can take five minutes for this to appear.
So I'm just going to pull up the video and wait for five minutes.
OK.
It's been about five minutes.
Just clicked on the boards back on the clutch dashboard back.
We go ahead and click on browse metrics we will now see a new metric.
So it isn't actually under ACTC it's under a new thing called Custom name spaces.
And in here we can see a Linux system we click on that we can see our instant site day and we click
in here we can see three new metrics we can see our memory utilization our memory available and our
memory use.
And right now there's only a single data point.
So we've only pushed this information into cloud watch once what we want to do is go ahead and automate
this when we want to push it in every five minutes or even every 1 minute.
So let's go back over to our techs bootstrap script and in here you'll be able to see this following
command.
And we're going to add this to our Crohn tabs so Krone's just like should do tasks in Windows.
Basically you can set a set up to run a command every minute or every five minutes or every month or
every day or every week.
And it will run the command So here's where you specify.
Basically this is every minute.
So we've got the air strikes divide by 1 so we're going to send this command every minute of every day
of every week of every month and we're going to run this route and we're going to run the following
command so we're going to put all memory utilization memory use memory available up into cloud watch.
So I'm just going to step back over to my terminal window.
I'm going to go over to my PC directory and I'm going to go ahead and type in Nannar and then Crohn
and we're going to go ahead and type in.
I typed in Condi but it's actually Krown tab and that is going to open up my contact and I'm just going
to scroll all the way down.
So in here you can see the different wild cards what they say.
Basically if you do wildcard to abide by then one will be every minute where you could do divide by
five which would be every five minutes every 10 minutes 15 minutes whatever.
Then you've got every hour every day of the month every month every day of the week.
So by pasting this in here what we're doing is we're going to run this command every minute going to
run it over every hour of every day of every month of every day of the week.
And we're going to run that route.
So his using a route and then we're going to run the following command.
We're going to put this information up into cloud watch.
So we're going to go ahead and hit control x.
We're going to go ahead and hit save and we're going to go ahead and hit enter.
And that has now is going to run every minute and it's going to push my data up in two cloud watch.
Now I'm going to go ahead and pause the video and then oppose the video for approximately 20 minutes
I'm going to watch this day to come in and populate in my cloud watch you know console and oppose the
video right now.
OK so I'm back in the cloud ruched.
So I have left this running for quite a bit of time.
Now if we want to go ahead and have a look let's go have a look at a memory utilization and you can
see here straightaway we started getting data points at 9:30 5:00 a.m. And we've been getting data points
ever since.
Now we have been sending these data points every 1 minute.
But because I don't have detailed turned on I'm actually only getting five minute intervals.
So you could go ahead and change detailed monitoring on for this easy to instance and then you'd be
able to see it on a minute by minute basis.
But right now it's aggregating it to five minutes.
I can see here my memory utilization and I can see here my memory available and I can also see my memory
used in here.
So we do know now that our scripts are sending this information into cloud watch and cloud watch is
now logging all this and storing this data.
The cool thing about cloud watches you don't have to just use it for you easy two instances.
You can also install the scripts on your on Primm instances and you can have them sending data to cloud
which you can use cloud watch as a holistic monitoring tool for both your AWOS environment as well as
your on premise environment.
So where this will come up in your exam is that you need to understand.
Well let's go ahead and have a look at my exam tips.
So like I said at the beginning of this lecture we have a host of metrics so you always get this on
your two instances no matter what and you'll be able to monitor the following 4 items so your OCP your
network your disk and your status check things like Ewert disks.
When we're talking about disk we're really just talking about disk IO and activity on the disk.
We're not talking about things like the amount of storage available on the disk so things like the amount
of storage available and your abs volumes or the amounts of RAM utilization you're going to need custom
metrics and that's what we just went and configured in this slab.
And also remember that with custom metrics the minimum granularity is one minute in order to see 1 minute
intervals or you will need to have detailed monitoring turned on.
So that is it for this lecture guys if you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture where we're going to talk about.