OK hello pluggers and welcome to this lecture.
So this lecture is one of the last lectures in this section of the coast and it's just to remind you
the difference between cloud watch cloud trail and config.
So learning the difference between these three different services will get you marks or ground as you
go and study AWOS.
So if we remember cloud watch monitors performance so that's where you're going to monitor things like
C-p utilization ramp utilization et cetera.
You can either use custom metrics or use the metrics that a builtin member they built him metrics for
to things like just GCP disk network and then the status checks and then if you need something different
such as Ram utilization you need custom metrics so cloud watch is all about performance monitoring cloud
trail monitors your API calls Supai provision in a to instance or an S3 barcode or dynamo D-B table
that will be recorded in Cloud trial told me the time it was provisioned what resource was provisioned
whether it was provisioned successfully supervision that what the IP address is et cetera.
So this is used for auditing and then we have AWOS come fake and this is basically a way I like to think
of it as a CCTV system.
So it's going to require the state of your AWOS environment and it will notify you of changes.
So if you want to know what your the rules were on your security groups from three weeks ago you can
use config for that cloud watching cloud trail wouldn't tell you that if you wanted to know who provisioned
the security groups two or three weeks ago that would be cloud trail if you wanted to know the C-p utilization
of your AC two instances that would be cloud watch.
So in your exam you're going to get a whole bunch of different scenario questions and I'll ask you what
the appropriate service is to do something.
So is it really important to know the difference between cloud watch cloud trail and AWOS config.
So we're almost at the end of this section.
So if you've got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Think.