R.K. helicopters on welcome to this section of the Course.
This section is campus and in this lecture we're going to look at campus 101.
So what is Kamis.
What camis just stands for Key Management Service and it's a managed service that makes it easy for
you to create and control the encryption keys used to encrypt your data.
AWOS Camus's integrated with the other AWOS services including abs S-3 redshift elastic trans coda Amazon
work my Amazon relational database or Adi's and others to make it simple to encrypt your data with encryption
keys that you manage.
So the best way to learn Kamis is to start using it.
So let's go to the AWOS console and I have a challenge for you see if you can find the KAMC service
if you can see it in the console.
OK so here I am in the AWOS console.
If you go to services and you go down here you might think that you know Kamis would be and security
identity and compliance.
It's not actually or it is but it's not a visible link that you can click on.
What you need to do is go over to identity access management.
Now what we're going to do is we're going to create a user and we're going to actually create a group
and we're going to put this use in the group assign it administrator access so that they can you know
use the entire AWOS console.
And then what we're going to do is we're going to create our encryption keys and give that use access
to the case we might actually just create two users.
So why don't we go ahead and create outgroups and we're going to create a new group.
I'm going to call this my KAMC great.
So these are people who have access to mass.
We're going to go ahead and hit next and I'm going to give them the group administrator access so they
might be trusted data security Paypal et cetera.
So going to go ahead and create groups or anyone in this group will become a be able to administer Haimson
do anything at the administrative level within the console.
So let's go ahead and create our users I'm going to add a user let's call our use my key manager.
So this is the person who's going to be able to basically do administrate or you know basically manage
the keys from a permissions point of view.
And that's always best practice to have someone who can manage the keys permissions but doesn't have
the ability to encrypt or decrypt.
And then you have the opposite.
So you have a user who doesn't manages the keys permissions but they have the ability to do the encryption
and decryption.
And that way you have two levels of access.
So this will be an meninges a group.
We're gonna give them both programmatic and AWOS management console access going to do a custom password.
I'm not going to tell you what it is.
And that's what they would need in order to log into the console to Antek this so that I can log in
myself go ahead and hit next.
Can I add them to our campus group and we're going to go ahead and just scroll down and hit next.
And so this is my key manager.
Let's create that user.
And then with my other manager and you do what you don't necessarily need the secret access for this
one in the next lecture we will need a secret access but we'll do that proud day to use those.
We're going to go ahead and close up and create a new user and this will be the person who does the
description.
So my encryptor So this user is going to do all the encryption and decryption going to give them access
to the console as well.
I'm just going to create a password and I'm going to make sure they don't need to change their password
coming in.
Going to go ahead and hit save and next review and create my user now I accidentally didn't add them
to the group so just make sure that I can do that.
So if we want to do that we just go in to here clicked on my encrypt click on groups and use it a group
and I'm going to add them back to my script.
And there we go.
So we've now got our two users my encrypt and my key manager and they're both members of the kamis Mike
Hamis great.
So you know what Kamis actually is.
Well it is part of identity access management.
If you notice I am is a global service but if we go into encryption keys you can see here we've got
our regions going to use a region that I haven't used before yet in this call so I'm going to jump over
to EU London.
You can choose any region that you want but just remember going into your exam that your encryption
keys are regional So encryption keys for Kamis are regional.
You can't have an encryption key in US Swan and then use that to decrypt data.
An EU west one they have to be in the same region.
So what I'm going to do in the London region and what I'm going to do now is going to go ahead and create
my case.
So I'm just going to create one k going to call it my encryption cane to keep it simple.
And then here we've got our advance options now have the material origins so Kamis we can either use
Camus's or we can use an external for the developer associate.
This is actually outside the scope but you need to understand this if you ever want to do the security
specialty and we go into a lot of detail of that in the security specialty course.
For now just click OK M-S as your key material of origin.
This means we're not importing any material ourselves we're just letting games do everything that it
needs to do.
So go ahead and hit next in here.
You might want to do your you know war game.
Let's say one could say that this is for the finance teams.
This is what they use to encrypt payslips or something like that.
Can it go in here and in here we've got our key administrators.
Who do we want who can administer this case through the camis API or this.
We're going to give talki manage.
So they're the only ones who will be able to do administration of this.
And then define key usage permission so who's actually being able to use this key to encrypt and decrypt
data.
Well we want that to be miring crypto.
And then we're going to go ahead and hit finish.
And that has created a policy and now we have our encryption key in here.
So they go we've created our first Kamis K. in A.
M..
So what have we to learn.
Well we learned about the customer masticate.
So we created our customer master key just then in that lab and the customer M.K. consists of a few
things consists of an alias so the name that we gave to it it consists of the creation date a description
the key state and then the key material.
This can either be customer provided or AWOS can provide.
We didn't import our key material but we do do that in the security specialty course.
This one we just use the AWOS provided one thing to note about the custom masticate is it cannot leave
Kamis you can never export this if you need to export Yuki's you can and need to use cloud hate s.m.
The main difference between camps and cloud HSM is that camis uses multitenant to hardware cloud hate
Sam is dedicated to you.
So that's the main difference.
And when you are using the cloud HSM you can export your custom Mosse decays.
So how do we set this up.
Well we simply set up a customer masticate by going into I am we created an alias and the description
we choose our key material option.
So we decided to let Amazon do this.
We then defied our key administrative permissions so which user or role can administer the K but not
use the K through the camis API and then we defined the key usage of permissions so which user can actually
go in and encrypt or decrypt data using this case.
And just remember the O'Chee material options is two options.
You can either use camis generated code which is what we just did or you can import your own key material
again for the developers so shit exam that's outside the scope but you will need to know how to do that
when you move on to security specialty if you ever want to go down that route.
So that is it for this lecture guys in the next lecture what we're going to do is we're going to use
the campus API are actually going to do it at the command line level.
So we're going to spin up a little easy to instance we're going to log in and we're going to run AWOS
configure where they're going to set up the credentials for the person who has the permissions to use
encrypt and decrypt them we're going to create some plain text files and encrypt them decrypt them and
re-encrypt them then we're briefly going to look at how we can rotate our kids using the command line.
So if you got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.