OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture lecture we're going to look at camis API calls and this
is the main thing that you're going to be tested on in the certified developer associate exam.
So the best way to do this is we're going to create a little easy to instance we could do the API calls
using pi or Java ph PE or whatever.
I'm actually just going to do it at the command line because it's a lot easier and that way doesn't
matter what language you know you'll be able to follow it.
So if you've got the time please join me in the ATO as console.
OK so here I am in the AWOS console.
I'm just going to change my region.
Make sure you provision your AC to instance in the same region where you provision geochemist key in
the last lecture.
So I did mine in London going to go over to AC too and I'm going to go ahead and launch an instance.
I seem to already have it running instance which is annoying because it's costing me money so quickly
going to terminate this instance instance State terminate and go ahead and say yes and then I'm going
to go ahead and launching new instance.
I'm going to use the Amazon Linux.
I am going to configure my instance details just leave everything as default.
We all were using this instance for is to use the command line again to go ahead and add my tags.
I'm not going to tag it for anything.
Gonna select an existing security group so hopefully I've got a security group with port 80 and port
22 open.
If you don't just go ahead and create one and go ahead and hit review and launch and then I'm going
to go ahead and launch my engines.
I'm going to create a new keypad because I'm not actually sure where my last campaign was.
I'm just going to call it mine.
London K.P..
So my London pay and download that key pair is just going to close this and I'm going to go ahead and
hit launch.
It's going to take a couple of minutes while I do that.
I did not note down my secret access key for my users so my user who's going to do the encryption and
decryption what I need to do is just click on encryption keys and make sure you change all region to
where it is that you were Bicester minds EU.
London.
My encryption key in here so my user who was going to do it.
Let's just have a quick look at our key administrator.
So this is my key manager.
That's suppose an administrative administrates the key my key user is.
Mine Crypta and you can actually also add external accounts to use this key to encrypt and decrypt So
be aware of that as well.
But you can't yet add an external account to do the actual management of that case.
So if my user name is encryptor.
So let's go over to users and grab my encryptor in him and what I want to do is his security credentials.
Essentially what I'm going to do is I'm going to make that that access key inactive and then I'm going
to go ahead and delete it.
Then I'm going to create a new Access case to create access.
And now what I'm going to do is I'm going to copy this secret access key into my clipboard and I might
even just paste it into a notepad so I have it for a little bit later.
Case I'm going to just go back over to easy to grab my public appear address or running instance am
just going to grab this public IP address in there and then.
What I'm going to do now is S-sh in to my easy to instance case I'm in my terminal window going to run
S.H. 400 for my London key Pead rpms.
You'd only need to do this in OSX suffusing party or anything else in Windows you don't need to do that
and I'm now able to S-sh to easy too high for use.
And then at my public IP address there minus I and then my key names are my London keypad.
P am sure you want to continue to yes.
Can elevate my privileges to roots are are or su and I'm going to go ahead and clear the screen.
OK so we're now ready to start using the command line.
So let's go ahead and create a plain text file that we're going to encrypt.
I'm just going to type in Eker.
Hello cloud gears.
And then I'm going to output this to secret.
TIA ex-state.
And if we want to type in LS We can see secret ticks T.
We want to read the contents we just type kept secret.
T s t.
And we can say hello Klau gears.
Now we want to do is we want to go ahead and encrypt this using our encryption key before we can do
this.
We what we need to do is configure our user accounts so we need to just run AWOS configure and we're
going to have to pass AWOS our access key ID and our secret access.
So my Access Key ID is this my secret access.
Is this my default region name.
Now I am using London which is us too.
Going to type EU west and then to.
So that would put me into London.
Make sure you type the default region name for the region where your keys stored remember Kamis is regional.
It is not global despite the rest of it and being global.
And I'm just going to change my default output format as default.
So what I want to do now is I want to take my secret ticks.
And I want to encrypt this I'm going to clear the screen just to make it a lot easier to see.
And you will be able to get all of these commands in the resources section of the coast to saved as
a text file.
So here is that ticker tape so we're going to run for commands.
We're going to encrypt our plain text files so we're going to encrypt secret optics take hold encrypted
sacret then going to decrypt it into another text Cocco decrypted sacret then going to run re-encrypt.
And this is going to take our encrypted sacret and encrypt it.
Run a basically decrypt and then re-encrypt it.
Except it doesn't create a plain text file when it does that.
And then we're just going to quickly look at this command which is enable key rotation.
We won't be able to do it using our current user simply because they do not have administrator access
or you know they do not have permissions access to the case.
But you still need to know is this command going into your exam because you will be tested on it as
well.
So let's go ahead and grab our key I.D. you can see it appears here three times.
I'm here in the AWOS console.
All I need to do is click on services and I need to go to identity access management and I go over to
my encryption keys I'm going to change my region to two.
I think it was London and in here I'm going to grab my key I.D. So this is my key I.D. him going to
copy that into my clipboard and I'm just going to paste it three times into my text file so I can just
literally cut and paste these commands as we go.
So let's go ahead and paste that.
OK so let's go ahead and get started.
I'm going to copy this into my clipboard.
We're going to create our first file which is encrypted secret RTX.
OK so quickly just check this directory.
We've just got secret ticks.
If I can get that we can see that it just says Hillary cloggers.
Let's paste the first command in here.
So we have now just encrypted it using our encryption key and we've called it encrypted secret dot ticks
T.
Type in LS I can see that I've got a new file encrypted secret thought ticks.
And if I kept encrypted secret dot ticks I can see that it is encrypted it is no longer in plain text.
Let's go ahead and clear the screen grab my second command which was to decrypt my encrypted sacret.
So I'm just going to copy that into my clipboard and paste it in here and hit enter.
And then if we type in LS We can now see decrypted secret dot ticks.
So I kept that decrypted secret tactics.
They go it's been decrypted.
Last thing I want to do is just re encrypt the file so I'm going I'm going.
Going to do this using the first encrypted secret.
So it's going to clear the screen in here we can see the re-encrypt command.
So I'm just going to copy that in there and it's going to encrypt it into new encryption that takes
it's going to paste that into my clipboard from my clipboard and if I type in LS I can now see this
file and this file is now called new encryption takes place and your encryption takes tea.
Now a cat that new encryption ticks hey you can see it's now encrypted again.
It's going to clear the screen.
We're going to look at our fourth command and this is to enable key rotation.
So AWOS Kamis enable key rotation that in and hit enter.
Interestingly this user does have the privilege to do that.
So I was mistaken when I said that they would not have the privilege.
So we have now enabled key rotation on this and the rotation would just rotate this key every single
year so that it's a new key each year.
So let's go ahead and have a look at my exam tips.
So what are my exam tips the camis you do need to know these for API calls and what they do.
So we've got AWOS Kamis encrypt and this is at the command line.
But if you are using you know if you're using the DKs the key ones or encrypt decrypt re-encrypt and
then enable rotation so encrypt all encrypt decrypt it will decrypt it.
Re-encrypt will basically take your encrypted one and instead of decrypting it into plain text it will
actually Wudi Crypta.
But it will.
Re-encrypt it immediately and destroy it.
The plane takes one straight away and then finally if you want to enable key rotation you just need
to say enable rotation.
Very straight forward.
That's pretty much all you really need to know about the API calls going into the developer associate
exam.
You will need to understand what a master key is and what envelope encryption is as well.
So we're going to cover that off in the next lecture.
So if you got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.