OK hilar cloggers and welcome to this very short theoretical lecture on what envelope encryption is
a Kamis envelope encryption.
So envelope encryption is simply the process of encrypting your envelope case your envelope K is essentially
your key that you use to encrypt your data and what the AWOS camis you know system does is we basically
we take what's called our masticate or our customer master key we use this to encrypt our envelope key
and our envelope key is what's used to encrypt our data.
So that is all it is.
It's basically encrypting a K we're basically encrypting the key that encrypts our data.
So that is all envelope case or sometimes is a cold day to case.
So when we go into our decryption with AWOS we have our data.
This is encrypted.
So this is our envelope.
And in order to encrypt that we take the kamis service and we use our masticate.
And we do an encryption algorithm and we use that to decrypt our data.
And we turn that data into basically plain text and then we take out plain text data.
And we use that to decrypt our data.
So that is literally all it is.
So what do my exam tips will just remember that the customer masticate is used to decrypt the data.
Which is sometimes referred to as our envelope K and then our envelope K is used to decrypt the data.
That is all you need to know and understand for camps for the developer associate.
Now if you are interested as we go through it in an awful lot of data go as well as cloud HSM and the
security specialty and it is actually quite fascinating stuff especially using cloud HSM because cloud
Hudood security modules up until just last year actually were very expensive to get any hands on experience
with and even using AWOS Hunwick security modules up until last year you still had to pay $5000 a month.
So if your student wasn't very easy to get experience.
Great thing is Amazon's changed that pricing model now and you can get hands on experience with hardware
security modules using cloud HSM and you just pay by the hour.
So do check that out.
It is in the security specialty.
So let's go on to the camp summary lecture and then you're done with the kamis section of the course.