OK hello cloggers and welcome to the summary lectures.
You're at the end of the camis section.
I understand it was pretty much very very you know fast section of the course but it does come up in
the developers so that you can go in and delete that E.S. to instance by the way we are no longer going
to use it.
And you can go ahead and delete OK's.
One thing to note when you delete your key is you have to disable it first and then you basically have
to share it.
And it would take between seven to think it's 30 or 35 days in order to delete.
Let's have a quick look at how we can do that.
So here I am and the U.S. consulate.
I'm just going to go over to I-AM which is under security identity and compliance.
Can it go over to my encryption case.
I was doing mine out of London.
I'm just going to click in here and we can say my key in here.
And then what I'm going to do is go to key actions and I'm going to disable it first then I'm going
to go and click on this key and I'm going to go to actions should locate deletion.
It's between 7 and 30 days ago.
I'm going to show you all this to be deleted within seven days and hit show George elation.
You can't delete it immediately.
You have to wait a minimum of one week.
That doesn't actually come up in the developer associate but it does come up in the certified security
specialty.
So moving on to my exam tips just remember what camis is.
It's a managed service that makes it easy for you to create and control the encryption keys that are
used to encrypt your data.
So integrated with a whole bunch of different services including abs S3 redshift elastic trans Koita
work meio are LDS and some others to make it simple to encrypt your data with encryption keys that you
manage.
When we do this we create a custom Ammal sticky on the customer Masaki consists of an alias so its name
its creation date its description the key state.
So whether its been enabled or disabled which is what we just did then and then the key material and
this can either be customer provided or provided by AWOS.
And remember that case in camps can never be exported Kaysing cloud hates us and can terms the actual
physical underlying hardware.
Its multitenant hardware but its basically multitenant HSM as well as cloud asem as dedicated HSM device
thats dedicated to you and we do again this often a lot more detail in the certified security specialty
to set one up.
All we did is we went in and we created an alias and gave it a description.
We chose our key material options so we use the Amazon provided one.
We then defied our administrative permissions which I am users roles can administer the K and then we
defined the usage Kamis permissions so which end users or roles can actually use the key to encrypt
decrypt data.
We then went through all the material options.
Again sorry I just repeating myself but we either use the kamis generate a material or your own case
material.
We do look at how you can employ your own material in the certified security specialty.
You will definitely have to know these API calls.
So if you want encrypted data using crypt you dont need decrypt your data use decrypt if you want to
re-encrypt your data use re-encrypt if you want to rotate ukase enable key rotation.
Do not use re-encrypt for key rotation.
You always want to just use rotation McCay rotation so bear that in mind.
And then finally we looked at you know envelope encryption.
So we saw that the customer masticating is essentially what we use to decrypt the data the data.
So this is our envelope came within the envelope and we use this to decrypt our actual data.
So envelope encryption is just a way you take the K that you use to encrypt data and you encrypt that.
So that is it for this section of the coast.
You are ready to move on and you are getting very close to the end.
So if you go to any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next section.
Thank you.