Hello Clockers and well see this section of the course and this section of the Course is all about developer
best practices and the development tools that AWOS provide to enable users to build and deploy their
applications in AWOS.
So this lecture is going to be all about C and C D and the various tools that they provide to enable
you to create your CIIC pipeline completely in the cloud.
So what is C and C D.
Well C stands for continuous integration and C D stands for either continuous delivery or continuous
deployment.
And those terms can sometimes be used interchangeably.
However there is a difference and we're going to go through the difference later on in this lecture.
But ultimately C R and C D are best practices for software development and software deployment and they
enable frequent software changes to be applied whilst maintaining system and service stability.
So companies like AWOS Netflix Google and Facebook have really pioneered this approach to releasing
code and those companies are successfully applying thousands of changes per day.
So for example for the last few years AWOS have seamlessly handled over 50 million deployments per year.
And that equates to at least one deployment taking place every single second.
And this is all done without impacting their service and without any service outages.
So how are they doing this.
Well one of the ways they do this is by automating their software deployment process or their software
release process using C.I. and seedy practices.
So let's take a look at an example see work flow.
Imagine you have multiple developers and they're all working on different features or bug fixes of the
same application.
So they are all contributing to the same application and they are sharing the same application code
repository.
So for example if you've ever heard of it.
So that is an industry standard code repository often used by development teams and the developers frequently
push that code updates into this shared repository at least once a day but often multiple times per
day.
And the next stage of the process is that the coder pulse actually is integrated with the build management
system.
And this boat management system automatically triggers an automated build every time a developer commits
code into the master repository.
So this means that even for the smallest change that gets committed an automated build is triggered
to ensure that the code will still build successfully.
Following each commit however we also need a way to ensure that the new code does not break the build
or introduce any new bugs into the application.
So how do we do that.
Well the last thing we need to do here is introduce a test framework and this test framework runs a
set of automated tests on a newly built application so it might run tests like for example integration
tests unit tests.
Functional tests etc. and these tests help to identify any bugs and prevent any issues being introduced
into the most code.
And finally see our focus is on very small code changes which get committed frequently into the main
repository.
Once they have been successfully tested so there is continuous integration
and the next stage in this process is the continuous delivery and the continuous deployment process.
So lets take a look at that is so Saidie can mean either continuous delivery or continuous deployment.
There is a difference.
So continuous delivery is the development practice where the much changes are automatically built tested
and prepared for release into staging and eventually production environments.
However there's usually a manual decision process to actually initiate the deployment of the new code.
So what does that look like in terms of our diagram.
So we still have all shared code repository why all the kids Stuart build management system builds that
code into an executable application.
We have an automated test framework to test that newly built code and finally we have a deployable packaged
application
and a user can then take that deployable package application and actually deploy it into their environments.
And that is continuous delivery.
But there's one more part of this process which is the continuous deployment element.
So what is continuous deployment well continuous deployment takes this idea of automation one step further
and it automatically deploys the new code.
Following the successful testing and it completely eliminates any manual steps.
So this means that the new code is automatically released as soon as it passes through the stages of
your release process.
So as soon as the code is successfully built tested and packaged up for release is then automatically
released into your environments.
So once again small changes are released early and frequently
rather than grouping multiple changes into a much larger release
and also the build test deployment and release processes are all fully automated.
So let's take a look at that in terms of ideogram and the big change here is that there is no human
intervention to actually go ahead and deploy the package application into our environments
so this means we don't need someone to initiate the release and the decision to actually release the
code is built into the automated logic of your continuous integration and continuous deployment pipeline.
So let's take a look at some of the toes the AWOS provide to enable you to run Yosi ICD pipeline within
the cloud.
So firstly we have a W-S code commit and this is their code depositary service
and it's a managed source control service enabling you to create your own private repository within
AWOS
we then have code build which is a fully managed build service which compiles your source code.
It can run some basic tests for you and it creates software packages that are ready to deploy into your
environment.
And they also provide code to deploy which is an automated application deployment service and it can
actually deploy your code to either easy to instances on premise systems solecisms within your data
center.
And even lambda functions.
And finally they also provide ws code pipeline which is a continuous deployment service and it allows
you to Mahto visualize and automate your entire release process.
So you can use pipeline to orchestrate all of these activities and completely automate the release of
new software in your environments and that at a high level is everything that you need to know about
continuous integration and continuous deployment.
And don't worry if it doesn't make too much sense to you right now we are going to be doing some laps
later on in the course for code.
Commit code build and code deploy.
So let's take a look at some of our exam tips.
So it's definitely worth a few points in the exam.
These tools are quite new but we are expecting to see some questions about them and AWOS have a really
good white paper.
Is definitely worth reading all about dev ops and best practices around continuous integration and continuous
deployment.
So I would definitely recommend reading that white paper.
And just remember continuous integration is all about integrating or merging your code changes frequently
at least once today.
And it enables multiple developers to work on the same application.
Continuous delivery is all about automating the build test and deployment functions.
However human intervention is usually needed to actually trigger the deployment into our environments.
Whereas continuous deployment fully automates the entire release process.
So your code is deployed into production as soon as it is successfully passed through your release pipeline.
And remember the main tools that they provide to enable you to get up and running with the CD within
AWOS there's the code commit which is also control service and that is get as a service.
Then code build which allows you to compile run tests and package your code then code deploy which provides
automated deployment easy to on premise systems and lambda and finally code pipeline which is the orchestration
C ICD workflow to which fully automates your end to end release process.
So that is the end of this lecture and the rest of this section we're going to dig a bit deeper into
all these different tools and we're going to have some lapse on the code commit code deploy as well.
So if you've got time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.