So let's see if we can get code build to build our image.
For us.
And in order to do that the first thing we need is a build spec file.
And I've got one already prepared which I'm gonna show you.
And this is the configuration file for code build which tells code build exactly how to build all Docker
image and you basically add into this file all the commands that you want code build to run in order
to build your software.
And there are a few debugging commands in here as well.
But the most important bits to note are in the pre build the build and the Post build section.
And we're going to be using exactly the same commands that I used earlier when I was manually building
out the Docker image.
The first one to note is this easy or get log in and then the second one is this docker build minus
T.
And then the docker tag command.
And then finally the docker push command.
But you are going to need to do some updates on this file in order to make it correct for your own configuration.
So first of all we're going to change the region.
So just set it to the region that you're working in and I'm working EU central this time and then inside
and then within the docker target command you're going to need to change this to the correct you or
I for your own ACR repository.
And I'm just going to change that also to the central region and then the last command you need to change
is this Docker push command.
And once again you need to change it to the correct you or I.
So I'm just going to change that's essential but do just make sure that you've grabbed the correct you
or I for your repository.
So hopefully you should recognise those Docker commands.
They're definitely worth remembering for the exam and understanding what each one of them does.
And now because we've updated that file we're going to need to save it and then put it to our code commit
repository so that it can be accessed by code build.
So head over to the terminal window and I'm in the same directory where my build spec dot Yama is located
and I'm going to run get at build spec so yellow then get commits minus M and I'm just going to add
the message adding build spec dot yellow and hit enter and then I'm gonna type get push and it will
automatically push that to our master repository.
So now if we come back to our code commit click on the build specs yellow set and we can see that that
has got our updated file in there and it includes the correct you or I for all Docker repository.
So now we are ready to get code build to actually build our Docker image for us so we can go back to
services and code build and click on Create project and I'm gonna call my project Hello cloud gurus
scroll down and it's already picked up the source provider as code commit but you could store your source
in S3 get hub bit bucket etc under repository you're going to need to add the name of your code commit
repo so it's my source code repo then scroll down for the environment settings just keep to the default
so we're using an image managed by code build on the operating system it's going to be Ubuntu runtime
will be standard image I'm gonna select standard 2.0 I'm gonna keep to the default of always use the
latest image for this runtime version and then make sure you select this privileged flag so enable this
flag if you want to build Docker images and we want to build Docker images so we need to select that
flag as well on the service roll we're going to allow it to create a new service role for us and it
should have all the permissions that we need to do everything within code build then scrolling down
to the built spec section and you've actually got a choice here so it's optional to use the build spec
yammer or file or you can actually go ahead and insert your own build commands instead.
So that is actually really important to note because by default code build is going to be looking for
a file called Build spec dot Jamil in the source code root directory but to be aware that you can actually
go in and override the build spec dot Jamil if you want to by inserting your own build commands and
if we click that option now you'll see that you can you can add the commands in this text box or you
can also switch to an editor mode and build out your own basically build out your own build spec dot
Jamil within this template and this is a really useful feature if for example you're building a project
and you don't want to use the commands and the parameters contained within the build spec dot yammer
or even if you don't have permission to modify the build spec dot Jamil or you don't have permission
to edit the source code within code commit you can actually just go in and add your own commands here
and that's also a really important tip for the exam so just remember that you can either add your commands
in the console as an alternative to using the build aspect or UML but we're going to be using build
Specter also just make sure that option is selected and scroll down and create build project so that
is our build project created and in order to start the build you just click this button here so hit
stop build and if we scroll down you'll see all the options that we selected earlier and once again
you can actually go in and override some of the environment variables if you want to.
So you can add them in as key value pairs or even create parameters within parameter store for example
if you wanted to add sensitive passwords access I.D. database connection strings etc. so you can go
in and do that as well.
At this stage but we're not going to do that we're just gonna hit stop build and pray that it works.
And as the build is in progress it actually gives you quite a lot of feedback.
So it will give you feedback on the various phases of the build as it's going through and completing
them.
And you've also got access to these built logs as well.
So if you click on tail logs it should also show you the logs as well and unfortunately it does look
like we have got a failed build.
So I can see an error here called Access Denied exception when calling the get authorization token and
that is related to our it's related to the service role that code build automatically created for us.
So it looks like there was some permissions missing and the permission it needs is the easy or get authorization
token.
So let's see if we can fix that.
So I'm gonna go back to identity access management.
I'm gonna find the role that it created for us earlier.
I'm just gonna search by typing Hello.
And there is our service role.
So let's take a look at the policy and it looks like the policy it's created for us it's got access
to cloud watch logs code commit an S3.
So there's definitely some permissions missing there.
So we need to go in and attach an additional policy to this role.
So just click on attach policies and I'm gonna search for registry.
So we need to give our service role access to the easy to container registry in order to log into it
and push Docker images into the registry so select the power user role and hit attach policy and then
we're gonna go back and try our build again.
So come back to code build and just hit retry build and hopefully this time it should be successful
so that has now succeeded.
And if we scroll down and check the phase details we can see that every phase was successful and you
can click on the build logs and it just shows you the last 10000 lines of the build log.
But if you want to view the entire log you can actually click on this link here and it will take you
into cloud watch logs and by default it's going to send all its logs into cloud watch logs so you can
drill down on the logs and you can see basically second by second of what is going on with your code
build.
So that's a really good way to troubleshoot if something is going wrong within your code build.
And there's just one last thing that I want to show you which is in our ACR repository it's just come
back to services ACR go into our repository and you should see that there's another image has appeared.
So our original image has been intact.
So that's the one that we created earlier.
And then the one that we created just a minute ago that has been added to our repository and it's had
the image tag of latest added.
So that was a pretty long lab.
I hope you got it to work.
Okay.
But please do let me know if you hit any issues and in the next lecture which is going to recap on everything
that we did in this lab as well as some of our exam tips.
So that is the end of this lecture.
I hope you enjoyed it.
I hope it all worked for you.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.