Hello truckers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be a doctor and code build lab
summary as well as our exam tips.
And if you remember in the previous lab we started off with our Docker file and we manually built a
Docker image and then ran the manual commands to push the image to the elastic container registry and
then we used a plastic container service to launch the docker container using the image in the registry.
We then created a source code repository in code commit.
We added our Docker file as well as our build spec camel file which contained all the manual commands
to build tag and push the Docker image into the plastic container registry and we then used code build
to build out our image and we pushed the image to the elastic container registry and we saw the new
image appear in the plastic container registry.
So let's move onto some of our exam tips for this lab.
Well firstly the docker commands to build tag and push your Docker image to the R repository.
These are really important commands to understand and remember the first one we have is docker build
and that just builds your Docker image for you based on your Docker file.
We then have this doc Docker target command which applies an alias to your Docker image and in preparation
for pushing it into your repository.
So in this case it applies a tag called latest.
And then finally we have the docker push command and this simply pushes your Docker image into your
ISA or Docker repository.
Remember that we use the build spectre Jamil to define all the build commands and settings used by code
build to run your build.
You can override the settings in the bills backed or Yammer by adding your own commands in the console
when you launch the build.
And finally if your build fails check the build logs within the code build console and you can also
view the full code build log in cloud watch.
So that is the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.