Hello Cocker's and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about cloud formation.
So let's get started now.
Confirmation it's a service that allows you to manage configure and provision your AWOS infrastructure
as code and resources are the resources that you're going to provision are defined.
Using a cloud formation template and that is the code element and cloud formation.
It takes that templates.
It interprets it and makes the appropriate API calls in order to create the resources that you have
defined in the template and the template supports either YAML or Jason.
So you can use either YAML or Jason.
Which ever you're comfortable with to create your cloud formation templates.
So what are some of the benefits of cloud formation.
Well firstly it allows you to provision your infrastructure in a really consistent way.
So it's the same every single time there's fewer mistakes because there's less opportunity for human
error.
It takes less time and effort than it would if you were to configure things manually.
You can also version control and peer review templates and it's free to use.
However you will be charged for any resources that you create.
It can be used to manage updates to existing cloud formation platforms and it can also handle dependencies
between different resources to ensure that resources are created in the correct order and it can also
be used to really quickly and easily roll back and delete the entire stack that you've created with
income formation as well.
So it's really easy to clear up environments that were temporary or just being used to test something
you can really quickly have cloud formation roll back and delete the whole lot for you as well.
So let's look at the cloud formation template in a little bit more detail.
So once again you can use either Jamo or Jasen to describe the end state of the infrastructure that
you are either provisioning or changing.
Once you've created the template you upload it to cloud formation using S3.
So within the cloud formation console you actually upload it and ends up in an S3 bucket and then cloud
formation accesses the template within the S3 bucket.
It reads the template and then it makes the appropriate API calls on your behalf to create the resources
for you and the resulting resources are referred to as a stack and it's called a cloud formation stack.
So let's have a look at an example cloud formation templates and most of these options or parameters
are optional.
It's only really the resources section that we'll see in the next slide that is mandatory.
So everything else that you can see on this page is optional.
So firstly First of all we have the template formas version and the only supported version is 2010 0
9 0 9 and that just refers to the version of the template format.
So the acceptable the supported template format for the cloud formation template.
Moving on we have the description and of course this is optional.
So you can just add in a description of your choice something meaningful to you.
So in this case it's just describing this as a template to create an easy to instance.
Next is meta data and that is simply data about data.
Once again it's completely optional.
So you can just put in a custom field and for this one we're just providing some data about the specific
instances that this confirmation template is going to provision.
So just give us a description of web server instance moving down to parameters.
So these saw input values that you actually input to cloud formation when you actually go ahead and
launch a stack using this template.
So this is information that you need to provide when you go ahead and launch this stack.
And in this case we're defining some environment an environment type and the allowed values are either
prod or test.
So we need to provide that when we actually go ahead and launch a stack using this template.
And then the next Prometa is conditions and we can use this and we can use conditions.
Once again it's completely user defined and we can actually use this to test a condition and take action
based on the outcome of testing that condition.
So in this case we are evaluating the parameter and type which was declared in the previous section
under the premises section.
So we're evaluating that and we're saying if it ECOs to prod then we should create poured resources
only so you can use it to tell color formation to make decisions based on parameters that you have input.
At lunchtime so moving on to mappings and we can use mappings to set our own user defined families.
So for example we could set the value of an AM I based on a region so we can completely define this
ourself.
So for example the EU west one that is the I AM Are we going to use and you could define different am
I.
For every different region you could define a different for different environments etc. etc. it's all
very flexible and completely user defined.
The next section called transform.
This is quite important because this allows you to actually include snippets of code which are outside
the main template.
Now you can either include for example code for a lambda function.
You could include your own code.
You want to reuse.
There's also a lot of code snippets which I ws provides.
And I'm just going to show you the web page where you can find these.
So I'm just going to search for cloud formation snippets and there's a whole load of different exam
scenarios that you can use to allow you to declare various different cloud formation template pods.
So for example as templates sandpits the dynamite be so easy to elastic container service audience 3:53
etc etc..
Loew's there's all sorts of different resources that I have provided example code for.
So for example if we take a look at the don't do IDB one at Scott is an example piece of code for creating
a dynamo IDB table the various different properties and attributes.
Global secondary indexes provision throughput etc. all the different things you need to define for Adani
IDB table and this example here is in gyse on.
But they also show you it in YAML as well.
So you could actually create reusable pieces of code which you can store in S3 and cloud formation will
allow you to actually reference that with in your cloud formation template.
So once again it just allows you to reuse code and maintain consistency throughout your code base.
Then moving on to the resources section.
So this section of the file is the most important.
And this is where you define the AWOS resources that you want cloud formation to deploy for.
So in this case we're going to be deploying an AC to instance.
We're defining the instance type as a T-2 micro.
And we're also specifying which IMO we want to use as well.
And finally the last section of this example template is the output section.
And again this is completely use the defined and in this particular template it gets you to output the
instance ID of the SE to instance that we are provisioning and the outputs.
You can see them displayed in the console and they can also be input into another cloud formation stack
as well.
And you don't need to know the template of by heart.
It's unlikely that they're going to ask you really detailed questions about it in the exam but it's
important to understand OK what is the anatomy of a cloud formation template what with all the different
sections are used for.
And remember that the resources section is the most important section and it's the only mandatory section
of the template.
And also remember that the transform section that is what is used to reference additional code stored
in S3.
It allows for code reuse for example you can specify lambda code and also template snippets or reusable
pieces of cloud formation code.
So let's take a look at some bar exam tips for cloud formation.
So a confirmation allows you to manage configure and provision AWOS infrastructure as code.
And remember we use either YAML or Jasen for the cloud formation template file and remember the main
sections of the cloud formation template.
So we have parameters which allows you to input custom values and in the example we use an environment
type.
So in that example transformation will expect to to state which environment the resources are going
to be for for example production or test conditions used to make decisions based on a set of parameters.
For example it will allow you to provision resources based on environment.
If you've used an environment term into the resources section remember that's the mandatory section
and defines all the AWOS resources to create.
And that could be an S3 bucket.
You see two instances an audio database dynamo DB database.
Pretty much anything that you can think of within J-ws you can create as a resource using cloud formation
mappings allow you to create custom mappings for example mapping a different am I to a different region.
So depending on which region you are working in you can tell cloud formation to use specific I might
add that region.
And finally transforms.
So this allows you to reference code located in S3 for example lambda code or reusable snippets of cloud
formation code.
Both of those located in S3.
However the best way to learn information is definitely to start using it and get your hands dirty with
it.
And that is exactly what we're going to be doing in the next lecture.
So the next lecture is going to be a lab.
So if we have time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.