Hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be a cloud formation lab and
we're going to make our very first cloud formation stack.
So let's get started.
So here I am in the AWOS console and you'll find cloud formation under management tools.
So it's not under compute it's actually under management tools because that's exactly what it is.
So we use it to deploy and manage resources using templates.
So click on cloud formation and the first thing we're going to do is just click on Create new stack.
And here it's asking you to select a template.
Now you can either create a new template on the fly using design a template but we are going to use
a template that I've already created.
They also do have sample templates here and you can play around with some of the sample templates that
they have as well.
So for example you can create a WordPress blog lampstand or ruby on rails etc..
So a few different sample templates that you can have a play around with.
But we're going to use a template that I've already created and you can either specify an Amazon S3
template you RL If you have one already uploaded to S-3.
If not you can just click on Choose file and you can select a file from your local machine.
So I've already created this cloud formation template here and I'm just going to walk through the template
and show you exactly what were creating him.
So here is my template and it's a really simple template on all it's going to do is create an easy to
instance and enable us to S-sh onto that new instance as well.
So first of all we have the template format version and it's always going to be 2010 0 9 0 9 because
it's the only supported template format version.
Next we have our description and the description is that it's just a template to create an easy to instance
and enable S-sh then moving on to parameters and we're defining a parameter called key name.
And it's going to be the name of an S-sh key pad that I have located on my system to enable me to log
into my PC to instance.
So it's got a type and it's also got a constraint description to remind us to provide the name of an
existing S-sh keypad.
So remember parameters is used for inputting parameters into cloud formation when we launch the stack.
Then the next section the most important section is resources.
So this section defines the resources that we are asking cloud formation to create for us.
And the first resource is called My easy to instance it's type is AWOS easy to instance under properties
we have an instance type which is going to be T-2 micro then Image ID and this is the a.m.-I the Amazon
machine image that we're going to use to launch the instant so the operating system and this line is
really important because this is the AWOS the next who I am I which is located in EU West one.
Now if you remember I am Mei's they are region specific and if I tried to access this I am from a different
region.
So I tried to launch this confirmation stack in a different region for launch in U.S. East one for example
isn't going to work.
So what you need to do is replace this.
I am my day with another.
I am available in your region and I'm just going to show you how to find one of those.
So come back to your console click on services and go to easy to I'm just going to open it in a new
tab.
If you click on launch instance I make sure you're in the region that you like a region that you want
to work in.
So for example if you're working in U.S. aist you can just select the region and then copy.
Am I.
Id just copy that and then place that into your file.
So that will just make sure that you don't show instance in the correct region and you are using the
correct I am Id feel region.
Otherwise it will not work.
So that's the only thing that you need to change in this file.
Just make sure you update that I am ID with a valid then x 2.
I am for the region in which you are working.
Then this next line key name is actually referencing the name that we created up here which is our canine
parameter.
So it's telling cloud formation to use to associate this S-sh keypad with on instance to allow us to
S-sh into the instance.
We can also apply tacks here.
I've just created a user defined tag of name and the value is going to be my FCF instance and then the
next resource we're creating is going to be a brand new security group and this security group is going
to enable S-sh access for port 22.
It's going to have one ingress rule allowing TZP traffic on port 22 from an IP range of 0.0 0.0 forward
slash their own.
So in other words enabling S-sh to the entire world to this instance and then the last section of the
file is going to be outputs.
And in this case I'm asking how information to output the instance ID of the new PC to instance that
we have created.
So that is the really simple capitalization template and once you have updated your ID then we are ready
to continue.
So come back to the console back to the cloud formation console and I'm just going to check up here
and make sure that I'm in the correct region so I need to be an EU Ireland which is EU west one to match
my I am I.
And now I'm going to select choose File and it's going to be my cloud formation template Jamo click
on next.
And we need to give a name to all stack.
So you just give your stock a name and we need to select all SISIA sites keypad and it's coming up under
parameters.
So remember that was our parameters section of a file.
So I'm going to select a key pad that I know that I have on my system and it should only show you the
key pads that are available for the region for which you are working and just click next.
We don't need to add any more options in here but just come down to the advanced section and I just
want to show you down here that we have this rollback on failure feature and this defines whether the
stack is rolled back.
If part of the stack creation files.
So you'd have a choice and by default it's set to Yes.
So this means if something goes wrong with the information provisioning then it will automatically Roback
the whole thing.
So for example if there's a problem with your YAML template and cloud formation cannot deploy the infrastructure
the resources that you have specified in the way that you specified them then it will automatically
rollback.
However you have the opportunity to set it to no.
So you could set it to know if for example you wanted to debug a cloud formation stack that was constantly
failing.
You might want to set its notes to try and understand what is actually going wrong here.
And if you're doing this from the API for example as a disable Roback flag that you would use but from
within the console you can just disable rollback.
Just basically toggling this radio button but we're just going to keep that to the default because hopefully
this isn't going to file and we're going to click on next and then click Create and it can take a few
minutes for it to actually go ahead and create this.
Sometimes it can take about three or four minutes.
So I'm going to pose the video now and come back to this when it is complete.
So that has now completed.
And if your status has not updated you can just hit the refresh button here.
I'm not going to click on my stack and down here we can see all the events associated with the cloud
formation tasks.
We can also view the template that we uploaded.
We can look at any parameters that the parameter that we provided and we can also look at outputs as
well.
So this was why at the end of the template where we asked cloud formations to give us an output and
the output is the instance Id And that is the value.
So let's go to our easy to dashboard and see if we can find on instance so come to se.
And there is our instance so it's running.
There is the name for instance my C-f instance if we look down here at the properties of the instance
you should have the key pen name that you specified.
You can view the embed rules as well of the security group.
You should have caught 22 for everyone.
So it looks like it successfully created everything for us.
It's created or easy to instance using that pen name and it has also given us port 22 in the associated
security group.
So that should be everything that we need to actually go ahead and look into our new instance.
So first of all I'm just going to copy the public IP and I'm going to move to my terminal window now
I'm just going to try and S-sh in that instance.
So I'm going to run SISIA.
Mine is I named my key pad which is my all and key pair to come easy to use at.
And then Thyssen the public IP address of money for instance
and then we also create star instance it's opened up the port for S-sh and it's also associated that
S-sh key with on instance as well.
So that is cloud formation.
You can see that it's really really simple to use.
It's really really easy.
And if we go back to our console we can actually get confirmation to delete the whole stack as well.
So if we come back to the console going to go to services confirmation actions and delete stack yes
delete on it should delete the whole lot for you.
And there's one other thing I want to show you.
If you come down to S-3 you'll see that confirmation.
It actually creates a bucket hat with your cloud formation templates in and so located in here if you
make it public you can actually download your confirmation template there.
So when you upload a template into confirmation it actually stores in an S3 bucket on what's cloud formation
has successfully deleted all your resources.
You'll be able to delete this bucket as well but you're going to struggle to delete it before confirmation
has finished deleting resources because there's a dependency on this bucket.
So that is really everything you should need to know for the exam for cloud formation.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.