Helicopters and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be about the service application
model and it's also called Sam.
So what is some.
Well it's an extension to cloud formation and it's used specifically to define service applications.
And it gives you a simplified syntax for defining these sedulous resources.
So for example be that API is lambda functions dynamo Debby's etc. and it also has its own command line
interface called the Sam say ally.
And that's what we use to package the deployment code.
Upload it to S-3 so that it can be deployed and then deploy the service applications using cloud formation
and with the CLID you get a couple of different commands.
So the first is called Sam package and this command takes a template a Jamo template as its inputs and
outputs some compatible templates and uploads a deployment package to an S3 bucket that you specify.
So that is the first command to package up your deployment packages.
And then the second command is some deploy and some deploy takes as input the same template that you've
just created in the previous command.
It specifies the name of your cloud formation stack.
So in this example the stack is going to be called my stack and then the final parameter that goes into
that command is this capabilities parameter.
And this enables cloud formation to create an I am low on your behalf to allow the function to execute.
Now those are the main things that you need to know and understand about some for the exam.
So let's take a look at some of our exam tips.
So you need to know that Sam is the service application model and it's an extension to cloud formation
and it allows you to define a provision Cephalus applications using cloud formation.
It has its own CLIA and its own commands to enable you to package and deploy your code.
So the first is some package which packages your application and uploads a deployment file to S-3 and
then the second one is some deploy which deploys your service applications using confirmation.
But the best way to learn this really is to actually see it in action and that is what we're going to
do next.
So we're going to have a really quick Sam lab where we're going to use some to deploy a small lambda
function using cloud formation.
So if you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.