Hello Clockers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is a confirmation time lap.
And in this lab we're going to deploy a lambda function using cloud formation and Sam.
So let's get started.
So I'm in my terminal window and the first thing you're going to need to do is install Python.
Now I work on a Mac and so a Mac it already has Python installed but it has like it has a pretty old
version of it and you're going to need at least Python 3 and usually by default you get Python 2 on
on a Mac.
So if you don't have Python 3 installed on your system then you going to need to go and download that
and get that installed and only some links in the resources to allow you to find the instructions to
install Python for your specific operating system.
But I've already installed it and if I run Python Monis Monis version it will tell me that I'm running
3 dot 7 and then the next thing you need to install is Pipp.
So if you don't have that installed once you've got Python installed you can just type easy underscore
Instow and then hit and that will install it for you.
And then the next thing you need to do is install the AWOS Sam C alloy and you can use Pipp to do that
so you just type.
Pip Instow AWOS hyphen Sam hyphen C L I will install it for you.
So that has successfully installed.
So the next thing we're going to do is we're going to create an S three buckets.
And this is going to be the packet that we use to upload our Lamda deployment package of to we've created
it.
So you want to make sure that the AWOS use that you've used when you run AWOS configure has the correct
permissions to create a bucket in S3.
So to do that you can just do it ws I am gets use user.
And that's just going to tell me which user I run IWM configure with when I can get that on my system
and it's a user called Fe.
I'm just going to check in my console to make sure that user has the access it needs.
So if I come down to security and compliance click on I am going to find my user there I am and onto
my permissions I've got S-3 full access.
And if you use it doesn't have S-3 for access then you can just go to add permissions and you can directly
at that find the access that you want and just add that directly to your user.
So I'm going to come back to the terminal and the next thing we're going to do is we're going to create
our S3 packet so we can do this from the command line just type AWOS S3 and bathe and make bucket and
then S3 Kahlon hyphen hyphen and then the name of your pocket and I'm just going to call mine cloud
formation.
Sam bucket.
And then you have to specify which region you want this created in.
And I'm going to use.
I'm going to use a new West too and then hit enter.
So that's created a packet.
And this is going to be the packet that we use to upload Alamdar deployment packages after we've created
them.
So I've got two files to show you.
One is index dot J.
S which defines Ahlam to function and the other one is a cloud formation templates as well.
So I'm just going to go to my text editor to show you those two files.
So this is our index dot J S and it's just a really quick lambda function to output this string.
Hello talker's this lambda function was deployed using Sam.
So it's just a nice function.
Really very quick and simple and it's just going to output that message.
So the other file I want to show you is called lambda YAML and this is the cloud formation template.
So it's pretty similar to the one we used previously in our other cloud formation lap but the main difference
that you've got is that it uses this transform parameter here.
And this is what defines it as a Samm deployment.
So this AWOS service that tells cloud formation that this is going to be using time.
So the resources that we're going to be provisioning it's going to be a function of the type services
function.
The Hadleigh is going to be called index dot handler and the runtime is going to be node 6 10 and then
the S3 bucket.
Here we need to make sure that this S3 bucket matches the name that you used when you created your S3
bucket.
So to make sure you changed that the same name that you used.
So those are two files and you're going to need to download them and have them in the same directory
that you were working in.
So now we are ready to run our two commands are to some commands.
And if you remember from the previous lecture there were two commands that we need to run.
So the first one is some package and that's going to package up the code and it's going to upload it
to the S3 packet.
And the second one is Sam deploy and that is going to deploy or function using cloud formation.
So this is our first command and it's some package and we specify the template file lambda Jamo So that's
how cloud formation template file.
And then the output template file is going to be this file called Sam template to Jamo and it's going
to upload all Lamda deployment code into the S3 bucket that we created and has successfully packaged
everything and it's written the output to the same template Toyama.
So if we type L S we can see that some templates are Jamo has been created and we can type more
and take a look at that file.
So that is the template file that Sam and cloud formation are going to use to deploy our function.
So now we are ready to run some deploy and I'm just going to paste the command in X is quite low command
and we're running some deploy and it's using this template file some template that our previous command
created.
The stock is going to be called my stacks.
That's the name for cloud formation stack and we are using these capabilities flag to enable cloud formation
to create an eye and Roll on your behalf to allow the function to execute.
So now I'm just going to hit enter and it's just going and creating a stack right now so he can check
all this in the console.
If I come back to my console go to cloud formation and you should see that your stack is being created
it's in progress.
And you can see that it's created the eye roll ready.
So it's still in progress.
And then hopefully if this is successful we should see a message soon telling us that it has created
a function as well and it can take a minute or so to complete.
So don't worry if it's taking a little bit of time I'm just going to pause the video now and come back
in a moment.
So that has now successfully created we have a status of create complete and if we check the events
below we can say it has successfully created or lambda function.
So let's go back to services.
Find Lamda it's under compute.
And we should see our test function has been created.
So it's called my stack last modified to two minutes ago.
So let's click on that function and if we scroll down we can see the function code here and we can actually
test our function as well.
So if we go to configure test events and stick with the default template hello world and we're just
going to call it my if and click concreate and then make sure my event is selected and then hit test.
So it feels it's been successful.
And you should see execution results succeeded.
And if you click on details you'll see a status code of 200 which means a successful status code and
then you see the body count gurus this lambda function was deployed using Sam.
So that is some nice kill formation using Sam and that should be everything that you need to know for
the exam.
So the main thing to remember is that if you're deploying several applications and you want to deploy
them automatically you can use Sam with cloud formation and it definitely simplifies things for you.
And there are those two commands that we use.
Remember we use some package to create Ah-Sam templates and upload our deployment code to the S3 buckets.
And then we used some deploy to actually go ahead and deploy our lambda function using cloud formation.
So hopefully that will work for you if you have any questions please do let me know.
There's one thing I just want to remind you about when you're using cloud formation to make sure once
you have finished with your stack do you make sure you go in and delete it all.
So you can come back to cover formation select your stock hit delete stack and of course you need to
separately delete your S-3 packet and make sure you'll have the function is deleted as well.
So that's the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.