Like hookers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about cloud formation nested stack.
Now there's a whole load of documentation related to best practices for cloud formation.
But the main thing that you need to be aware of for the exam is nested stacks and stacks of stocks that
create other stacks within cloud formation and they allow you to use your information code for common
use cases.
So for example a standard configuration for lied about on the web server or application server etc..
So if you have a load balancer configuration that you use again and again in your environments you can
create a dedicated template for a light balancer and then instead of copying and pasting the config
every time you want to reuse that code you can store it in its own cloud formation template and then
reference it from within another cloud formation template.
So it is a template within a template.
So let's take a look at the cloud formation Template structure for nested stacks and nested stacks are
declared within the resources section of the cloud formation template and it's going to be of type AWOS
cloud formation stack on the properties of the supported properties or notification i o n which you
can use to define an existing Asinus topic when notifications about stock events can be sent.
The parameter section is for parameters that you want to pass to cloud formation when the nested stack
is created and you can add tags as well to describe your stack and the template you RL is the most important
bits.
And this is mandatory and this is the you are l of the template which specifies the nested stack that
you want to create and it must be a file located in an Amazon S3 bucket.
And finally you can optionally include a time out in minutes and this is the length of time in minutes
that cloud formation will wait for the nested stack to complete and the default is that there is no
time out.
And this is completely optional.
So the only element that is mandatory is the template you RL.
So let's take a look at some of our exam tips.
Just remember nested stacks allow you to reuse your cloud formation code.
So for common use cases you don't need to copy paste.
You can just reference the confirmation code from within your cloud formation template.
They are really useful for frequently used configurations.
So for example for a frequently used configuration for a load balancer web server application server
and all you need to do is create a cloud formation template defining the resource that you want to create
store in S3 and then you can reference it from the resources section of any cloud formation template
using the stack resource type so that if everything that you need to know about it's tax for the exam
if you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank ye.