Hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be our development theory summary.
So it's going to summarize everything we've learned in this section including all of our exam tips.
So let's get started.
So continuous integration and continuous deployment and all of the related toes are definitely worth
a few points in the exam and it's worth reading that white paper it's really explains the topic very
well and it will really help you consolidate all of your knowledge in that area.
So I would definitely recommend reading that before you go into the exam remember.
Continuous integration is all about integrating all merging your code changes frequently at least once
per day and it enables multiple developers to work on the same application without impacting each other.
Whereas continuous delivery is all about automating the build test and deployment functions of the release
lifecycle and continuous deployment fully automates the entire release process and it allows code to
be deployed into production as soon as it is successfully passed through the release pipeline and the
tools that they provide to allow you to get started with C and C D R code commit which is the source
control service.
So it gets as a service code build which enables you to compile your source code run tests and package
code code deploy which performs automated deployment to easy to on premise systems and lambda and code
pipeline which is the entire C ICD orchestration or workflow tool which fully automates your entire
release process right from build to test and finally deployment.
So code commit is based on get it's a centralized repository or repo for all your code.
Pineries images libraries etc..
It tracks and manages your code changes maintains version history and manages updates from multiple
sources enabling collaboration between multiple users and multiple teams.
Deploy is that fully managed an automated deployment service and it can be used as part of a continuous
delivery or continuous deployment process.
Remember there are two different types of deployment approach.
You've got the in-place also known as rolling update and this is where you stop the application on each
host and you deploy the latest code on each host either in turn or all at once.
And this type of deployment applies too easy to an on premise systems only not supported for lambda.
It's good for environments where you don't mind taking your systems offline for the duration of the
application deployment.
And remember if you want to rollback this kind of deployment you need to redeploy your previous version
of the application so it can take some time.
Then the other type of deployment approach that we have is blue green.
And remember this is where we provision new instances and then install the new application on those
new instances.
The traffic is then routed to the new instances according to your own schedule and this is supported
for easy to on premise and lambda functions.
One advantage is that the Roback is really easy and all you need to do is route the traffic back to
your original instances assuming you haven't already terminated them.
And blue represents the active deployment or your original instances whereas Green is the brand new
release.
Moving on to a default code deploy the app spec file is used to define all the parameters that you need
for the deployment.
For example the location of any configuration files application follows any pre and post deployment
validation tests run and for AC to an on premises systems.
The app Spectro YAML file must be placed in the root directory of your application revision.
So that's the same folder that contains your application code.
And remember this is what we configured in the code deploy and the code pipeline lab for AC to an on
premises systems.
The file must be written in Jamo.
However to support either YAML or Jason format and try to remember to run order of the hooks in our
code deployed deployment and I try to think of it as three different phases so the first phase would
be all the activities that you need to do in order to block your traffic at the load balancer.
So d registering you instances from the load balancer and that would be before block traffic blocked
traffic and off to block traffic.
Then the next phase would be all the activities you need to do in order to upgrade your application
or install your application.
So that would be application stop before install install off to install application start and validate
service and then the final phase.
Everything that you need to do to reregister all instances with your light balancer.
So that would be before allow traffic allow traffic and off to allow traffic.
And just remember that they refer to this sequence of events as the run order of hooks and it all relates
to the hooks section in your aspect or YAML file.
Remember Koepp pipeline is a continuous integration and continuous delivery service and it automates
your end to end software release process based on a workflow that you define and it can be configured
to automatically tracheal pipeline as soon as a change is detected in your source code repository.
And if you did the code pipeline map you would have seen that in action.
So when we updated the code that was located you know S3 bucket that automatically triggered our pipeline
to pull down that source code and deploy it to our instances.
Finally could pipeline integrates with lots of other services from a W-S like code build and code deploy
as well as third party and custom plugins.
And if you remember as part of the Lappe that we did for code pipeline we integrated with code deploy
and S3 moving on to TACA TACA allows you to package up your software into containers which you can then
run an elastic container service or s.c.s and ATOC a container includes everything that the software
needs to run including code libraries runtime environment variables etc..
I remember we use a special file called a doc file to specify the instructions needed to assemble your
doc image and once built the doc images can be stored in a plastic container registry or AC or an atheist
can then use the image stored in the registry to launch dock containers on your s.c.s cluster.
Remember there are a few different commands that Daka provides to allow you to build and tag and push
your doc image to the E.S. repository.
And the first one is to build.
Mine is T and that simply reads the Daka file and runs all the commands in the doc a file to build your
image.
We then have the doc tag command and that is used to apply a tag or like an alias to your image so that
tag can be used to refer to your image programmatically.
And then finally we have the talker push command which pushes the image into your PC or repository.
Moving on to code belled.
Sorry just remember code build is a managed build service and it can be used to build source code run
tests and produce software packages based on commands that you define yourself and by default we used
to build Specht YAML file to define the build commands and any settings used by code builder to run
your build.
And that's completely user defined.
So it's up to you exactly what you put in that build Specht YAML and code build will run it all for
you.
And remember that you can completely override the settings in the build specked YAML by adding your
own commands into the console when you launch the build.
So that means that even if you don't have permission to modify the build specter YAML or if you don't
have write permission to the source code within code commit or wherever you're holding your source code
you can always override the settings and input your own settings at the console when you launch the
build.
And finally if you build files just check the build logs as they appear at the bottom of the code build
console and you can also view the full code build log with in cloud watch so that is the end of the
section really well done so getting through that section.
I hope you enjoyed it and learned a lot.
So if you have any questions please let me know.
If not please feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.