Hello Clockers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is called Coe's commit one by one and it's
just a really quick theoretical lecture just just to give you an overview of code commit before we go
into the lab which is coming up after this lecture.
So let's get started.
So what is code commit.
Well code commit is a fully managed source control service and it enables companies to host SECU and
highly scalable private repositories.
So if you're not familiar with it it's an industry standard open source distributed source control system
and it's a central repository for all your code.
So that could be pineries images libraries scripts any artifacts that are used within your application
and it allows you to actually manage updates from multiple sources so multiple teams multiple uses.
And it also enables collaboration
so when users want to interact with code commits they create a copy known as a branch of the master
code repository and they can update this copy independently without impacting any other uses.
So that means everyone can work on the codebase in parallel save to code changes which are ready to
be applied into a repository are known as a commit and when the updated code located in a branch is
ready to be added into the master repository the branch is then merged into the master repository.
And I ws code commit provides all the functionality of get.
You can use it on your local machine to interact with your code can repo so you can run all the normal
commands like get at get commit get to push etc. and your data is encrypted in transit and in rest.
So when you connect to code commit you do it via either a shitty piece S-sh
And that's really all you need to know for code commit.
So let's just move on to our exam tips.
So the main things you need to know is based on get is a centralized repo for all your code.
Pineries images and libraries it chucks and manages your code changes version history and it manages
updates from multiple sources and enables collaboration.
So that is the end of this lecture.
And if you want to get your hands dirty using code commit Please join me in the next lecture.
Thank ye.