Helike hookers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be all about code commit and
it's going to be a lab.
So first we're going to create a new repository in code commits we're going to add a file into the repository.
We're going to create a new branch which is like a new working area in the repository.
We're then going to update our file.
And then finally we're going to merge all changes from a branch back into the most repo.
So if you've got time please join me in the AWOS console.
So here I am in the console and you will find code commit it's down on the developer tools.
So just click on code commit click on get started and they have recently updated the console for code
commit to make it easier and it much more user friendly than it used to be.
So that's why you can see this banner up here saying do I want to return to the old experience.
Well I definitely don't.
I'm going to stick with that new experience.
So this lab uses the new console.
So the first thing we're going to do is create our new repository and we're going to start by giving
it a name.
And I'm just going to call this CC repo.
You can add an optional description
and then click Create.
So that has successfully created all repository and it gives you a description of the different types
of connection you can have in your repository so you can have either CPS or S-sh.
And this just describes the different connection types from your clients.
So whenever you connect to the repository it's always done in a secure way and your connections will
be encrypted in transit using either CPS or S-sh.
But we're not going to configure those kind of connections right now we're just going to interact with
our repository using the console.
So I'm just going to close that section down.
And now we're going to add our very first file into the repository.
So click on that file and we're going to create a new file.
So we're just going to create a really simple text file.
We need to give it a name.
The name of the author and an e-mail address associated with this change that we're making.
And we can also add an optional commit message as we commit or change into the master
and then select commit changes.
So that fine has now been committed to the master and you can say that we can view the file from the
console if we click on the name of our repository.
We can see the file is located there and we can see that it's located in the Mostert branch.
And of course the most a branch that's all open source or almost a source of our code.
But just imagine that you needed to make a change you needed to update a file.
For example if you are developing a new feature or if you are fixing a bug in an existing piece of code
Well you wouldn't want to make that change on the master copy of your data.
So that is where branches come in.
And what you would do instead is you would create a new branch and you would make those updates on your
own branch and a new branch is simply a new working area and it's a copy or a clone of the original
master branch.
So let's go ahead and create a new branch.
So let's click on braunches create branch and we're going to give it a name.
I'm just going to call it my branch and we're going to select to create the branch from the master.
So it's going to be a clone of the Master.
So click on Create branch so that Sawhney Brawns created.
And if we click on the branch it has exactly the same file and we click on the file.
It looks exactly the same.
So now we can go ahead and add a file.
So I'm just going to click on it and add another line to the file.
Once again we need to add the author name so he might get it.
What's the email address and we can add an optional message.
Again
and click on commit changes.
So now we've updated the file but we've only updated it in my branch and if we go to branches We've
got two different branches there.
And you can say that we lost comment made a comment on my branch just now.
But the original branch is still three minutes out of date.
And at this stage in practice you'd probably want to get your updates peer reviewed.
You might want to run some tests say some automated tests preferably or some manual tests to make sure
that you're happy with the changes and that they're good to go and that you're confident that you want
to merge them into the master.
So once you're happy and you're ready to merge your changes into the master.
The next thing you need to do is create a pull request.
And this is going to apply the changes that we made in our branch into the Mostert repository.
So it's going to merge the change we made into that mosta branch.
So in order to do that we click on Create pull request and we need to define the source and destination
so the destination is going to be the Mahsa and the source is going to be my branch.
So select your branch and then click on compare.
And what this does is it runs a number of tests to make sure that there's no conflict between my branch
and the mosta.
So for example one of the checks it would do is it would check that the mosta has not been updated by
somebody else while you were preparing your own changes.
And if that has happened that means your own branch is going to be out of date.
And if your branch is out of sight then you're going to have to clone the code from the most to gain
and add your changes into the brand new copy of the code.
But for us right now there shouldn't be any conflicts between your branch and the master.
So we should be able to go ahead and much change into the most branch.
So first of all we need to give Amerge a title to describe what we're doing.
So I'm just going to type merging my branch into the mosta And if we scroll down it shows you this visual
representation of the changes that we're actually making is compared to two files and it's detected
that we're adding this line here.
And if you ever used Get help before it's very similar you get the same view and get hardware where
it will show you if you've deleted something changed something or added something and it would color
code that the differences between the two files.
So it makes it really easy to identify the changes that are going to be made especially if somebody
else is reviewing your code.
So let's go ahead and click Create and that will create a pull request.
So now a pull request has been created and the next thing which needs to do is click on much and that
will merge or branch into the monster repository.
And it gives you the option of deleting the source branch off to the much so do you want to delete my
branch off the merge has been completed or not.
And generally you would want it to delete that source branch off to you has merged at a later date if
you want to do another change and it's best practice to just create another branch and start again with
a clean branch.
So let's go ahead and click merge pull request and hopefully that should be successful.
So it says my branch has been merged into monster and if we click through these tabs it just gives you
an overview of the events that happened.
So she created our pull request.
We merged the pool request.
We can take a look at the changes and we can also view the commits as well and if we go back to our
branches you can see that my branch has now been deleted.
So we only have the most branch if we click on the most a branch click on the file and you can see a
file has been updated.
So it's very similar to get hub if you ever use that before.
And in addition to working in the console You can also work with code commit from your local machine
and you can interact with the repository using the standard get commands and you don't really need to
know that for the exam you don't need to memorize any get commands or anything like that.
The main thing you need to know for the exam is that code commit is a source control system enables
collaboration between different teams in different users working on the same project and it's secure
allowing you to connect using HGT B.S. and S-sh So your data is always protected in transit.
So I really just remember that the exam what code commit is and what it is used for and there's just
one last thing I want to show you on code commit which is under settings and you can actually configure
notifications using S and S and cloud watch to send notifications to subscribers when certain events
happen in your code.
Commit repository.
So for example you can send a notification when somebody does a pull request or closes a pull request
or when somebody comments on a poll request as well.
And this is why you would set it up so you can set up a cloud watch event roll.
And also an SNF topic for people to subscribe to that notifications for people to subscribe to the notifications.
So that is the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.