Helicopters and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is called Code deploy one on one and it's just
a really short theoretical lecture just explaining the basic concepts of code deploy.
So let's get started.
So what is code to deploy.
Well code deploy is an automated deployment service which allows you to deploy your application code
automatically and you can use it to deploy your code to E.C two instances on Primus systems and also
lambda functions.
It allows you to quickly release new features avoid downtime during application deployments and avoid
the risks associated with manual deployments and it also ensures that all of your deployments are completely
consistent because it removes all the manual steps associated with deploying software.
It automatically scales with your infrastructure and it integrates with various CIC Dittoes.
So for example Jenkin's get hub the Lachine suite of products as well as AWOS code pipeline and you
can also use it with configuration management tools like ansible puppets and shift and there are two
different deployment approaches available.
And these are really important tonight.
The exam.
So the first one is called in place and the second one is called blue green.
So let's look at those in a little bit more detail.
So for an in place deployments the first thing that happens is the application is stopped on each instance
in turn as shown in the diagram.
We have three instances and they're all running version 1.0 of all software.
And in order to run the emplace deployments we shut down the application on the first instance and during
this time the instance is going to be out of service.
So your capacity is going to be reduced.
We then install version 2.0 of our application and then at that point we can bring that system back
on.
And if all your instances are behind a load balancer You can also configure the load balancer to stop
sending requests to any instances which are being upgraded and then bring them back into your load balanced
group as soon as they're ready to service requests.
Now an in place upgrade is also known as a rolling update and it can only be used for AC to and on premise
systems is not supported for lambda.
And another drawback of this kind of deployment is that when you need to rollback your changes the previous
version of the application will need to be redeploys.
So it's not instant.
Moving on to the blue screen deployments with this approach in the diagram again we have three instances
running version 1.0.
And that represents the active deployment.
So the existing systems and we actually provision brand new instances and deploy the latest revision
of our software on these new instances.
So you can see in the diagram we have three new instances and these are all running version 2.0.
The new instance is then registered with an elastic load balancer.
And as soon as they're ready to service requests traffic will be routed to these new instances and eventually
the original instances will be terminated.
So the big advantage of a green deployment is that the new instances can be created ahead of time and
then the code can be released to production by simply switching all traffic to the new servers.
So the release process really just becomes a change on your elastically balance and switching back to
the original environment is also much faster and more reliable because it's just a case of routing the
traffic back to the original servers.
As long as you haven't already terminated them.
One other advantage of a green deployment is that there's no reduction in performance or capacity during
the deployment because we're not shutting down any of our active servers.
So let's move on to some of the code deployed terminology.
First of all we have deployment group and this is a set of easy two instances or lambda functions.
So it's a new revision of the software is going to be deployed deployment is the process and components
used to apply a new revision deployment configuration is a set of deployment rules as well as success
or failure conditions which are used during the deployments.
The app spec file and this is a special configuration file which defines the deployment actions that
you want code deployed to execute.
Revision refers to everything needed to deploy the new version.
So for example the spec file any application files executables etc and application is a unique identifier
for the application that you want to deploy and this identifier is used to ensure that the correct combination
of revision deployment configuration and deployment group are all referenced to in the deployment.
So let's take a look at some of our code deploy exam tips so just remember it's a fully managed automated
deployment service and it can be used as part of your continuous delivery or continuous deployment process.
And remember the two different types of deployment of Partch for the emplace or rolling update you stop
the application on each host in order to deploy the latest code.
It's for easy to on premise systems only not for Lamda and to Roback you have to redeploy the previous
version of the application.
So it's not instant and it will take you some time to rollback for the blue green deployment.
Panu instances are provisioned and the new application is deployed to these new instances.
So this means your existing application on your existing instances are not impacted at all.
Traffic is then routed to the new instances according to your own schedule and is supported for AC to
on premise and also lambda functions.
Finally Roback is really easy.
All you do is rate the traffic back to the original instances on your load balancer.
And remember TLOU is the active deployment or your original set up Claras.
Green is the new release.
So those are the basics of code deploy.
We are going to be following this up with a lab.
So you will get the opportunity to get your hands dirty with code deploy.
So if you have time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.