Hello Cokers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be a code deploy nap and we're
going to do a few things in this lab first we're going to create our own E.S. to instance which is going
to have access to an S3 bucket where our code is going to be stored.
We're then going to install the code deploy agent onto our easy to instance and then we're going to
use code deploy to deploy a really simple web application to our AC to instance.
So if I got time please join me in the U.S. consulate.
So here I am in the console and the first thing that we're going to do is where we need to create are
easy to instance.
But before we do that we're going to configure a service role with ESRI access.
So they are easy to instance can access an S3 bucket containing our source code.
So first of all we're going to find security identity and compliance on the console and a way to click
on I am and we're going to go to roles and create grow.
And it's going to be a service role for the E.C. to instant make sure the AC 2 is selected.
Click on next Am I going to search for the S-3 full access policy.
Click on next.
I'm going to give our own name.
I'm just going to call it my S-3 role and then click Create more.
We also have to create a service role with a code deploy as well.
So this is going to be an identity access management role which allows code deploy to make API calls
on your behalf and it's going to give code deploy permission to install applications on your AC to instances.
If we go into service roles find code deploy and select or use case at the bottom.
So this is to allow code deploy its core services such as auto scanning on your behalf and we want it
for easy to not for lambda so select Code deploy next on it's already selected the correct policy.
So we can take a look at this policy.
I'm going to open a new tab so we can just have a look at the policy.
So this policy allows code deployed to do all these different actions for auto scaling describe instances
and terminate instances for easy to read the tags.
It gives access to cloud watch and also registering and registering instances with your light balancer.
So those are all the permissions that will get applied to code deploy.
So if we come back to our management console click on next and we're just going to give it a name and
I'm going to call it CD service roll and click on Create.
Whoa.
So now we are ready to launch our AC to instance.
So come back to services and find AC to under compute click on launch instance and we're going to stick
with the Linux too am I.
So I select that one to my car click on next and we can keep most of the day.
So it's going to load into the default PC.
We don't need to specify the subnet you want to make sure that it's going to auto assign a public IP
because we're going to be installing a web application on this instance so we want to make sure that
we can reach it over the Internet so just make sure that setting enable is selected.
Scroll down to identity access management role and we're going to select the S3 roll that we've just
created and click Next Next the text section we're going to add a tag I'm going to add a tag code name
and I'm going to call my application my web app.
So code deploy is going to use these tasks to identify the instances that you're going to deploy the
application to.
So that is why we need to apply tax to our easy to instance.
So then click on next.
And for the security group we can just stick with the launch wizard security group by default.
It's going to give us S-sh And we're also going to add the rule for HGT page so just select HTP and
get to the rest of the defaults and then hit review and launch and before it launches the instance it's
going to ask you to select an existing key pair or to create a new one.
Now if you already have a key pair for this region then you can go ahead and use that if you don't have.
Don't worry you can just select Create a new key pad and it will go ahead and create one for you and
you can save the dot PEM file that it produces locally.
So I'm just going to acknowledge I have access and hit launch instances.
So now my instance has been created and I'm just going to copy the IP address and I'm going to go and
look into my instance.
So first of all I'm just going to make sure I'm in the correct directory for my key pad.
So that's my key pad.
So now I'm going to run S-sh minus.
And then the name of my key pad.
And then easy to dush user at.
And then the IP address of my instance.
So now that we've looked into our instance the next thing we need to do is install the code deploy agent
on our PC to instance.
And if you take a look at the resources section of this lecture I've included a text file with all the
commands that you need to run.
So let's go ahead and have a look at that in the text editor.
So these are all the different commands that you need to do in order to install the code deploy agent
on your PC to instance.
So firstly we're going to do some update.
We're then going to install Ruby.
We're going to install you get and then we're going to use you get to get the code deploy Agent files
and they're actually stored in an S3 bucket and it's specific to a region.
And actually you're going to need to change this region according to where you are working from where
you've deployed your instance where you're going to deploy your S3 bucket etc..
So it says a central one.
That's not correct for me.
I'm actually in using a West too today.
So go ahead and change that to the correct region if you don't change it it doesn't really matter.
Are you still going to be able to download it.
It's just going to be quicker if you use a region local to you.
And then the next thing we're going to do is we're going to add execute permission to the install files
that we download and then we're going to install the code deploy agent.
And then finally this last command is to just check that the code deploy agent has been successfully
deployed.
So let's go ahead and cut and paste those commands into our easy to instance.
I'm just going to add one is why so.
Well
then install Ruby
install get
with then get a CD in the user's home directory would then use this W get command to install the latest
code deploy Agent files on all system
which is going to change the permissions and execute permissions to the install file.
Then run the installation.
And then finally we're going to check the status of our code deploy agent
so the code agent is running.
That's it's process ID so that has successfully been installed.
Now the next thing we need to do is actually on our local machine.
So we need to configure our local machine as the developing machine which is going to connect into code
deploy and it's going to package up all code and upload it to S3 for code deploy to use.
So in order to do that we need to create a new identity access management user with all the permissions
required to do that.
And then we're going to run AWOS configure on our local machine with the relevant user credentials.
So first of all I'm going to go back to identity access management in the console.
Click on uses Adisa and I'm going to call my user CD user I'm going to give some programmatic access
as well because I want to be able to run AWOS configure and supply the access key and seek access key.
So then hit permissions.
I'm going to directly attach existing policies.
So the first one my going to add is for code deploy.
So I'm just going to add code deploy full access and I'm also going to add as three full access as well.
So then click on next uncreate user.
So I use has been created Amico access key and secret access key.
And this is what we're going to use when we run AWOS configure on our local machine.
So first of all I'm just going to copy the access key come to a terminal window and make sure this time
your on your local machine.
So for me that's my back and I'm going to run AWOS configure and it's going to ask for the access key.
I want to use.
So I'm just going to control the news the access key come back to the console and grab the access key.
I'm going to keep to my default region name of EU west too.
You need to make sure it's the same region that you're going to be working in.
So the same one you've created for instance and we're going to keep my deep throat at the format as
text so hit enter in preparation for this lab I've created a set of deployment files on my local machine.
So I'm going to show you the files that I've created now so I've got a directory called my web app and
inside that directory I've got a file called aspect to Jamo and that is the configuration file used
by code deploy.
I've also got index to.
Which is a simple web page that we're going to be installing on the easy to instance.
And then finally I've got this script directory and this just includes pre and post installation scripts
which are going to be run at different stages of the deployment.
So I'm going to show you these files in the text editor because it's just going to be a lot easier for
you to read them.
So let's just take a look at these in the text and it's in now.
So the first four we're going to look at is aspect to Jamo and the purpose of aspect of Jamo is to define
all the primitives needed for the code deploy deployment.
So first of all we have a version number.
Then the operating system that they this applies to then any files that we want to copy to the instance
so in this case it's going to be indexed to HMO the destination on our instance that they are going
to be copied to.
So within easy to instance this is going to be copied into opt of HMO and then this hook section defines
the commands that we want to run during the deployment.
And when we want to run them.
So before the installation there's a script which installs any dependencies and there's also a couple
of scripts to stop the application and also to start the application.
So let's take a look at some of these files.
So first of all is the index so I checked him out and it's just really a simple web page that just says
hello talkers.
This is version 1 of my application the dependencies file.
All that does is if it's not already installed it will install TPD.
And then the start service script simply just starts HTP day and the stop server just stops.
TPD.
So these are all the files that we need to build our deployment.
And the app spec Jamo is the most important one.
And at the moment these files are just installed on my local machine but we need to get them into an
S-3 pocket in order for code to deploy to access them.
So we're going to come back to the console to configure our S3 packet.
So I'm going to go into services and find S-3 under storage concreate buckets and I'm going to call
my pocket CD buckets Tasche Fe click on next next next and create bucket.
So now we're ready to bundle up our application files create our application Inco deploy and then upload
our application code Pando into this S3 bucket and we have a few different commands that we're going
to run from the command line in order to do this.
So I'm just going to come back to my terminal and the first command we're going to run is going to create
the application within code deploy and it's going to name the application.
My web app and don't worry these commands are going to be included in the resources section of the course.
So you'll just be able to copy and paste them into your terminal and then once that's done the second
command that we need to run it just pushes the application fall into our S3 bucket and you're going
to need to go in and add the correct bucket name for your for the bucket you just created.
So I need to change that name
and then hit enter.
So that has created all application within code deploy and it's also pushed the application zip file
into all three buckets.
And of course the zip file it just contains all apps aspect to YAML or indexed to HDMI.
And all scripts directory as well.
So what's going you can just down that web app does it from the resources section of the course.
So let's go back now to Arkansas.
IMO have a look in S-3 bucket and just make sure that has been copied across correctly.
So if we go into a bucket that we should see web app does it and it's just been copied over that just
a second ago.
So now we're ready to deploy this application using code deploy.
So let's come back to services and come down to code deploy and it's under developed tools.
So just click on code deploy and the application we've just created using that command should already
appear in your code to deploy dashboards So there is.
So we're just going to click on the app and now we're going to define a deployment group and this is
going to define the host or the group of hosts but we're going to be deploying our code too.
So just click on Create deployment group and we need to give it a name.
I'm just going to call it my digi and we need to select a service role.
Which code deploy is going to use to access our target instances and it's just going to be the see service
role that we created at the beginning of the lab.
So just select that one then for deployment type there's two choices so we have that in place and the
blue screen and of course the in place is when each instance is briefly taken offline during the deployment.
So that means the instance is not available during the time of the deployment.
And then we have the blue green and this is one way you spin up new instances and you deploy to those
new instances and then once your new instances are healthy you can then terminate your original instances
as soon as you are ready.
But because we only have one host is it Poitou and it's the very first time we're deploying this application.
We can just go ahead and use the in place upgrade.
It doesn't make sense to use blue green in this case.
Then for Environment configuration.
So you can select any combination of either auto scanning groups easy to instances or on premises instances
to run this deployment on.
And in this case we're going to be using 82 instances and then it's asking us to define which instances
we want to deploy to using the instance tags.
So if you remember we created our tag attached to our instance and the tag was called app name and the
valley was my web app.
So moving down to deployment settings we can choose to either deploy to all of our instances at once
we can do one at a time we can do half at a time because the first time we're deploying an application
it makes sense to use all at once.
But if you're in a production environment and you only want to deploy to half of your instances at a
time you have the opportunity to select that using this dropdown list.
So we're just going to stick to all at once if you're using a load balance.
You can use the load balancer to manage the incoming traffic and manage the load across New.
In the original deployment we don't have a load balance.
So I'm going to de-select that and then click on Create a deployment group so that deployment group
created.
And then finally the last step in the process is to just go ahead and click Create deployment.
So our deployment group is selected.
It knows the name of our application.
It's going to easy two systems.
It's going to be an in place deployment.
The revision is stored in Amazon S3.
And if we click on this search box it should select all web Aptos zip file located in the three bucket.
So we're moving down you have some settings around Roback configuration and how you want code deployed
to behave.
If some part of the deployment files.
So for example if you try to run a deployment but then you find a file on the target instance has the
same name as the file in your application.
What are you going to do.
Are you going to file or are you going to overwrite or are you going to try to retain both.
So you can select your settings as you wish there.
And there's also a rollback configuration as well.
So you can override the default rollback settings so what happens when a deployment files.
What happens when certain cloud watch alarm thresholds are met as well.
So you can choose to disable rollbacks or you can it enable rollbacks.
So I'm just going to keep to the defaults for all of those and then go ahead and create deployment.
So now our planet is in progress.
And you should see the status indicator here.
And sometimes it does take a few minutes.
But there we go.
That has succeeded.
So hopefully that's worked for you and you have the same succeeded message as well.
And we can actually check our deployment check what's actually been provisioned for us if we go back
into services.
Easy to just grab the public IP for instance.
I put a new tab in our browser and hopefully you should see the same web page.
So it's basically installed the ICC P web server.
The index to ICM has been copied over onto our easy easy to instance and it's been installed involved
up Dab-Dab HMO.
An easy to instance is now serving this Web site and that has all been deployed using code diploidy.
So that is the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.