Hello Clockers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is code pipelined 1 0 1 and it's a really
quick summary lecture and it's just going to go through the theory of code pipeline.
So let's get started.
So what is code pipeline.
Well it's a fully managed continuous integration and continuous delivery service and it can orchestrate
the build test and even the deployment of your application every single time there is a change to your
code all based on a user defined software release process.
Now traditional manual approaches to code delivery can be slow and prone to human error whereas an automated
process like code pipeline allows developers to frequently release new features and bug fixes in a fast
reliable and consistent way.
So let's take a look at a really simple release process workflow
C-code pipelined allows you to model your release process as a pipeline made up of different tasks such
as the simple workflow represented in this diagram.
So in this workflow the code gets updated then the next stage is for the code to be built.
Then a set of automated tests would be run.
And finally once the tests have successfully been run the code can be deployed so the age of these different
stages of the work flow.
You define exactly what happens.
And this can all be modeled using the code pipeline interface all the Seelye and Co pipeline can also
integrate with code commit which is a source code repository within AWOS also code build which is the
code building service in WS as well as code deploy which is the code deployment service
and it can deploy to Lamda plus elastic beanstalk use cloud formation the plastic container service
as well as integrating with third party tools like get hub and Jenkin's And when you configure code
pipeline within the IWM console it's automatically configured so that every code change pushed into
your code repository.
If it's S-3 or code commit that will cause code pipelined to automatically trigger the work flow and
begin the set of actions defined for each stage of your pipeline and the pipeline will automatically
stop.
If one of these stages fails.
For example if one of your automated unit test files the entire pipeline will stop and any changes will
be rolled back.
And this means that any software issues are caught really early before the code gets deployed into your
environment.
So the issue is a core stage where they're still really easy to fix.
So here is an example of a work flow within AWOS code pipeline.
We have our user on the left hand side updating her source code which is located in an S-3 bucket's
every time she updates the source code in the bucket.
This triggers an alert in cloud watch which in turn triggers code pipelined to begin the work flow.
So in this example code pipeline is using code deploy to fetch the updated source code and then deploy
it to the instances on the right hand side and code deploy can actually deploy to on premise instances
in your own data center.
Easy.
And also lambda
So let's take a look at some of our code pipeline exam tips.
Firstly it's a continuous integration and continuous delivery service and this means it automates your
end to end software release process all based on your own user defined workflow.
It can be configured to automatically trigger your pipeline as soon as it changes detected in your source
code repository.
So whether that's S3 or code commit and also integrates with other services from AWOS like code build
code deploy code commit as well as third party and custom plugins
so that they end this lecture later on in this part of the course.
We do have a code pipelined lab.
So if you got time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank ye.