Hello packers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be a code pipeline lab and this
lab is actually going to be in three different stages.
So first of all we're going to use cloud formation to create an easy to instance.
We're going to upload version 1 of our application into an S3 Buckets and then we're going to deploy
our application to our easy to instance using code deploy.
Then in the next stage we're going to build a code pipeline and manually trigger code deploy it to update
our application to version 2 and then finally we are going to configure an automated pipeline which
is going to be triggered when we add a new version of our code to the S3 bucket.
So that's automatically going to trigger a cloud watch event which is going to trigger code pipeline
to redeploy the code to our easy to instance using code deploy.
So without further ado let's get started.
Now the first thing I want to show you is that there are a load of resources provided for this lecture.
So firstly we have a text file which contains all of the cloud formation commands.
So these are the commands that we're going to use to create or easy to instance.
And there is also this code revisions zip file and when you unzip it it's going to create three different
directories.
And that's going to be for three different versions of the web application that we're going to install.
So if I go into the first directory we've got our aspect of Yammer which you should be familiar with
already.
If you've already done code deploy lab we have an index to HMO which is the web page for our web application.
We have a scripts directory which contains three different scripts.
So there's an install dependency script.
So code deploy is going to go in and install H2 TPD.
Then we have a script to start H2 DPD and to stop it as well.
And these are all contained in this my web app dot Zip.
And that folder structure is reflected in each of these three different directories.
So when you download the zip file and it creates these directories for you you don't need to unzip my
web app does it because that's what we're going to be uploading into code deploy.
So just keep that folder structure exactly as you see it on my screen.
The first thing we're going to do is we're going to come to our cloud formation commands and we're going
to create our instance using cloud formation and I've provided the cloud formation template view to
use.
And it's in the resources section of the course and all it does is launch an easy to instance with the
code deploy agent already installed as well as the identity access management permissions and the security
groups you're going to need as well.
So it's a really quick way of setting up our instance so that we can just get on with the fun part of
the lab which is configuring code deploy and code pipeline and don't worry if you haven't used cloud
formation before we have a lab coming up later on in the course where we're going to be going through
it in a lot more detail.
So for now the first thing that you need to do is download the cloud formation template and I'm just
going to show you the template now just to show you exactly what it's doing.
So basically it creates your easy to instance and it allows you to tag your instance so that you can
easily identify it later on when we come to use the code deploy it also Associates an existing SSA each
key pad name as well and it sets up a security group which will allow you to log onto the easy to instance
once it has been launched.
And if we scroll down here to the mapping section you'll see that this template is going to allow you
to launch instances in one of these four regions.
So you have a choice of either U.S. East 1 U.S. West to EU West one or AP southeast too.
So for this particular lab you can only work in one of these four regions.
So pick the region that you want to work in and just make sure that everything that you do within this
lab is done in the same region that you select.
Now in order to use this cloud formation template we're going to need to store it in an S3 bucket because
cloud formation always sources its templates from S3.
So I'm going to return it to the console come to services and click on S3 and I'm going to create a
new bucket and I'm going to call it C F templates hyphen fe check the region is where I want to be working
so it's I'm working in EU Ireland and hit create.
So there's a bucket so just click on the bucket hit upload and we're going to add our cloud formation
template into this bucket.
So hit ad files select the template and hit open and upload.
So once we've done that we need to run the cloud formation command.
So I'm going to come back to my commands and here is the command that we need to run but there's just
a couple of things that you're going to need to change on your side.
So first of all we need to provide the template you are all.
And this is going to be the you are all of the file that we've just uploaded to S3 so you'll need to
change the region to the correct region and you'll also need to specify the correct bucket name as well.
And then the second thing that you're going to need to change is this key pair value.
And this is going to be the name of a key player located in the region that you're working.
So I've added the key pen name of my key player in Ireland.
And if you haven't got a key pair created you can simply go into easy to make sure you're in the correct
region.
So I'm in Ireland click on key pairs you can see I've got two key pairs there but if I didn't have any
I could just go in and create one.
Make sure you download it to your local machine and remember to set the permissions so that only you
can read it.
And before you can run any of these commands you do need to make sure that you have run a W as configure
on your local machine and in the previous lab in the code deploy lab.
If you've already done that lab you will have already configured your NWS come online interface.
And if you remember we used the credentials of an identity access management user called CDO user.
And if you haven't done that lab then definitely do go back and do it before attempting this one.
And I just have a couple of really cool commands that you can run right now to verify your setup.
So here I am in the terminal and the first thing I'm going to run is a W as I am get hyphen user and
I love this command.
It just tells you which user you have used to configure your AWP command line with.
So in my case mine is set up with CDO user.
And if you're just on the previous lab you should be as well.
And then the second come out I'm going to run is a W.S. configure list and this is going to tell you
how you set up your command line and the main thing I'm interested in here is what region I am configured
to be using.
So I'm configured to use EU W1 but if you're not in the region that you want to be in then all you need
to do is just run NWS configure and you can just go in and change the values and you can change your
default region there to match the one that you want to be working in.
So my command line is set up using the credentials of this CDO user.
And in order for that user to use cloud formation to launch 82 instances and also create security groups
we're going to need to add some additional permissions for our user.
So I'm gonna show you how to do that right now.
So if you come back to the W S console and I'm just going to come down to identity access management
go to users I'm gonna find my user and looking at this user they already have S3 full access and I also
have code deploy full access but they're going to need some additional permissions.
So in order to do that I'm going to create a new policy so come to policies create policy select Jason.
And I've already prepared the Jason code for this policy and you'll find it in the resources section
of the course.
So here is our code for our new policy.
So it's going to allow access to cloud formation identity access management and easy to as well.
And this is going to give our user permission to create or easy to instances.
So I'm just going to copy that.
Come back to the console paste that in the Jason editor click review and I'm gonna give it a name.
I'm just gonna call it C F access and then click on create policy.
So that is our policy created and we just need to go back and attach it to our user.
So come back to see user ads permissions attach existing policies directly and we're going to filter
out policies on customer managed and then just search for the EFF.
And there is ICF access policy.
So then click on review and add permissions.
So now we are good to go to use cloud formation to create our instance.
So once you've done that you can just copy that command and you'll notice here these backslash is these
just give you a line continuation just to make the command a lot easier to read if you're working on
Windows you're going to need to use this character here to denote the line continuation.
So just substitute these backlashes for don't know what these characters called it looks like a little
hat but you get it by entering shift and 6 at the same time.
So I'm just going to copy that command post it into my terminal window and hit enter and because cloud
formation has got quite a few things to configure it can take a few minutes to complete but I'm just
going to show you another command which will allow you to check the status of the cloud formation command.
So just come back to our commands file and it's this one is just going to verify the status of your
cloud formation command.
So at the moment we can see that it's in progress.
So I'm just going to give it a few minutes to complete and then I'm gonna come back and check again.
So while that is working I'm going to come back to the console and create my S3 bucket so come back
to services go into S3 hit create bucket and I'm going to call my bucket C.P. bucket dash fe I'm going
to make sure that it's in the region of Ireland because everything in this lab it needs to be in the
same region if it's not in the same region it's not going to work so hit next.
And we need to configure versioning on this bucket because ultimately we want code pipeline to notice
when a new version of our source code appears in the bucket and then we can accept all the rest of the
defaults.
So next.
Next and create bucket.
So that's a bucket created to go into the bucket and we're going to upload version one of our application
so click upload add files and you'll need to navigate to version one of our application.
So it's this folder and grab the file called my web app dot zip and it must be the zip file it can't
be the individual files so click on open and upload and I'm not going to go back to the terminal window
and see if cloud formations stack has completed.
So I'm just gonna hit up arrow to repeat our previous command and hit enter and hopefully it should
say create complete.
If that has been successful.
So the next thing I'm going to do is I'm going to try and look into that instance to make sure that
the code deploy agent has been installed successfully.
So I'm going to come back into my NWS console go to services to make sure I'm in the right region Ireland
click on running instances select my instance and copy our public IP address from down here I'm then
going to change directory to the directory where my private key is safe.
Mine's in downloads and then I'm gonna run SS H minus I.
And then the name of my key pair and then AC to dash user at.
And then I'm gonna paste the IP address of my easy to instance top.
Yes.
And then we are our easy to instance just.
I'm just gonna hit clear.
And then there's one come on that we just need to run on here to check that the code deploy agent has
been correctly installed.
So just copy that and paste and we can see that the code deploy agent has been installed and it is running.
So the next thing we need to do is configure code deploy to deploy our application using the code that
we just uploaded to the S3 bucket so come back to the console and we need to go to services and come
down to develop tools and hit code deploy.
And the easiest way to do it is just just go to get started.
Make sure you are in the same region that you've been working with the whole time so I'm in Ireland.
Click on Create application.
So I'm just going to call it my web app select the compute platform that's going to be easy to and click
Create application.
So the next thing we need to do is create our deployment group.
And this is going to define the instance where we're going to run our deployment.
So I'm just going to click on Create deployment group.
I'm going to call it my DG.
And if you've already done my code deploy lab you will already have an appropriate service role that
you can use.
So just click on CDE service role.
That's the one that we created in the previous lab for deployment type.
It's only one instance.
So we're just gonna use an in-place deployment for environment configuration is just going to be easy
to instances.
And this is where we need to define which easy two instances are going to be part of this deployment
group.
So we need to find the tag that was attached to our easy to instance.
So I'm just going to go up to services and open that in a new tab come back to easy to find my instance.
Go to the tags and it has a tag which is called name and the name is code.
Deploy demo spelt like that.
I'm just going to copy that.
Come back to my code deploy console and the tag is going to be name and the value that is found it for
me.
It might find it for you or you might need to paste it in but it should be code deploy it demo then
scroll down.
We're not going to be using a load balancer.
So uncheck that and then create deployment group.
So that is our deployment group created.
So the next thing we need to do is click on Create deployment select your deployment group that you
just created under revision.
You're going to need to provide the S3 location where we uploaded the web app zip.
So it's going to be S3.
Then the name of your bucket and then the name of the file which is my wife zip and click Create deployments.
So that might take a few minutes to complete.
So it's going to go in uninstall 80 TPD and copy across our index or HDMI.
So none of that has succeeded and we can test it by going back to our easy to console grabbing the public
IP of our instance.
I'm going to open a new browser tab and just paste that into the browser.
And there we are.
That's Virgin One of our application installed using code deploy.
So far so good.
So the next thing we need to do is configure the code pipeline.
So first of all we're going to use code pipeline to manually deploy a new version of our application.
So the first thing I'm going to do is update the code in my S3 Buckets with the next version.
So come back to the console go to services S3.
Go to our bucket.
Now we can't delete this old version because we have version control enabled on our bucket.
So I'm just gonna go ahead and upload the next version of our code.
So go to upload ad files and I'm going to go into my virgin to directory and grab all zip file.
So it's our version to directory my web app dot zip click open and upload.
And if we hit the show button next to versions it will show or two different versions of the file.
So now I'm gonna go back to my code deploy tab and you'll find a code pipeline under developer tools.
And it's on the left hand side underneath.
Code deploy so we can just go straight into code pipeline from here and I'm going to click on Getting
Started click on Create pipeline give it a name.
I'm just gonna call it my pipeline and underneath surface roll you can either have code pipeline create
a new service roll in your account which will give it access to everything that it needs to do you can
use an existing service role if you already have one but I'm just going to stick to the default and
let it create a new service role for us.
So keep to the rest of the defaults and hit next.
And we now need to provide a source provider.
So this is where our application source code is located and all is going to be in S3 we select the bucket
where we've stored our code and we also need to provide the name of the file under detection options.
So the recommended option is so allow our cloud watch events to automatically start your pipeline when
a change occurs to the source code contained in our S3 bucket.
So I'm just gonna keep that to the default pit next under built provider.
You can actually integrate code pipeline with a W S code build and Jenkins as well if you're actually
building code as part of the pipeline.
But in this example we're not doing that so I'm just going to click Skip build stage and then for deployment
provider this is going to be code deploy.
Make sure our region is the correct region.
The name of our application is my web app the deployment group is my DG hit next reviewed the settings
and if you're happy with those settings create line and there's our pipeline and it does take a few
minutes to complete.
So I'm just going to pause the video now and come back when that is complete so that is complete and
the deployment has succeeded.
And I did actually end up having to retry the command.
I think what happened was it just took a little bit longer to create the service role and then the command
ended up failing.
So they do give you a retry button if that does happen.
Just be aware in case you do see it fail the very first time you run this.
So we've manually triggered our deployment using code pipeline.
So let's go back to our Web page and refresh and see if we've got version two of our application.
So I'm just gonna hit reload and there is version 2 which we have deployed manually using code pipeline.
So now we get to do the fun bit.
So we're going to upload the final version of our web applications S3.
And if it's all working properly then code pipeline should automatically run a new deployment and it
will deploy the new version to our instance without us having to manually trigger the build.
So I'm going to come back to my S3 console and I'm gonna upload the next version of the application.
Click on ADD files and then you'll need to navigate to our version 3 directory and grab the my web app
top zip from that directory click open and upload and then straightaway we need to come back to code
pipeline and you can see straightaway it's detected that there has been a change in our S3 bucket.
So it's kicked off a new pipeline and it's triggered code deployed to begin the new deployment.
So that has succeeded and we can go ahead and test that.
If we go back to our browser window with the application hit refresh and there we are.
That's version 3 of our application We've uploaded our new version of the source code and that has triggered
the automatic deployment using code pipeline.
So that is everything that I wanted to show you about code pipeline and if you want to go in and delete
everything you can go into edit and delete.
And then also remember to go into cloud formation and delete your cloud formation stack as well so that
you don't get charged unnecessarily.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.