I Clockers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about advanced code deploy specifically
the app spec file.
So let's get started.
The app spec file is used to define the parameters which will be used for a code deploy deployment and
the file structure depends on whether you're going to be deploying to Lamda or to easy to all on premises
systems.
So for the lambda deployments the app spec file can be written in either YAML or Jason and it contains
three different fields.
And the first field is version.
And it is reserved for future use.
And currently the only allowed value is 0.0 then there's resources and resources really refers to the
name and the properties of the lambda function that you're about to deploy.
And lastly we have hooks and hooks are used to specify the lambda functions to run at set specific points
in the deployment process and they use to validate the deployment.
So for example to run validation tests that you might want to run before allowing any traffic to be
sent to your newly deployed Lamda instances.
So let's have a look at an example of a lambda spec Jamo.
So our first field is the version 0 0 as the only supported parameter.
The next one all resources.
So remember that's the name and the properties of your lambda function.
So firstly we have our name my lambda function tight just identifies it as a lambda function and properties
and there are four fields currently supported.
And these are mandatory.
So you must have your name written had an alias feel Amzah function and also the current version that
you're running and the target version that you want to shift to.
And finally we have hooks which specify the functions that you want to run at a specific points in your
deployment.
So for lambda we have two different hooks available before allow traffic and off to allow traffic.
And let's just have a look at those in a bit more detail.
So before allow traffic is used to specify tasks or functions that you want to run before your traffic
is routed to your newly deployed lambda function.
So for example after deploying your lams function you're going to want to run some tests to validate
that the function has been deployed correctly and is behaving correctly and you want to do this before
you actually allow any live traffic to be routed to the function.
We then have off to allow traffic and this is used to specify the tasks or functions that you want to
run after traffic has been routed to your newly deployed lambda functions.
So for example you might want to test that the function is correctly accepting traffic is behaving as
expected and it's performing as you expect.
Now if AC to an on premise is systems the spec for looks slightly different it still has the version
and it once again that's reserved for future use.
Currently the only value supported is 0.0.
And it also has an operating system.
So this is where you defined whether you're using Windows or Linux etc. the files Prometa is used to
define the location of any application files which need to be copied.
And where they should be copied to.
So we provide a source and destination folder of any files that we want to copy across and similar to
the lambda version of the file.
We also have hooks and once again these are lifecycle event hooks that allow you to specify scripts
this time that need to be run at set points in the deployment cycle.
So for example if part of your deployment process is to unzip application code prior to the deployment
you can specify that as one of your lifecycle hooks and you can also run functional tests on your newly
deployed application.
And deregister unregister instances with load balance.
So there's quite a lot of things that you can specify within this Hooke's section of the app spec file
and for AC to an on premises deployments the app spec file must be placed within the root directory
of the revision.
And this means the directory containing all your application source code.
And if you don't do this the deployment will fail.
So a typical set up looks like for example a folder called my web app and then within that folder your
app specter Jamo file and then in this example we have three different directories one called scripts
containing any scripts you want to run one called config containing any configuration files that you
want to copy across and one called source and that would contain the source code for your application.
And if you've already done the code deploy or the code pipeline leps you would have already seen a directory
set up very similar to this.
So let's have a look at an example aspect to it YAML file for an easy to instance.
So we have our version number 0 0 0.
Then we have the operating system.
And in this case it's going to be Linux the files section and this is the section which defines any
files that you want to copy across.
And in this example within the conflict directory We want to copy across conflict OTTI XTi and we're
going to copy that to a folder called slushed webapps slash config on our destination host.
We also have another directory called sose.
And in this example we going to copy everything in that source directory into the destination web apps
slash my app and the Hook section.
In this example it simply defines a couple of different scripts that we're going to run before the installation.
And then another script that we can run off to the installation.
So before the installation we can run these two scripts which are going to unzip our resource bundle
and data bundle.
And then after the application has been installed we're going to run this script to test to ensure the
application has been successfully installed continuing in the books section of the file.
Once the application has started we want to run a set of functional tests and those again allocated
in no scripts directory.
And we have a timeout that of 36000 seconds or one hour and then the loss of this section we want to
validate the service and we have a monitoring script again located in the scripts directory.
And also with a timeout of one hour and all of these scripts are going to run as the code deploy user.
So that would be the identity access management user that you need to set up with all the correct permissions
you need in order to run code deploy.
So the Hook section for the spec file is really important to understand.
And once again this specifies the scripts that you want to run at specific points within your deployment
lifecycle and they do run in a very specific order.
So let's take a look at that order.
Now so imagine that you have a set of 82 instances sitting behind a load balancer and you want to update
them using code deploy.
Well the first thing that you need to do is really deregister your instances from the load balancer
because you don't want to continue to send traffic and send requests to those instances when you're
trying to update them.
So the spec file supports hooks which will enable you to do that.
And so logically those would be the first activities that you want to do right at the beginning of the
deployment and the hooks associated with registering from your light balancer or before block traffic
which allows you to specify Tulse you want to run on instances before they get deregistered from the
load balancer then block traffic which actually registers your instances from the load balancer then
off to block traffic.
So any tasks you want to run on your instance is after they have been de-registered.
Now the next sequence of events covers all the steps that you would normally need to do when upgrading
any application.
So first of all you'd want to stop your application so gracefully stop the application in preparation
for deploying the new revision.
Download bundle.
And this simply tells the code deploy agent to copy the application revision files into a temporary
location.
Before install.
Details any Prete installation scripts for example backing up a current version decrypting any files.
Any activities that you need to get done before you begin the installation the install stage is where
the code deploy agent copies the application revision files from that temporary location to that correct
final location to install hook details.
Any post installation scripts that you need to run.
So if for example configuration tasks any changing in file permissions adding executable access to a
file etc application start restarts any services that was stopped during the application stop stage
and validate service.
So this details any tests that you want to run in order to validate your service.
Then moving on.
These three fine herx all relate to reregistering your instances.
Back with the load balance.
So we've got before allowed traffic which specifies any tasks that you want to run before you reregister
your instances with the load balancer allow traffic which is the activity of registering the instances
with the load balancer and off to allow traffic.
So any tasks you want to run on your instance is after they've been registered with the load balancer.
So that's quite a lot to remember but it is really important to try and remember the sequence of events
that happen during a code deploy deployments.
And I've tried to summarize them here in this graphic and in my mind.
I kind of see it as a three stage process really.
So right at the beginning as a set of tasks that we need to run in order to de-register all systems
from the light balancer.
So that's the before block traffic blocked traffic and off to block traffic.
Then the next stage we have all of the tasks that you need to do in order to upgrade your application
and then finally we need to do a set of tasks to reregister with all load balancer and just remember
the sequence of events always happens in the same order.
You can't change the order of course and often they refer to it as the run order of hooks.
So if you see any questions in the exam relating to the run order of Herc's in a code deployed deployment.
This is what they're talking about.
So let's take a look at some of our exam tips.
So the spec file defines all the promises needed for the deployment.
So for example the location of any application files any pre and post deployment validation tests run
for AC to an on premises systems the spec file must be written in YAML and it must be placed in the
root directory of your revision.
So the same folder containing your application code lambda however supports YAML or Jason for the spec
file and once again Schweitzer's remember a run order books in the code deployed deployment.
We have the before block traffic block traffic an after block traffic then the applications stop before
in so Instow off to install application start validate service and then finally those steps to reregister
with your life balance before allow traffic allow traffic and of to allow traffic.
So that's the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not please feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.