Hello bloggers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be a doctor and code build lab.
So what is Doctor.
Well Doc is an open source technology and it allows you to create applications based on either Linux
or Windows containers and a container is a lightweight standalone executable software package which
includes everything that the software needs to run.
So for example that includes the code any runtime environment libraries environment settings etc. and
AWB provides the elastic container service as a fully managed clustered platform which allows you to
run your Docker images in the cloud.
But what does that have to do with code build.
Well we can use code build as a fully managed build service and this will run a set of commands that
you define.
So for example it will compile your code for you run tests and produce artifacts which are ready to
deploy.
And in this lab we're going to start off by creating our own docker container manually using the command
line and we're then going to learn how to use code build to build our Docker image as well.
So we're going to take source code from code commit code build is going to retrieve that source code
and it's going to use the instructions within the source code to build out a Docker image.
So if you're ready let's get started.
And please join me in the console now.
Now the first thing that we're going to do is we're going to install Docker.
So if you go to this Web site it's docks dot Docker dot com forward slash install.
And the community addition is fine.
It's open source.
That's going to give you everything you need.
And there's different instructions depending on which operating system you're running locally.
So I'm working from a Mac.
So there's an image that I need to download from the docker store.
So I just click on Download get Docker and it's going to download this Docker dot TMG file and it's
really simple to install.
Once you've downloaded that file you just click on the image and follow the instructions.
But of course if you're running Windows there are separate instructions for Microsoft Windows.
Once again you just download the executable install file from the docker store and then just run it
and follow the instructions.
So once you've done that you can just come back to the terminal window and I'm just going to type Docker
minus minus version and that will confirm that you've got Docker installed and you can also run Docker
run Hello dash world.
And that will also confirmed that Docker is correctly installed on your machine.
So now we're going to create our very first Docker image and I've already got a file created.
And it's called Docker file.
So let's just have a look at that file now and this file is gonna be in the resources section of the
court so you can just download it and it's a really very simple file.
All it does is instruct Docker that we're using Ubuntu image.
It runs this app to get update minus Y command which is similar to a young update for you to it then
installs Apache.
It creates a really simple Web page which is going to be followed up laptop index to HMO.
It then configure Apache so it sets a few variables it exposes port 80 and finally it starts Apache.
So that is all talk of file and that's all the information needed in order to create our Docker image.
Now we need somewhere to store our source code.
So I'm going to store this source code in code commit.
So let's go back to the console.
Go to services and find code commit under the developer tools then create repository and we need to
give our repository a name.
And I'm just going to call it my source code repo hit create.
And in order to connect to a code commit repository you're going to need to have installed get 1 7 9
or later on your local machine.
And they actually give you this link to go ahead and install it.
But if you've already done all code commit lab already you will have downloaded get as part of that
lab.
So you should already have it configured on your local machine.
But if you don't you can just view this get downloads page and get that installed on your local machine
and then the second prerequisite is that you need to set up the AWB CLIA credential helper.
So you will also need to have configured your NWS CLIA on your local machine using the A W W configure
command and you'll need to have done that with the user credentials for a user who has access to interact
with code commit.
And once again if you've already done code commit lab you will already have a user who has access to
interact with code commit.
But I'm just going to go to the identity access management console now and show you how to create that
user.
So let's click on services identity access management users add user and I'm just gonna call my user
C.C. user I'm gonna give them programmatic access click next.
And I want to attach an existing policy directly and I want to add code commit and I'm just going to
give them code commit full access click on Next and create user.
So it's created this access key and secret access key.
So I'm just going to copy that access key.
Now go to my terminal window and I'm gonna run a W S configure and when asked me for that access key
I'm just going to hit control V.
Now it's asking for the Secret Access Key copy that secret access key and paste it.
Now it's asking for the default region name.
So it's got you central one.
And that's the correct region for me because I'm working in Frankfurt.
So I'm just going to hit enter and default output format is Jason so I'm just going to keep that as
the default.
So hit Enter so let's come back to our console window back to services code commit click on our repository.
Now in order to connect to the repository there are a couple of commands that we need to run and if
we scroll down it actually gives you a link to the documentation and there's a couple of different links
but for the purposes of this lab the commands are going to be exactly the same.
So you can click on this link and it will take you through some of the configuration steps that we've
already done.
And then it's this set up the credential helper and connecting and cloning the repository.
Those are the commands that we're going to run now.
So you'll find the first two commands are here and then further down the page in step four it gives
you this get clone command.
But don't worry because I've added these commands to a text file so you can just cut and paste them
from the text file.
So here are the commands.
So the first one is the conflict command to configure the credential helper.
So I'm just going to copy that and paste that into my terminal window.
Come back to my text file and copy the second command and paste that into my terminal window and then
with the third command.
This is the get clone command and you're going to need to replace this repository.
You or I with your own you or L from your repository.
And I'm just gonna show you how to find that.
So if you scroll to the top of your repo you'll find this button this clone you are all button just
hit that select clone 18 yes.
And that will copy the you are right to your clipboard.
So just replace my you arrive with your own.
And then you should be good to go to copy that command and paste it into your terminal window.
And we have cloned an empty repository because there's no files in there yet.
So just hit Alice and you should have a new directory called my source code repo.
So now we're going to put our files into that repository.
So I'm just going to copy my Docker file into my source code repo and I'm also going to copy the build
spec so Yammer into the source code repo as well and I'm going to change directory into the source code
repo.
My files are in there.
I'm just going to run the get commands to add these files into our code commit repository.
So I'm just going to type get at DOT and get commit minus M adding Docker file and build spec dot Yemen
and then finally run get push.
Okay.
So that has successfully pushed those two files into all source code repository.
And if we go back to the console we should be able to see those files in the repository now and we can
see our two files in there now and you can see the doctor file and the contents of the file if you click
on the file name.
Now the next thing we're gonna do is we're going to create an easy s plastic container service cluster
and that's where we're going to be able to run our Docker image.
So come up to services under compute.
You'll find a plastic container service.
So click on a plastic container service and click on clusters create cluster and you have a choice of
different cluster templates and they'll build all this out for you using cloud formation and we want
to use the AC to Linux and networking template.
So the resources that is going to create for you are the cluster VPC various subnets and an auto scanning
group with a Linux EMI.
So just make sure that is selected and hit next.
And the first thing we need to do is give our cluster a name.
So I'm just going to call it my cluster for provisioning instance types.
I'm just going to stick with on demand and for the size of instance you can select the one that you
want to use.
This is just going to be running a really small web page.
So I'm just going to select the T2 micro so that instance type will be on within your free tier number
of instances.
I'm going to keep it as one.
However if you were in production or even if you were in non production even if you were using this
for test or development you'd want to have more than one instance of course.
So if one instance went down you wouldn't lose your service.
However for the sake of this demo we can just keep that as one and this is the ABI that's going to create
for you and we can just keep to the default storage of 22 gig and all of the other defaults we can just
keep those as they are.
So it's going to create a brand new VPC with this side a range and a couple of subnets as well.
And it's going to create the basic security group with public access to port 80.
So we just keep all of those defaults and hit create and is just running this cloud formation stack
for you doing all the heavy lifting for you is going to build out your ECM cluster and it does just
take a few minutes.
So I'm just going to pause the video here and come back when that's completed.
So now the cluster has been created.
And if you click on clusters it will show you your cluster so click on the name of your cluster.
So just click on my cluster easy s instances and you can see down here where we have a container instance
and also the underlying easy to instance as well.
And we can click on that instance and it will take us to easy to dashboard and you can see it's the
T2 micro.
This is the public IP address and it's just a basic T2 microbe that it's created for you.
Now the next thing we need to do is create a repository to hold our Docker images.
So let's come back to elastic container service click on repositories and click on Create repository.
So the first thing that we need to do is give it a name.
And I'm going to call it my Docker repo and click Create repository.
So that's created a repository.
And if you select the repository name and then click on this view push commands button it will show
you a set of commands that you need to use in order to push Docker images into your repository and these
commands are really important to remember because they can come up in the exam.
There's a different set of commands whether you are running Windows or Mac or Linux.
And it actually builds out the commands for you.
So you all you have to do is cut and paste them.
So this first command is just going to authenticate your Docker cloud to your registry.
So I'm just going to copy that head over to my terminal window and paste and straightaway I'm seeing
this access denied exception when calling the get authorization token and this is because my user account
a user.
So the user that we created earlier is not authorized to perform this ECI command get authorization
token.
So in order to fix this I'm just going to head over to identity access management in the console had
to I am going to find my user and permissions attach existing policy and I'm just going to search for
registry.
So this is going to pull up all of the predefined policies relating to easy to contain a registry and
I'm going to go in and add the easy to container registry power user to my user hit next and add permissions
then I'm going to come back to my terminal window and try that command again hit up arrow
and I actually had to run that come on twice.
So you may find that you have to run the command a couple of times before it actually picks it up.
Then I'm gonna grab my next command which is to build our Docker image so it's going to build the image
using the docker file which is located in our docket repo.
I'm just gonna copy that command and paste.
So that has successfully built the image we are then going to tag the image so that we can easily identify
it.
So just copy that command and it's going to target as the latest image.
So just copy that command and hit enter and then the final command is to push this image into our newly
created repository.
So just copy that command and paste and that will push the image into our repository.
Okay so that has successfully pushed all Docker image into our E S registry.
So let's go back to the registry now and see if we can find it in the
and there is on new image.
So now the image has been created and we can see it in our AC Our repository.
So this means we're ready to now launch or docker container.
So in order to do that we come over to clusters and task definitions create new task definition and
the launch type is going to be easy too.
So just make sure that is selected and click on Next we need to enter a name
and we don't need to select a roll.
Keep to the defaults for networking for task size.
It's only going to be running a small web page.
So I'm just gonna put 512 for both CPSU and ram.
And so this task size allows you to specify a fixed size for your task.
So the next thing we need to do is add a container.
So the container name I'm going to call it my container and for the image.
This is going to be the brand new Docker image that we've added to our our repository.
So we need to find the registry.
You are well.
So in order to find that we can come back to the console go to ACARS and repositories select your repository
and just take the euro from here.
For the memory limits we can just keep that as the default.
And then this bit here is important.
The port mappings.
So this actually maps your host and container ports so it will map if we want to access port 80 we need
to make sure that we've mapped the host port 80 with the container port 80.
So I'm just going to add 80 and 80 for the health check information can just leave that blank.
Same for environment and network settings.
We can just keep all of this as the defaults and then click add and then create.
Now in order to launch our task we need to create a service so click on actions create service and it's
already found our task definition.
So we need to select the launch type of easy to it's found our cluster name as well so it's for service
name.
I'm just going to call it my service number of tasks it's going to be one we can keep the task placement
as a balance spread across ages but you can there's a few different options you can have you can have
one task per host for example or custom but we don't need to change that and it's actually beyond the
scope of this course and the exam so we don't need to really delve into that in any more detail.
I'm going to click on Next for load balancing.
We're just going to keep it as the default.
Which is none.
So we've only got one container and one hosts so we're not we don't need to load ballots across those
so click on Next service auto scaling.
Again we're just going to keep that as the default so click on Next and create service.
So now our service has been created and you can just click on my service to view it and you'll see that
the task definition is running you can click on the task and see the details of it click on events and
you'll see.
You should see that your service has reached a steady state.
So in order to actually view your service we need to head back to ar e s console go to clusters click
on your cluster find easy two instances and head over to your easy to instance and grab your public
IP.
Paste your IP and there is our Web page so that is a web page running in a docker container on our ECM
cluster.
So we now have our Docker image running in ECF and we've built our using those Docker commands.
But what if we want to automate all of those docker build commands and have a W W do it all for us.
Well we can actually do that using code build and that is the next part of this lab.
So let's see if we can get code build to build our image for us.