OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture lecture we're going to look at E.C too.
And this is an introduction so we're calling in to one or one and we're going to introduce what E.S.
to actually is.
So what is it.
Well it's elastic Compute Cloud.
That's what it stands for so it's ECAC and it's abbreviated to e c.
And it's basically a web service that provides resizable compute capacity in the cloud.
So it's just virtual machines in the cloud and it reduces the time required to obtain and news servers
to minutes rather than in the old days when you needed a new survey you had to put in a purchase order
you had to go and rack and stack and all the cabling and it could take anywhere from 10 days to a month
to get your servers.
When we came along it was a massive game changer because suddenly you could provision virtual machines
in the cloud within minutes and it completely changed the industry.
And Amazon basically led that.
So that's what E.C 2 is.
You can also scale your capacity both up and down you know changing your instance types and will go
through that in a lab and you also are able to scale the capacity out so you can add more and more instances
behind let's say an elastic load balance.
So easy two has changed the economics of cloud computing and it basically allows you to pay for the
capacity that you actually use rather than previously when you wanted to go out and buy physical servers.
You would actually go and the provisions you'd look for a server that you'd be able to grow into.
So you would maybe get a server that had a lot more C-p capacity and more capacity than you actually
need it right now.
But of course you are going to buy the server over a five year term.
You had to plan for five years you know in advance and so people would spend a lot of capital upfront
and they wouldn't necessarily get the good return on investment.
So easy two has changed that now so that you can literally just pay for the capacity as you use as you
use it and depending on the different billing methods you pay you know by the hour even by the second.
So it has been a complete game changer in cloud economics.
So now that we know what to is and we understand how the economics of cloud computing has changed let's
look at the different pricing options.
So we'll start with on demand and on demand allows you to pay a fixed rate by the hour or even by the
second with no commitment and depending on whether it's an hourly rate or a per second rate depends
on the two instances.
So it depends if it's Linux or Windows Linux instances.
By the second whereas Windows instances currently by the hour I would expect that to change very very
soon though.
Moving on we've got reserved instances and this is where you make a reservation with Amazon you basically
entering into a contract and these contracts can be one or three years in length.
But because you are entering in a contract and you may be paying a certain amount up front all of it
up front.
It gives you a significant discount on the hourly charge for an instance and we'll look at different
use cases for that in a couple of slides.
We then have spot.
And this basically enables you to bid a price and you can choose whatever price that you want for instance
capacity.
And then it gives you a huge amount of savings provided you can actually get that price and the spot
price moves around all the time and again we'll have a look at some different use cases for it.
Basically think of it like the stock market is where you want to go and purchase a share let's say the
shares at $100 and you're and they want to purchase that when it drops down to $90.
You basically do a bid when that unit price drops to 90.
You then buy that share and then you could force a sale once it goes over 100 or something like that
so it just moves around all the time.
And then finally we have dedicated hosts and these physical to serve as that dedicated for your use
and they can help you reduce costs by allowing you to use your existing server balance software licenses
so can be really good for things like VM or for Oracle.
Maybe some sequel servers depending on the you know different licenses you can actually bring your licenses
over to AWOS and use dedicated hosts.
So let's look at different use cases for the four different pricing models to start with on demand.
And this is basically perfect for users that want the low cost and flexibility of AC too without any
upfront payments or long term commitments.
It's also good for applications with short term or spiky or unpredictable workloads that cannot be interrupted
and applications that are being developed or tested on Amazon to for the first time and basically throughout
the rest of this course we're going to be using on demand instance on demand is great for learning because
you can go in provision an instance go into what it is you want to do.
Maybe it's moving some abs volumes around or something which will come to an a bit.
And then once you're done you can go in and terminate it and you're only paying either by the second
or by the hour depending on the instance.
Moving on to reserved instances this is you know useful for applications.
Steady State or very predictable usage.
So these might be your you know your web web servers for example.
So applications that require a reserved capacity and users can make upfront payments to reduce the total
computing costs even further.
And the way it works essentially is that if you pay for it all up front and you you know do a three
year contract that's when you're going to get your maximum discount whereas if you only pay a little
bit upfront and go for a one year contract you're not going to get as big a discount as if you paid
at all upfront for three years.
And the standard reserved instances can be basically be up to 75 percent off the on demand costs so
again that would be if you are paying everything upfront for three years and then you get these things
called convertible reserved instances and these basically have the capability to change the attributes
of the reserved instances so long as the exchange results in the creation of reserved instances of equal
or greater value.
So you can basically change your reservations and look through the different instance types but essentially
it means you could go from a very intensive instance over to a very memory intensive instance.
You see you're not locked into a particular instance type.
And again we're going to cover the instance type is coming up in a few slides and then you'd finally
have shed jeweled reserved instances and these are available to launch within a specific time window
that you reserve and this option allows you to match your capacity reservation to predictable reoccurring
Shatru that only requires a fraction of a day week or a month.
So maybe you have a month and so the end of every month every Friday at the end of the month than you
need you know some reserved instances for that.
But after that Friday is over you can scale it back rather than using on demand.
You can now actually use shed or reserved instances as well.
And then we have spot instances or spot instances or applications that have flexible start and end times
and applications that are only feasible at very low compute prices.
So a lot of genomics companies you know people who are in the sort of genome field or big pharmaceutical
companies or you know chemical companies use this you know spot instances to do huge amounts of computing
and they will do this at like 4:00 a.m. on a Sunday morning and that will save them an awful lot of
money compared to using the same compute capacity you know from a nine to five during the week.
So there's there's heaps of white papers and studies on that.
If you go over to Amazon's Web site and have a look when you go into a spot pricing you can read examples
of exactly that.
So spot instances great for users with an urgent need for large amounts of additional computing capacity.
Moving on to dedicated hosts to this is useful for regulatory requirements that may not support multitenant
virtualization.
So you might still you know your country might say that.
You know if you work in the health field for example you're not allowed to use multitenant virtualization
because you could be potentially exposing your data to somebody else.
You know they do ring fence that now but a lot of let you know you know what it's like the legislation
never keeps up with technology.
It's great for licensing which does not support multi-tenancy or cloud deployments and it can be purchased
on demand so you pay at an hourly rate and it can be purchased as a reservation up to 70 percent off
the on demand price so that is dedicated Herse.
So I've looked at all the different pricing models let's move on to the instance type So here are all
the different instance types.
I know what you're thinking how am I going to memorize this.
Well you don't actually need to memorize it going into any of the associate exams where it does come
become useful is at the professional level and to be honest actually insists ops administrator associate
you do need to know the different instance types because they will try and trick you and they'll create
instance types that don't exist.
So it's quickly run through the different instance type.
So we've got an F1 which is a field programmable gate array and the use case for this is genomic research
of financial analytics real time video processing big data.
Moving on we've got i3 which is high speed storage so that's for things like non-sequel databases data
warehousing et cetera.
Get out G-3 is such a graphic intensive.
This is video encoding 3D application streaming et cetera.
We've got our hated ones which is high throughput so so be things like you that reduce workloads distributed
file systems such as DFS map our FS et cetera.
So anything that you're using you know huge workloads and you need high disk throughput for them got
Tator to take two is what we're going to be using for the rest of this course.
So this is the lowest cost general purpose computing that's available.
So this will be like web servers and small database get out date which is dense storage so these are
things like file servers data warehousing had do with got our files which is memory optimized memory
intensive applications.
The way I remember that is Ram full with.
Then got M5 which is general purpose so this is for things like application servers save files which
compute optimized.
So C.P. intensive apps and database servers pay 3s.
These graphics or general purpose GP use.
So we use these for things like machine learning or even bitcoin mining if you wanted to do that.
And then we've got our X ones which a memory optimized and these are like huge amounts of neurons so
these are things like SAP HANA Apache SPARC cetera.
Now with the families you know when you're watching this one might become an EF 2.
That just means it's a new generation or i3 might change to I4 Yaniv actually really going to be tested
on that.
What's important to remember is the two letters not the numbers going into your exam.
So that leads to the question how are we going to remember all those letters.
I'll tell you how we did it in 2078.
So we have this duck.
It's sort of like a Scrooge McDuck and I call him Dr. mkt gift picks so he's clearly a doctor because
he's got glasses he's Scottish because he's wearing a kilt.
So you got the muck and then what he likes to do is walk around and hand out pictures of Scotland so
he's gifting Paix.
So Doctor gift picks.
Now this worked really really well.
Lots of people remembered it.
And you know if you type it into google lots of blogs come up about it and then Amazon released a new
instance type to reinvent in 2017.
And that was the high density instance type.
So it's broken up my mnemonic.
So we've got another one for 28:18 So I'm a huge fan of fight club it's one of my favorite movies of
all time.
So we've got Edward Norton from Fight Club we've got Doc Dimmick gift pick software.
Right.
And this is how I remembered them now which is fight.
Dr. McPeek so right.
Dr. MC pace that was the best I could come up with.
So I want you just to imagine Edward Norton fighting a Scottish duck who likes to hand out pictures
of his homeland.
If you remember a fight a doctor picks you'll be able to remember every single instance type and that
can be incredibly useful.
Certainly if you go into the solutions architect professional exam as well as the soap's administrator
or associate as well as any of the specialty exams because you know what a valid instance types and
whatnot and Amazon you know in some of the exam questions we'll just make up letters and you're like
well that's not a valid instance type so that answer is clearly wrong.
So fight Dr. McK pics so just remember Edward non-fighting a Scottish duck and it should work for you
and hopefully Amazon won't release any more instance types this year.
But who knows if they do all have to come up with another crazy pneumonic.
So we've talked about Acey to you now.
What it is basically a virtual machine in the cloud.
We've also explored that there are different instance types so you have ones REM ones VCP new ones for
graphics et cetera.
Last thing you need to know is what is abs.
And if you think of two as of virtual server in the cloud ABS is a virtual disk.
That's all it is.
Abs stents far less stick block storage and allows you to create storage volumes and attach them to
two instances and once attached you create a false system on top of these volumes and you can run a
database so you can install applications or you could store files on that cetera and you just use it
any way that you would use a block device.
So as volume's placed in a specific availabilities zones where that automatically replicated to protect
you from the failure of a single component.
So an ABS volume doesn't exist on just one physical disk.
It's actually spread across an availability zone so individual disk actually dies you abs volume will
be fine.
So I want you to think of it as just a disk in the cloud that you attached to your AC to instances.
Now the the ABS volume that is attached to your easy to incidents where Windows or Linux is installed
is called the root device volume.
And then you can have other volumes on top of it.
So if you think about Windows.
Windows is typically installed on your C drive but then you can have additional disks.
You can have a D drive an E drive an F drive etc. so you can do that in the cloud as well.
So abs volumes come in different types.
The most popular is general purpose SSD.
This is sometimes referred to as GP 2 and that basically balances you know its general purpose.
It balances both price and performance and you get a ratio of three IOPS per gig with up to 10000 IOPS
and the ability to burst up to 3000 IOPS for extended periods of time for volumes at three thousand
three hundred thirty four gigabytes and above.
So if you see an exam question and it's saying that you know you've got less than less than 10000 IOPS
you probably want GP to because it gives you the you know performance as well as best price.
We then have provisioned the IOPS and this is again another SSD drive.
This is a very high performance applications so things like you know intensive applications relational
databases no Sakal databases basically anything way you need extreme performance and you basically would
use this if you need more than 10000 IOPS.
So if you have an exam question and it's talking about you've got a really big no sequel database and
it's going to use a lot of IOPS you probably want to go for provisions.
IOPS SSD as opposed to using general purpose and you can provision up to 20000 IOPS per volume.
Moving on.
So we've cut it off.
SS day SSD drives before we before we had SS desribes we had magnetic storage volumes so these are the
magnetic disks.
So we've got throughput optimized this is known as estée one.
This is used for big data data warehouses load processing et cetera.
It's important to realize that throughput optimize hard disk drives cannot be a boot volume so they
have to be additional volume so that example that I use befool the root device volume to boot volume.
So if you go to a Windows server it's typically going to be on your C drive.
This throughput optimized disk could not be Yosi drive it could only be your day drive.
In other words it has to be an additional volume comp b a boot volume.
We didn't have cold hard disk drive.
This is known as SE1.
This is the lowest cost storage infrequently access workloads so typical use case might be a file server
and it cannot be a boot volume either.
So you can boot from normal magnetic stand.
So this is the lowest cost per gigabyte of all abs volume types that is bootable.
So this is the only magnetic volleyer that is bootable.
This is legacy.
You know it previous generation Amazon don't even include it in their comparison tables anymore.
But you can definitely still use it.
And magnetic volumes are basically ideal for workloads where data is accessed infrequently or what using
applications where the lowest storage cost is important.
So you might want to use your test and dev environments and use it on magnetic while you get it all
set up and then move over to SSD.
You know general purpose SSD or provision to IOPS.
So you are at the end of this lecture.
Hopefully you have learnt a lot.
So what of my exam tips.
Well let's start with the four different pricing models.
Remember what on demand is it allows you to pay a fixed rate by the hour or by the second with no commitment.
You then have reserved capacity.
This allows you to get a huge discount on the hourly charge but you have to enter a contract of one
or three years.
The longer the contract and the more you pay upfront the greater the discount so to get your maximum
discount you need a three year contract.
You need to pay for it all up front and then have spot the spot price moves around all the time.
So let's say I bid at $100 and suddenly the spot price goes up you know to let's say the spot price
comes down to 90.
OK so previsions my service and then let's say the spot price goes all the way back up to 150.
Those instances would then be terminated.
So you're only going to pay for what you bid on and a hundred dollars is just an arbitrary number.
Sure it's charged by the unit by the hour.
Etc. but I'm just using it as an example.
Then have dedicated hosts so we've got physical to servers with dedicated hosts.
And these are really useful for things like regulatory requirements perhaps you can't go in under the
legislation you can't do multitenant in a virtualization.
Or it could be existing software licenses or VM ware or a code or something like that where you're being
restricted and you have to use dedicated hosts and just coming back the instance if a spot instance
is terminated.
So lets say you bid 100 bucks and it goes and you see you know it's provisioned and suddenly it goes
up to 110.
So when that happens your instances are going to be terminated but you're not going to be charged for
a partial hour of usage.
So you basically don't need to pay for that hour.
In the hour in which it is terminated.
However if you terminate the instances yourselves then you be charged for the complete hour in which
the instance has run so bear that in mind that's a very popular exam question.
And so you go into the exam remembering out you monica so fight.
Dr. Meck pics.
So here we go.
Edward Norton fighting our doc likes to hand out pictures of his homeland in Scotland that will allow
you to remember every single instance types and that can be extremely valuable.
Certainly if you go on to any professional specialty exams and then also remember our different you
know abs volume types that we just cut it off so we had General Purpose SSD.
We have provision to IOPS SSD.
So typically you're looking at anything over 10000 IOPS you want to go to provision to IOPS anything
below you want to use purposelessness day and then and magnetic we have the throughput optimize hard
disk drive.
So this is where you've got large amounts of throughput so things like big data with then got our code
hard disk drive.
So this is where we don't have a lot of demand.
And we just want to have the very low cost.
So we would use cold hard disk drive and you know use case for that would be follow servers and then
we have magnetic and magnetic is the only one that we can actually use as a root device volume or a
bootable volume.
And this is previous generation so bear that in mind that is it for this electric guys we've learned
an awful lot.
Let's go ahead and get started with AC too.
We're going to go in and get our hands dirty.
We're going to go provision our first easy to instance.
So if you've got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.