OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture this lecture we're going to look at backups multi-phase
Z and read replicas with us.
Now it doesn't matter what exam that you're doing whether it's solutions architect associate developer
associate or city administrator associate having a clear understanding of the difference between Moltke
a Z and read replicas will pick you up at least three or four points on your exam in some exams or pick
you up more really depends on the exams you need to have a clear understanding of what that is going
into the exam.
Before we get onto that though let's just start with some backup.
So there's two types of backups for AWOS these automated backups and there's database snapshots now
automated backups will allow you to recover your database to any point in time within a retention period
and the retention period can be between 1 and 35 days.
Automated backups will basically take a full daily snapshot and will also store transaction logs throughout
the day.
And then when you recover AWOS will first choose the most recent daily backup so choose the snapshot
that's most recent and then apply those transaction logs that are relevant to that day.
And that's how we do a restore with automated backups.
And this basically allows you to do a point in time recovery down to a second within the retention period
windows the retention period window is between 1 and 35 days.
Now a cool thing about automated backups is they're enabled by default the backup data is stored on
S3 and you're going to get free storage space equal to the size of your database.
So let's say you have an instance of 10 gigs you going to get 10 gigs worth of storage that's free on
S-3 and backout so taken within a defined window during the backup window storage IO may be suspended
while your data is being backed up and you may experience some elevated latency and you saw in the last
lecture where we basically defined all backup window we left everything as the default values.
But when you go and create your database you can define the backup window.
You can also edit it for your existing databases.
Moving on to snapshot snapshots is simply what you think they are they're basically a snapshot of the
database so just like a Polaroid takes snapshots.
When we do a database snapshot it's going to take a snapshot of the database.
It's always done manually so that always use initiated and they will always be stored even after you
delete the original D.S. instance if you delete the original instance your automated backups will also
be deleted with it as well.
Whereas D-B snapshots basically sit as a standalone file and you can delete the LDS instance without
having to worry about those snapshots being deleted as well.
So moving on to restoring backups whenever you restore either an automatic backup or a manual snapshot
the restored version of the database will be a new D.S. instance within DNS and points when we do a
restore.
Let's say that this is our DNS end point for the original database we've got original doti hyphen Westhoff
and one to D.S.O. Emerson 8.
So when we do a restore it's going to have a new DNS endpoint so they basically completely separate
databases with completely separate DNS and points.
Now before we have a look at how we go and do this I just want to talk a little bit about encryption
encryption at rest is supported for my sequel Oracle esque sequel serve a purpose gress.
Q Oh Maria D.B and terasa everything now supports encryption at rest.
It's done using the AWOS Kamis or key management service.
We cover a mess in a awful lot of detail in the certified security specialty course.
So if you do want to go on and get a security certified which is really valuable right now definitely
check out that course.
So once your instance is encrypted the data stored at rest in the underlying storage is encrypted as
all of its automated it backups read replicas and Snapshot.
So once you encrypt a database anything you do with that database in terms of making a copy of that
data is going to be encrypted as well.
And at the present time encrypting an existing db instance is not supported.
To use ADSI encryption for an existing database you must first create a snapshot and then make a copy
of that snapshot and encrypt the copy.
And we'll look at how to do that.
And General backups right now.
OK so here I am in the AWOS console in the audio section which sits under databases and what I want
to do is I want to go over to that a database instance that we launched in the very last lecture.
So go to a cloud and click in here in here we've got our instance actions.
So I in here I can create a replica arrayed replica we can take a snapshot restore to a point in time
migrate latest snapshot et cetera et cetera.
I'm gonna explain what read replicas and multi Zee's can also modify the database.
If you click home modify in here you'll be able to scroll all the way down and change the backup retention
period so he can go from seven days all the way down to 35 days.
We can also go and change the backup window it is in UTC time so you can say I wanted to start at 2
a.m. or 216 a.m. UTC and have a window for half an hour.
So you can change that all in there.
So let's go and actually let's go click on snapshots in here we can see our automated snapshots.
So these are snapshots.
This was the first snap that was taken when I first created this database.
If I wanted to go and do a point in time I'd go back over to my instances click in here and I can go
to instant actions and I can go to restore to a point in time.
Essentially what that's going to do if I click in here and go to custom I'll be able to do the date
the time and it's all in UTC and I can go right down to the very second.
As I said what it's going to do is first restore that snapshot and then it's going to ply with transaction
logs to that snapshot and then bring it back to a point in time down to the second so it is really really
cool.
Let's have a look at one last thing before we move on to regret because this is multi ese.
If I click on instances and have a click in here I can go instance actions and I can take a snapshot.
Let's go and take a manual snapshot or call it a cloud your manual snap and go ahead and hit take snapshot.
That is now creating my snapshot.
I'm going to pause the video and just wait for this to come up.
OK.
So I'm just going to refresh the page hopefully that has finished being created now.
And there we go it is now available by click in here.
What I can do is I can go to actions and I can go to a copy snapshot when I go to copy snapshot.
I can actually scroll down you can see I can enable encryption.
So that's how we would turn encryption on and basically create a copy and then from that copy that encrypted
copy of the snapshot I would then deploy a new instance.
So that's important to remember your exam.
Now let's learn the differences between multi a.z and read replicas.
So what is multi-phase Z.
Well here we've got an elastic load balance so with some E.S. two instances behind it and they're all
pointing at an LDS database this database is in USA aist one a.
So they see two instances if they make any rights to us one.
So any changes to that database.
What will happen is those changes will be synchronously replicated to us.
East one be and U.S. East one bay will be an exact copy of uss aist one a.
Now it's important to understand this is for disaster recovery only.
So in the event that we lose U.S. East one way it will automatically fail over to us at least one B.
So how does that work.
If you remember in the last lecture we had the connect up HP file and we had this thing called the hostname
and the hostname simply contained our DNS and points a cloud Garou dot see one x w s a 1 K L x t Daut
EU hyphen West hyphen one dot Amazon Dot com.
So that is simply a DNS address that DNS address is actually public and publicly available.
And what will happen is that if you lose your primary database Amazon will detect that and it will update
the DNS address to point to the IP address of your Z copy of your database.
So it's really important to understand that you never deal with IP addresses when dealing with D.S.
you always just use this DNS endpoint and this day NSA endpoint will fail over automatically to your
you know your secondary Malte a Z database azy allows you to have an exact copy of your production database
and another availability zone and AWOS handled a replication for you.
So when your production database is written to this right will automatically be synchronized to the
stand by database.
And so in the event of database maintenance or D-B instance failure or an availability zone failure
Amazon will automatically follow it to the standby so that the database operations can resume quickly
without administrative intervention so files are automatically your downtime is going to be very very
limited probably only a minute or so.
So it's really really critical to remember the multi Asie is for disaster recovery only.
It is not primarily used for improving performance.
If you want performance improvement you're going to need read replicas and it's really critical to understand
that any of the associate exams and disaster recovery you using multi azy if you want performance improvements
you are going to use read replicas.
Before we go on what a read replica is just remember that multi azy databases are available for a sequel
server.
Oracle my Sekou post Q Oh Maria D-B.
You could argue or Rore as well.
Aurora is actually built into the entire database design.
I haven't put it here as a bullet point but it definitely has Rohrer by it is spread across multiple
availability zones.
You don't need to turn on multiagency for Aurora but the other instances you can definitely turn it
on.
So moving on to read replicas what is a read replica.
Well let's take our lastic Lloyd Belon so without E.C two instances as we had in the last few slides.
And they're basically doing a right to an audio database.
Now when you set up a raid replica these rights are going to be pushed out to other copies of the database
and you can have five read replicas per production database by default.
And so why would you do this.
Well let's say that 90 percent of your traffic is read traffic and you've got all these easy two instances
90 percent of what they're doing is just doing raids from the database.
This could be like a very popular Wordpress blog or popular Joomla site or something like that.
To be honest it depends on the workload.
But a lot of applications a lot of it is read you know people are reading more than they contributing
on the Internet generally speaking.
So you know you could scale this out by instead of having those two instances going to the production
database the primary database they read from the read replicas or you could have it so that one reads
from the production and the other to read from read replicas whatever.
This is a way of scaling out your database so that you take the load off the primary database and you
spread that load across one or more read replicas.
You can also have read replicas of Raid replicas you will get some replication latency if you do do
that but you could have a read replica in a nother availability zone but you could have a RAID replica
in a other availability zone or you could have a read replica in a completely different region.
It's completely up to you.
So read replicas allow you to have a read only copy of your production database.
This is achieved using asynchronous replication for the primary haughtiest instance to the read replica
and you use read replicas primarily for very real heavy database workloads so use RAID replicas to scale
out.
Now I did say earlier the bolt a Z is synchronous whereas read replicas are asynchronous.
You don't actually need to worry about that at any of the associate level questions when you start doing
the professional level questions so try and confuse you and try and test whether you know which is synchronism
which is asynchronous but you won't have that at the associate level.
Xrayed replica databases currently available for my sake will serve a purpose.
Q Oh Maria de Bay and Aurora so it's available for fall.
They are currently not available for sale.
Will serve at all for our école.
So rate replicas they use for scaling not for disaster recovery if you need to scale out to use read
replicas if you need disaster recovery you want multi azy you must have automatic backups turned on
in order to deploy a raid replica.
You can have up to five raid replica copies of any database and you can have a read replicas overread
replicas but watch out for latency E-Trade replica is going to have its own DNS endpoint.
You can have read replicas that have multi enabled.
This is a very new feature that was released in January 2018 so you can have a RAID replica in a completely
different availabilities zone or completely different region that has multi Asie turned on and you can
create raid replicas of multi Asie source databases.
So in other words if you have multi Asie turned on to your you know to your instance you can still go
in and create read replicas doesn't break it at all and then read replicas can be promoted to become
their own databases.
Now this will break the replication but this can be very very useful if you need a copy of your database
maybe you've got too many read replicas you're not using enough of them and you want to do some you
know some other sort of work on your databases and you don't want to do this on your production database.
You can promote your read replica to become its own database.
This will break the replication however.
And then finally you can have a read replica in another region it doesn't have to be tied down to the
region in which all production database is in let's go have a look at how we can enable multi a.z and
read replicas in the console case.
Here I am back in the AWOS console if I go down to databases and click on relational database service.
So open up the splash screen.
I'm going to go and grab the instance that we were using previously.
A cloud are going to go in and click on it so it's selected and then go to instance actions straightaway
I can click on Create raid replica You can specify the destination here so it can be completely different
region.
You can specify the subnet groups the availability zones whether it's publicly accessible or not.
You can actually enable encryption on your read replicas even if the primary database is not encrypted.
You can select your instance classes here you can make Read replica multi a Z and then you just basically
can go and set up monitoring you're going to have an enhanced monitoring or you can have logs exported
to cloud watch logs from your raid replicas as well.
Can Go ahead and hate can so I don't really need to create a raid replica the other way you can turn
on multi Asie as you just go over the instance actions go to modify and you can actually just specify
that you want multi Asie deployment.
And the way this would typically be done is let's say this is my test dev database and my site is almost
ready to go live but I didn't want to have multi azy on test and Dev on what I can do is go into my
database and make up multi azy and thus promoting it to become a production database.
So that is read replicated and multiagency in a nutshell.
You do definitely have to have a clear understanding of the two going into any associate exam and pretty
much any professional exam you will always get marks for knowing the difference between the two.
I remember raid replicas of scaling for performance enhancement whereas multi azy is for disaster recovery.
You can go back now and delete this D.S. instance going to be using it anymore so just go to your instance
actions and go ahead and hit delete.
I'm not going to create a final snapshot.
You can if you want.
If you aren't going to create a final snapshot it says it.
I acknowledge that upon instant solution all my automatic backups including system snapshots some point
in time recovery will no longer be available so it will delete all the automatic backups when you delete
your yes instance.
So that is it for this lecture guys if you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.