OK Hillary pluggers and welcome to this lecture this is actually going to look at Elastic cash one or
one or less the case.
Some people renounce it that I'm going to pronounce it the American way.
Going forward to cash so less to cash is a web service that makes it easy to deploy operate and scale
and in memory cache in the cloud.
And basically it's going to improve your performance of your web applications by allowing you to retrieve
information from fast managed in-memory caches instead of relying entirely on slower disk based databases.
So basically it's a way of caching your most frequently used queries from your database instead of putting
it in your database we put it in elastic cache and that takes a bit and it takes a lot of load off your
production databases so you know always constantly querying the top 10 for sale items for example where
you're not constantly querying you know maybe it's a new Wordpress blog or something like that you can
actually cashola that information using elastic cache.
So it can be used to significantly improve latency for many read heavy application workloads.
This could be things like social networking gaming media sharing in Q&amp;A portholes in particular will
compute intensive work loads such as a recommendation engine and caching improves the applications performance
by storing critical pieces of data in memory for low latency access cache information may include the
results of intensive you know database queries all the results of computationally intensive calculations.
So the more you cache the less load you put on your database the more you for your database up and you
basically make your applications far more effective.
If you've ever used Magento Magento is a slacker online web store or online software for building stores
and it is an extremely memory intensive.
So we use Meng Passhe a lot.
When I worked at Rackspace Magento take a huge load off the database.
So we've got different types of elastic cash we've got to we've got memcached day memcached day is a
widely adopted memory object caching system.
LS The cache protocol compliant with memcached so using popular tools that use with your existing memcached
environments right now it's going to work seamlessly with the AWOS memcached deal less to cache service.
We then have read us and read us is a popular open source in memory key value store that supports data
structures sorted sets and lists and elastic cache supports master slave replication and Malte a Z which
can be used to achieve cross Bayly abilities and redundancy.
So if you need MOTY a z axis you want to use Radice.
If you're not concerned about redundancy then you want to use memcached.
And of course these a very popular scenario questions as to whether or not you should use memcached
or Redus.
So although both memcached and Radice appear similar on the surface in both caches they are actually
quite different in practice now because of the replication and persistent features of red as elastic
cache actually manages read us more like a relational database and read us elastic hash clusters are
managed as stateful entities which include failover very similar to how Amazon manages database Fail-Safe
with memcached.
It's designed as a pure caching solution with no persistence.
So less to cache manage is memcached nodes as a pool that can grow and shrink.
Very similar to an ATM isn't easy to auto scaling group.
And if you haven't come across auto scaling yet it's obviously you can start with two web servers and
then as you get to a certain load you Wadham it will automatically add a web server behind your load
balance so increase it to 3 increase it to 4 etc..
You do you go in and configure it.
So individual nodes with memcached are expendable and less the cache provides additional capabilities
here such as automatic node replacement and auto discovery.
So what are the use cases for memcached.
Is object casing your primary goal for example to offload your database.
If so then use memcached.
If you want something as simple as possible.
Then you want to use memcached.
If you are planning on running large Schneiders with multithreaded performance with utilization of multiple
costs or multiple OCP cause.
If so then use memcache.
And if you want the ability to scale your cache horizontally to scale out as you grow then go ahead
and use memcached day with Redus.
If you're looking for more advanced data types such as lists hashes and sets use Redus to sorting and
ranking data sets in memory hope you such as with the later boards.
If so use Redus really remember that going into the exam if you see a scenario we're talking about using
a lead creating a board and they ask you whether you should be using memcached auratus choose red this
is persistence of your store information important so do you actually value your data.
You want persistence then.
If so use rattus and you want to run in multiple zees with failover then you read us.
So basically if you want something as simple as possible go use memcached.
And if it's just literally taking a load off of your database use memcached.
If you've got Laborde information or you want multi availabilities zones or you know a persistence of
your entire data is really really important to you than you want to go and use read us.
So typically you're going to give a scenario question where a particular database will be under a whole
bunch of load or stress and you may be asked which service you should use to alleviate this.
The answers are always going to be less to cash particularly if your database is particularly read heavy
and not prone to frequent changing.
However they could throw in a scenario where redshift would be a better answer because if your database
is feeling stressed because management running online analytics processing transactions on it then you
probably want to use red S sorry red shift rather than less to cash.
So if you few If you think it's a data warehousing question go for a red shift.
If it's literally just about taking stress off your database because it's very very real heavy then
you want less to cash.
And then again going into the exam just remember you want to use memcached if object casing is your
primary goal.
You want to keep things as simply as possible as simple as possible and you want to scale your cash
horizontally.
You want to scale out that's when you use memcached D.
If you've got lists hashes and sets you want read us if you're doing leaderboards you want read us if
you want data assistance if you want more availability zones.
And if you need the pub sub capabilities needed then you want Retta.
But definitely if it's talks about leaderboards read us read us read us.
So that is it for this lecture guys.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.