OK hello cloggers and welcome to the very last lecture in this section of the course the true summary
lecture in here we're just going to summarize everything we've learnt in this section of the course.
Now if you have done our solutions architect associate course you will notice that the easy to section
of the developers so cost is quite a bit shorter and that's because the new developer you know associate
exam is actually really Servilius focused.
So they're really trying to get away from easy to so you don't need to know anywhere near as much about
E.S. too as you did when you were doing the solutions architect course.
And we will have a whole section on service coming up.
So let's go through my exam tips and we will start with the different types of revenue models for easy
to or pricing models for easy to see on demand.
This allows you to pay a fixed rate by the hour by the second with no commitment.
We've got reserved which provides you with the capacity reservation and you have basically one to three
year contracts if you pay the more you pay upfront and the longer the term the better right that you're
going to get.
So if you get three years upfront and you pay at all upfront you're going to get the best rate possible
then have this enables you to bid whatever price you want for an instance capacity providing even greater
savings if your applications have flexible start and end time.
So it moves around just like stock market.
And then we have dedicated a host of physical easy to servers that are actually dedicated for use the
use cases for this would either be to allow you to do things with licensing or it could be your regulatory
requirements.
Some governments don't want multitenant virtualization.
Remember that if a spot instance is terminated by Amazon easy to you're not going to be charged for
the partial hour of usage.
However if you terminate the instance yourself you'll be charged for the complete hour in which the
instance ran.
We then learned about our different easy to instance type.
So you Monnick that we are going to use to remember all the different types is fight Doctor picks.
So I want you to think of Edward Norton fighting a Scottish doc who likes to hand out pictures of Scotland's
and that way you will remember every single instance type going into this exam at the social level.
Typically you don't need to know all the instances but definitely when you go on to do the specialties
or if you go on to do the professional levels it is really useful and if you are going to work with
AWOS anyway is pretty useful to know the different E.C to instance types.
We then moved on and we looked at the different abs volume's so we had SSD so we had general purpose
SSD.
This is what we've been using throughout most of the costs that have provisioned the IOPS.
And this is for mission critical low latency workloads.
So basically anything over 10000 IOPS you want provisioned IOPS anything below.
You can go with a general purpose SSD.
We then had magnetics we had throughput optimized remember this comp be a boot volume.
And this is designed basically frequently accessed throughput intensive workloads.
We then had cold hard disk drives this could be designed for things like you know file servers et cetera.
Neither of those can be boot volumes.
And then we have magnetic this can be a boot volume it's previous generation and it still exists in
the console.
Moving onto elastic load balance as we learnt about the three different types of load balances.
So the application load balances network load balances and classic load balances.
If you do see the word elastic load balance Typically they will be talking about classic load balances.
We learnt that we get a five or four ERA on our classic load balances.
This means that Gateway's timed out.
Why is the gateway timed out was not because the AOB is broken.
Essentially it's timing out means there's something wrong with the application stack so it could be
a web applications it could be a database server something is not working in there and that gateway
is timing out.
So we need to go and troubleshoot your applications stack.
We also learn that if you need the IP for Address end user then you going to do this through the Axford
forehead up.
Moving on to route 53 We basically learned that this is Amazon's DNS service and allows you to map your
domain names to two instances or to load balances or two three buckets then looked at the command line.
So we learned about least privilege you always want to give your users the minimum amount of access
required.
You may not want to give your devs administrator access.
You may want to restrict it a little bit more.
It's entirely up to your organization.
We also learned that we should create groups say should assign users to groups and your users will automatically
inherit the permissions of the group the group permissions are signed using policy documents.
We learn about.
In terms of the command line interface that we have a secret access.
So we learn that you're only ever going to say this once.
If you don't say that you can delete the K and then just regenerate it.
And if you do do that you are going to need to run the AWOS configure again.
And we also learned that you shouldn't use just one access.
So don't share one access came across all your developers that's just stupid.
Create one secret access Kaon access key ID per developer.
That way if somebody leaves a company on bad terms you only need to delete that one key rather than
having to delete it across all of your developers across all of the stack.
So always create one key pad.
Her developers and remember that you can use the Selye on your PC so you can install this on Mac Linux
or Windows.
I actually use this you know to store my files in S3.
So go ahead if you haven't done that already.
I definitely suggest Googling.
You know depending on what OS you using and you'll be able to run the installer once it's installed
all you need to do is type AWOS configure and enter in your Access Key ID and secret access.
OK.
Moving on if you want to get away from access key and secret access keys you can use roles but of course
you would only use a role within your own AWOS environment you can't you know Graham's Horo to your
Mac or your PC or anything like that.
But they are definitely preferred from a security perspective if you have a scenario question where
people are saying should you use a row or should you use an access key idea or secret access key.
So long as we're talking about in the context of within your A.W. environment always choose roles and
roles controlled by policies you can change a policy on a role.
It's going to take immediate effect and you can attach and detach roles to running a C two instances
without having to stop or terminate these instances then learnt about encryption or root device volume's
Sweetland you can encrypt the root device volume which is simply the operating system that the volume
is stored on.
So the ABS you know volume that your operating system is stored on and you can do this using operating
system level encryption so things like windows bit lock up for example.
You can also encrypt the device volume by first taking a snapshot of that volume.
We then created a copy of that snap with encryption.
We then basically took that snap and created an Amazon machine image out of that snap and deployed it
and that basically encrypted the root device volume.
And you can also encrypt additional attach volumes just simply using the console.
The Seelye or the API.
We then went onto databases we learned about D.S. which is basically for online transaction processing.
We use D.S. for things or as has the following technologies Seiko server.
My sequel postscripts.
Q Well Oracle Aurora and Maria de Bay.
And then we have dynamo D-B which is Amazon's no secret service.
We have it redshift which is Amazon's sort of online analytics processing site data warehousing service
and then we have elastic cash which is out in memory cations engine and that consists of memcached D
and it also consists of read us in terms of Amazon.
We learnt that LDS instances can be multiple availability zones and that is only for disaster recovery.
Its not foolproof.
Improving performance for performance improvement you going to need read replicas read replicas are
used for scaling not video.
You must have automatic backups turned on in order to deploy a raid replica.
You can have up to five replicas copies of any database.
You can have RAID replicas of Raid replicas but you gotta watch out for latency Atri replica is going
to have its own DNS endpoint.
You can have a RAID replica now that has multiple availability zones and you can create replicas of
multi source databases.
Regrip like is can also be promoted to their own databases.
But this then breaks the replication and you can have a RAID replica in a second region for my sake.
And Maria de Bame moving on to a less to cache typically you're going to be given a scenario where databases
are under a lot of stress you know alert and you will be asked which service you should use to alleviate
this noise.
Always depends on the scenario.
You choose the last to cache if you databases particularly read heavy and not prone to frequent changing
but if that's not the case redshifts are a good answer.
If your database is getting stressed because management K-8 running online analytic processing transactions
on it and then it is really important to understand the difference.
Use cases between memcached and read us going into this exam.
You need to use memcached if object cation is a primary goal.
You want to keep things as simple as possible and you want to be able to scale out your you know your
cache horizontally.
You'd use rattus if you have much more advanced data types.
If you're doing things like sorting and ranking such as leaderboards definitely use read us if data
persistence and multiple availability zones is important to you then you want to use read us.
And if you need pub sub capabilities then you also want to use read us.
Well congratulations you've done really really well.
I hope you've learnt a lot.
So that is it for this section of the course in the next section we're going to learn all about three
going to hand over to Faye Ellis who will be teaching you that once you've cut it off S-3 you come back
to me and learn all about service and serious architecture so I hope you go ahead take a break make
Sophia coffee and we'll see in the next section of the course.
Thank you.