OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture this lecture we're going to start getting our hands dirty
with AC too.
The best way to learn AWOS is to go ahead and start using it.
So let's look into the AWOS cons..
OK so I've looked into the AWOS console.
Now I want you to first just take a moment to change all region and I would do the rest of this course
in the U.S. East in the Northern Virginia region.
And the reason for that is that's the main region where Amazon will release all their news services.
So if you see something that's quite cutting edge in this course and you can't find that new console
it could be because it's not available in your region.
So if you can just use us aist Northern Virginia.
So that's how you change a region.
Now what we want to do is we want to click up here and go to services and we can see compute and straight
on to compute is AC too.
So let's go ahead and click in there and what we're going to do in this lab is we're going to set up
a little web server.
So the first thing we need to do is you get this splash screen.
You can see that this is a brand new account by default.
I don't have anything we want to do is go ahead and launch our first instance.
So instances are created from Amazon machine images and you've got a whole bunch here that you know
you can choose.
So these are two different operating systems so you could have a amazon Linux or Linux Redhat scroll
down you could have windows et cetera.
Work for this course we're just going to use the Amazon Linux and wine as our default one.
Also note that you have the marketplace here and community and so you can actually go and buy a pre-built
you know virtual machines to do different things.
So let's go ahead and click on the Amazon Linux am I and then here this is where we do our instance
families.
This is where we can select whether we want to micro or if we want to use something that's optimized
for memory or something that's optimized for compute.
This is where Dr. mkt fight Dr. McK picks comes in.
So these are all your different instance types so we're going to use tape to my credit go ahead and
hit next configure instance in here.
This is where we say the number of instances you can have a purchasing option you could request a spot
instance you could go and enter in your price.
I'm not going to do that in here.
This is the network so we're going to deploy this into our default VTC.
We will cover all bases later on in the course but think of of APAC as just a virtual data center in
the cloud that's unique to you.
We can use the default BBC to use the default subnet.
We'll cover that off Also later on in the course and we want to auto assign a public IP address so when
this is first provisioned we want it to have a public IP address.
We're not going to assign any identity access management roles just yet.
We can do that later on on shutdown.
What do we want this instance to do.
Do we want it to stop or to terminate.
We just want it to stop enable terminations protection will stop us from accidentally deleting this
instance.
You definitely want to do that you know on a production service.
I'm not going to click on that now.
Monitoring all instances I'm monitored by default but you can have detailed monitoring detailed monitoring
allows you to monitor it monitors at every every minute as opposed to every five minutes.
I'm going to leave it as a default tendency we are going to run on a shared hardware instance and scroll
all the way down and in here we've got advance details so we can add in user data.
These are bootstrap scripts we're going to cover that offer later on in the course so basically we're
not making any changes here whatsoever.
We're going to leave everything as default.
We're going to go ahead and hit next to add our storage.
So here's our route.
Device volume or boot volume you can see that it's SSD general purpose.
You can also do provisions to IOPS and you can do the legacy magnetic.
I'm just going to leave it as SSD and we're not going to have an encrypted or anything.
You can go in here and add additional volumes if you want but we're not going to do that for this lecture
and we're going to go ahead and hit next to add our tags so our tags could just be something like name
and then the value will be my web.
So something like that.
So at any tag that you want.
So it's always you could have name you could have department you could have staff ID you know anything
that you want.
And then the value.
And then we're going to go ahead and configure our security groups.
So what is a security group will think of a security group as a virtual firewall.
So this is way you allow traffic in and out to your little instance.
So we're going to need to enable If this is going to be a web server.
People are going to be doing it over port 80 or are the TTP so going to have to enable port 80 in order
for this to work.
So we're going to create a new security group I would call this my web DMZ.
So you know that this is the security great for all your web service.
We're going to allow S-sh in from anywhere.
So S-sh is how we're going to connect to our easy to instance use SS hate for Linux of the windows use
Oddy pay it's just article to remotely administer your AC to instances.
So in here we can do this so you can do your IP address.
You could do anywhere.
I'm going to select anyway so this is the Sajda notations old old old old old old Ford slash.
And this is that's for IPB for this is for IP basics and this is basically just saying allow anyone
to be able to connect in using SS hige to this instance.
It's not really secure you should really lock it down to your IP address.
But this is just a test and Dev server anyway I'm going to go down and we're going to allow TZP access
as well.
And we're going to say we want DTP access from anywhere.
So people will be able to connect to this to instance on port 80 or port 22 on port 80.
They'll be viewing web traffic on port 22.
They'll be administering the server.
So let's go ahead and hit review and launch and then what we want to do is we just want to go ahead
and hit law and she will get this little sort of warning saying that you know the security group is
open to the world for S-sh it's not best practice but you know this is just a test and Dev server so
go ahead and hit launch.
Now if you've never done this before you are going to need public and private case.
So we are going to create a new key pair and this is how we connect inter AC to instance so this is
how we stop other random people just being able to connect in.
It is literally like setting up a lock on the server.
You've got your public key is the lock itself and your private key is the key that you use to open the
locks.
You can share a public case around with anyone but never share your private case soon as you share your
private KPP will be able to access this.
So we're going to call it my new key pair.
Something like that.
And go ahead and download it.
Make sure you save it somewhere safe.
And because if you lose this you won't be able to access your PC to instance if it.
You can say it's Dell.
Man I'm just going to close this and then we're going to go ahead and hit launch instance and that will
now launch our instance.
Let's go ahead and view this so it will take a little bit just says pending.
And what I'm going to pull is a video wait for this to go green and then we're going to connect into
this instance.
OK so that instance is now live.
So I will be able to connect to it.
So here's my public IP address.
If you just copy and paste that into your clipboard you'll be able to connect using that public IP address.
Now there's a couple of ways you can connect.
You can click click here and go connect.
And it says that you can use a standalone S-sh client which is what I'm going to use and I'll show you
how to do that in both Mac and in Windows.
Or you can use a Java S-sh client.
Now I am running this on crime and it's no longer a supported plug in.
So you can try and do it using Internet Explorer or Firefox or whatever but I'm going to use a standard
S-sh client.
So what I'm going to do now is I'm just going to load up terminals so if you are using Windows you can
skip the rest of this video.
Go to the very next video and I'll show you how to log in using Windows using potty.
But if you are a Mac user just follow along with me.
Ok so I'm in find and I've clicked on applications what you need to do is just scroll down to utilities
or open up utilities and you want to open up terminal.
Now my terminal is quite big.
You can go up here and go to show and you can go a new window using something like Herberts one of my
favorites.
You can use any settings that will just change the font and the colors and all of that.
So I'm just going to use my standard one and so straight away I'm in the Guri directory.
I need to go over to.
So CD downloads and that's where I downloaded my private key.
Now my private key was called My new key pair.
The first thing I need to do is to change the permissions on this so I need to make it quite locked
down to be able to connect to my PC to instance.
So what I would do is call type and say S.H. mod 400 my new key pent up pay.
And hit enter.
So that has just changed the permissions on the file.
And now all I need to do to log in is type S-sh AC to high end users.
That's my user name.
And then at.
And then the IP address and then minus I.
And what are we using.
We're using my new key pad.
PM And that will then use this keypad to try and connect them via S-sh via port 22 to see two instance
going to hit yes here tied.
Yes.
And it's added that private key to sorry it's added this computer to my list of known Herse.
And then what I need to do is I'm just going to clear the screen so you can see it a lot easier mean
elevate my privileges to route so I'm going to type sudo or su.
And so now I'm a super user you can see here it says route.
And so this means I have for admin access.
So we have a little Linux server in the cloud Let's go and make it a web service for the very first
want to do is just run a yum update minus.
Yes.
And this will just update the you know the operating system with all relevant packages.
It means it's got all the latest updates applied to it so that hopefully there will be no vulnerabilities
and that can take just a little bit of time but it's just cleaning up now it's done all the installations.
And once this is done what we need to do is we're going to go in and install Apache and Apache just
turns this little server into a web server and then what we'll do is we'll create a little web page
just says hello cloggers or something like that.
So that has now finished updating.
Let's clear the screen and to install Apache we just need to write yum install and then hate TTP day
and then we'll just do mine this wife of mine.
Yes.
So that has now installed and again I'm going to clear the screen so you can find what I'm doing much
easier.
So I've installed Apache.
The next thing we want to do is we want to start the Apache service so we say service hatred DVD start
and that has now started the service.
And then we just want to do one other thing.
So the service has started.
The one thing that we want to do is if this to instance read boots we want Apache to come back on automatically
so to do that we just type in check config and then hatred TDB day and then we say on and that will
just means that if we restart this to instance Apache will come on automatically so we can now type
in service HDDVD and then status that will show us if the TSBD service is running the Apache service.
It is now running.
And when we install that we've created a directory.
So if we go to CD.
Dub dub dub page Timo This is the root directory of our Web site.
We type in ls.
We can say that there's nothing there.
So let's go ahead and fix that one I'm going to do.
I'm going to write to Nannar index Daut hate TMLC and we're going to create a little web page.
So here's a little textedit built into our easy to instance I'm just going to quickly do some code so
tim will make this really simple so body then hate Schwann so head.
And then it's just going to say hello cloud jurors going to endow H-1 again and our body says like literally
the most simple piece of a team or you can do.
And we're going to end it here now and TMLC and then I'm just going to hit the control x.
They will ask us if we want to say I'm going to hit yes.
And then I'm going to hit enter.
And so now if I do.
LS We can see my little index don't hate him.
So next thing to do is I'm just going to clear the screen let's go over it all a web browser and see
this Web site.
OK.
So here I am and my web browser I just type in the IP address you can see straight away Hello cloud.
So we've created a little web server in the cloud we've created Web site where we can now connect to
that web site using our using that public IP address.
So what we now want to do is we're going to look at how we can register a domain name and how we can
point that domain name back to this to instance.
Now before we go on to registering a domain name we need to in the need to create a application load
balance or in order for all this to work.
So let's go in the next lecture and explore.
From a theoretical point of view what a what the different types of light balances are.
What's available to you.
And then once we've done that we'll go on and we'll register domain name and we'll point out my name
to our application load balance which will then point out to instance and then you will be able to visit
this Web site just by typing in a domain name.
So if you've got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.