OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture this lecture is actually for Windows users only.
And we're basically just going to teach you how to use potty and potty Cajun and you need to use potty
in order to S-sh into your easy to instance and you need potty and in order to convert you'll be M-file.
This is the key pedophile that's generated when you first create an instance and a crate is generated
in a dopy format but poddy doesn't support PE files.
They poddy needs that time PBK files.
So basically puttee Cajun turns p m files into PPK files.
So in order to do this you need to open up your browser.
OK so here we are in our browser.
I'm on Google and I'm just going to type in putty and there we go we've got the potty download page
and that's our top green and all.
Don't you case.
Just click on that and then basically you just want to save the party say and you want to save the putty
Gen X C to the top and the bottom link.
Once you've done that it will finish downloading.
You might just want to copy this across to your desktop just because you will be using this a lot throughout
the course.
So if I just minimized everything and refresh my desktop There we go we can save putty.
So potty is always the computer to computer icons.
This is what you're going to use when you're exercising and then PATTI-JANE is always the key generator.
So it's got a computer to key icon.
So the next thing we want to do is just go ahead to the AWOS management console we want to launch an
instance.
So we go in and launch an AC to instance and then use the Amazon Linux.
Am I going to delete everything else as default because I just want to show you how to connect into
this instance.
I'm just going to call this putty as my instance and then go ahead and hit next.
Going to add create a new security group I'm just going to leave it open to the world in moments launch
was at €1 might look like.
Launch was to.
But just leave S-sh open to the world.
It is a security risk.
You could lock it down to your IP address.
But again this is just for demo purposes only.
Go ahead and hit launch.
Now we want to create a new case to MICKOLUS My Katie.
Katie and we're going to download this KPN now you'll see here it says it's been downloaded as adult.
P M-file.
And in order for us to be able to use this with Cotty we need to convert it to a PPK file and that's
where Pati Cajun comes in.
So we minimize and go back to our desktop and we open up PATTI-JANE we will be able to do that first.
I'm just going to kick off this instance those two and then go ahead and hit launch.
OK so that is now launching.
So while that's going on again I'm going to go back into Puttock Cajun.
I'm just going to open it up now you might get this message saying protect your PC.
Just click more info and hit run anyway.
And so here we go with go potty.
So the first thing we need to do is go and load our case.
So go ahead and hit load.
Now this compares a lot of people straight away because they can't say they came.
That's because it's looking for a PPK file but we saved it as a P M-file.
So what we want to do is just hit all files down here and then open up my party.
PM And there we go says successfully imported it to use this case with potti you need to use the saved
private key command to save it and putties arm format.
So we're going to go ahead and do that.
It's saved private.
K this is asking about a pass phrase if you want to protect it.
What you can do is passphrases just basically a password so you need a password in order to open up
this case just an extra level of protection.
Most people you know for the purposes of this course you don't need to if you're going to do this in
production maybe you do want one it's going to go ahead and hit yes.
And then what we're going to do I'm just going to change this to all files I'm going to change.
Click on here so maintains the same file name but then instead of saving as adult p p p am I'm going
to save it as a dot OK.
Go ahead and hit size.
And that is literally it.
Now we go into our downloads directory we can see a p m file and we can see a PPK file.
So the next thing we need to do is open up party.
So it is puttee.
It's a very simple interface to use.
I'm going to go ahead and go and look at my Acey two instances and hopefully it is live now.
And I will be able to get an IP address.
So here it is.
And there's my pin address down here so I'm going to highlight the IP address and I'm going to right
click and copy it.
Now if we go back over to our party configuration we can type in here a c too high end user.
And then at and then the putty the IP address is $52 51 to 120 to 70.
Now what I can do is also copy and paste this save sessions one of them save it just yet is the last
thing we want to do is go to here's we're going to go into S-sh we're going to go over to walls and
in here we're going to enter with our private key is so this is the one that we've just generated.
My party Kaid PPK going to open it up.
And now we we go all the way back up to the top to session we can hit save We don't need to do this
again.
We can basically just go in it load.
And then open.
So let's go ahead and open that first thing it's going to ask is about service.
Case cashed in the registry.
So you just go ahead and.
Yes.
And there we go with connected into our easy to instance.
Now you can see this is quite small can be quite hard to read.
So let's close this off and just close the session then what I'm going to do and I'm just going to go
back to my desktop and I'm going to open up.
Party will load up our default settings.
Now we can actually change the appearance.
We can go in here and change the font size.
So you go here and it's 20 that's going to change the font you change the colors etc..
I'm just going to leave the colors as standard and then keep the font as 20 I'm going to go ahead and
save that.
Now when we open it's going to be much bigger.
You got much bigger it takes now for the rest of this lecture I'm going to switch over to my Mac.
All commands will be exactly the same.
Because right now we're all on a PC to instance in the cloud so we're all using Linux so all the commands
will be the same whether using Windows or Mac to elevate my privileges to rootes I'm going to type sudo
su.
And so now I'm a super user can see or be here it says root.
And so this means I have for admin access.
So we have a little Linux server in the cloud Let's go and make it a web service.
The very first thing we want to do is just run a yum update minus.
Yes.
And this will just update the you know the operating system with all relevant packages.
It means it's got all the latest updates applied to it so that hopefully there will be no vulnerabilities
and that can take just a little bit of time but it's just cleaning up now it's done all the installations.
And once this is done what we need to do is we're going to go in and install Apache Apache just turns
this little server into a web server and then what we'll do is we'll create a little web page just says
hello hoggers or something like that.
So that has now finished updating.
Let's clear the screen and to install Apache we just need to write yum install and then hate TTP day.
And then just to remind us why.
For mine yes.
So that has now installed again I'm going to clear the screen so you can find what I'm doing much easier.
So I've installed Apache.
The next thing we want to do is we want to start the Apache service so we say service to DVD start and
that has now started the service.
And then we just want to do one other thing.
So the service has started to.
The one thing that we want to do is if this to instance reboot we want Apache to come back on automatically
so to do that we just type in check config and then hatred DVD and then we say on and that will just
means that if we restart this two instance Apache will come on automatically so we can now type in service
HDDVD and then status that will show us if the HD DVD service is running the Apache service.
It is now running.
And when we install that we've created a directory so if we go to CD.
Dub dub dub page Timo This is the root directory of our web server.
We type in l s we can see that there's nothing there.
So let's go ahead and fix that one I'm going to do.
I'm going to write to Nannar index dot TMM and we're going to create a little web page so here's a little
textedit built into our easy to instance I'm just going to quickly do some code.
So Timo make this really simple so body then hate Schwann so head.
And then it's just going to say hello cloud gurus going to endow H-1 again and our body is like literally
the most simple piece of HTML you can do.
And we're going to end typed here now and tomorrow and then I'm just going to hit the control X. they'll
ask us if we want to save I'm going to hit yes and then I'm going to hit enter.
And so now if I do ls we can see my little index dot hate himself.
So next thing to do is I'm just going to clear the screen.
Let's go over to the web browser and see this Web site.
OK so here I am and my web browser I just type in the IP address or you can see straight away Hello
cowgirl.
So we've created a little web server in the cloud we've created web site and we can now connect to that
web site using our using that public IP address.
So what we now want to do is we're going to look at how we can register a domain name and how we can
point that domain name a to this to instance.
Now before we go on to registering a domain name we need to in the need to create a application load
balance or in order for all this to work.
So let's go in the next lecture and explore.
From a theoretical point of view what a what the different types of balances are what's available to
you.
And then once we've done that we'll go on and we'll register domain name and we'll point out my name
to our application load balance which will then point out to instance and then you'll be able to visit
this Web site just by typing in a domain name.
So if you've got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.