OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture this lecture before we get started on route 53 and creating
our own domain name we are going to need to create an elastic load balance or as a part of that.
And I just wanted to go through the theory of elastic Loide balances.
So what is an elastic load balance or what's the load balance.
Well the hint is in the name of load balance or simply helps us balance our load across multiple different
servers.
So let's say you've got a whole bunch of web servers and you want to equally balance the load between
them.
You deploy a load balance and then using various types of technology it will help you balance the load
across those web servers so no one web server will get overwhelmed.
And so hopefully your application won't crash.
So that's all a load balance is now with us.
There's three different types of balances with our application load balances in our application load
Belon so operates at the OS.
I like 7 so if you're not familiar with the OS side Lia's just go ahead and type it into Google and
click on the Wikipedia article.
It basically will go and explain all the different layers of computing.
So application load balances can actually make very clever decisions they can actually go all the way
down to the application layer and they can load balance based off that so they could if it could see
that packets are destined for let's say sales at a cloud.
Gary It would then send those packets directly to the sales web servers or application servers if it
was a different subdomain could go to a completely different subdomain.
It can also look at whether or not someone's making a purchase.
Maybe that would go to a whole bunch of different application servers.
My point being is that application load balances can see all the way up to the application layer and
they can make very clever routing or routing decisions based on that you know information.
We then have our network Loide balances.
This operates at layer for this is where you basically want to super fast performance and super fast
speed.
It is basically AWOS as most expensive load balance but it is what you would use in production especially
if latency is an issue you want to use network load balances and then we have our classic load balances
in our classic load balances pretty much you know they don't recommend them.
But it is there for legacy purposes.
Interestingly the developer associate exam actually tests you mostly on classic low balances even though
AWOS themselves are pushing you to either use application load balances or network load balances.
So we will have a quick look at a classic load balances as well.
But in the next lecture what we're going to go ahead and create is an application load balance.
So let's start with application load balances and they're best suited for load balancing of Hastey to
be and Hastey to be traffic they operate at least 7 an hour application of where they are intelligent
and you can create advents requests routing sending specified requests to specific web servers.
So here we've got a Tesla Model X. let's say something let's say that you know we have an application
inside our model X. We could send all that model X traffic to a specific set of web servers that are
only designed for Model X and then if we had a Tesla Model S or we had a Model 3 for example we could
get our application load balances to send them to completely different instances depending on the you
know depending on the packets.
Basically the application load balance could be configured so it could figure out what type of car was
being sending the request.
And then it could send that to a group of web service that is designed specifically to respond to traffic
for that car.
We then have our network load balances so network load balance is best suited for load balancing of
TCAP traffic where extreme performance is required.
And again I love Teslas.
Here is a Tesla Roadster.
It is going to be capable of doing a zero to 60 miles an hour in under two seconds.
Think of extreme performance that is going to be one of the basically the fastest production ever made.
So operation operating at the connection level low for network load balance is capable of handling millions
of requests per second while maintaining ultra low latencies.
So use a network load balance for an extreme performance but do bear in mind it is going to be the most
costly load balance of the three different load balances.
And so think of extreme performance.
Think of a Tesla Roadster.
You can get extreme performance out of them but they are the most expensive Teslas that you can buy.
The classic load balances have Cattaro.
So a classic load balance the legacy stick load balances you can load balance Hastey to be and HTP require
applications using a 7 specific features such as the x4 would add 4 and sticky sessions but you can
also use strict lay a for load balancing.
For applications that rely purely on the TZP protocol so you can either do essentially you either do
a seven oleo for using the classic load balance but last seven it's not anywhere near as intelligent
as an application load balancer.
It is literally just using the exported four and sticky sessions will come to explode four in one more
slide.
But before we do that I just want to talk about load balance errors.
So the classic load balance.
If your application stops responding the elastic load balance or Costic load balancer responds with
a 5 0 for error.
And this means that the application is having issues.
And this could either be at the web server layer or the database layer.
But basically it's not the load balancer itself that's having the issue.
It's something below the load balance.
It's just not getting a response.
And that means you need to troubleshoot either the web server or the database layer.
You need to basically identify where the application is filing and scale it up or out where possible
so that if you get a 5 for era it's basically a gateway timeout error.
Moving on to x4 did fall so it's good to use the here.
This is the public IP address I've just made one up and $24 one to talk to 3 2 3 1.
They then do it DNS requests and they hit our load balance load balance so take that request and it
will use the private IP address or $10.00 0.23 and it will then send that on to our A.C. to instance.
Now AC to instance will only see that private IP address see 10.0 $0.00 2 3.
Now this can cause problems because you probably want to know where in the world you use it is where
they're coming from et cetera.
So how can you get the IP for public address when you're lastic load balance is sending you the private
address.
Well really easy.
You just gotta go and look for it in the Axford forehead and you'll be able to see the public ip address
this are 1 2 4 1 2 3 2 3 1.
So just remember that going into your exam.
So speaking of exam tips.
So basically just remember that there's three different types of load balances.
You've got your application load balances your network load balances and your classic load balances.
Remember that a 5 or 4 ERA means that the Gateway has timed out.
And this means that the application is not responding within the Idle Timeout period.
So how do you do what how do you troubleshoot this.
Well go ahead and troubleshoot the application is the web server down.
Or is the database server down.
Do you need to scale out.
You need to scale up etc..
And if you need the IP for address of your end user using classic load balancers then you just need
to use the Axford forehead up so that is load balance in a nut shell.
Remember these tips going into your exam and you'll do fine in the next election.
What we're going to do is we're going to register a domain name using route 53.
They're going to point to that domain name to an application load balancer which will have some E.C
to instances inside it and then hopefully we'll be able to resolve our May name all the way down to
our easy to instant.
So if you've got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.