OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture this lecture we're going to look at route 53 and it is
the legacy you will need to log into the AWOS.
But before we do that let's have a brief overview of what route 53 actually is.
So Rick 53 is Amazon's DNS service and allows you to map you don't main names to things like AC to instances
to load balances which would cover off a bit later.
And two as three buckets which will also cover off a bit lighter.
So Rick 53 essentially allows you to buy a domain name.
We could buy say hello pluggers dot com and then we'd be able to connect that domain name to three different
end so either AC to auto load balances or to S3.
So let's go and look into the AWOS console.
OK so here I am in the console going to go to services and I'm going to go down to network so down his.
And here it is on the network and content delivery route 53 or route 53.
How you want to say it.
So what we want to do is go ahead and get started now and we're going to go ahead and create a hosted
zine and we don't have any hosted zones what we might want to do first before we create this hosted
zone is to go and register a domain.
So we go in and register a domain and click on registered domain.
So now you need to choose a domain name.
Now Dotcom's are about $12 you can get something cheaper.
Let's have a look at what the cheapest one is or a $9 one.
It's entirely up to what you want to buy.
You can say there's so many different top level domains now.
Here's one for $8 may do UK.
So I'm going to just go ahead and buy a dot com.
You can choose whatever it is you want and then you can just type in here we can do Hellery cloud Gere's
I'm pretty sure that is taken.
Pretty sure I bought it from some but you know in another course maybe it would do.
I'm a cloud.
Dot com.
Let's see if that's available.
Yes it is available.
We're going to go ahead and add it to my cart then I'm going to go down and hit continue.
Now we have to fill in all this registrant information.
So I'm going to go ahead and do that.
You can do this yourself.
And once that's done I'm going to go ahead and hit submit.
OK so I have gone ahead and filled that out.
I just need to agree to the terms and conditions.
It's going to send me an e-mail to the registrant e-mail address just to check that I actually ynot
and you won't be able to get past the screen until you've verified that e-mail case you've just gone
ahead and verified that e-mail is just refreshed the status here.
And we can say that has been registered.
Now we're going to go ahead and hit complete purchase and that has now purchased my domains.
So it says thank you for registering your domain to route 53.
I'm a coward Gary.
Dot com.
What's next.
Domain registration might take up to three days to complete.
We'll send an e-mail to the registrant contact.
Once the domain is successfully registered so you just click on go to domain's and you say that this
status is domain registration in progress.
Now it doesn't normally take three days.
It depends what top level domain name that you use.
I'm just going to pause the video and wait for this domain name to become available.
OK so this is now available for disclosure.
It was a long weekend over the you know over the last few days.
So this is a few days later but you should be able to register it.
You know within a few hours it really just penciled the top level domain.
So we get it back over to our dashboard and we click on hosted zones you'll be able to see your domain
inheres.
So I'm a cloud Gouri dot com.
Now what we can do is we can go ahead and go to our record sets.
And this is where we create our DNS records so if we go back over we can create things like our a a
record and a record is essentially if you think of an old school telephone book you used to look up
Mr. Smith in the telephone book and you get a phone number.
Essentially when you're creating an error code it's exactly the same thing.
What we're doing is we're saying where I'm a cowgirl.
Dot Com is going to guard.
So if we just click on create a record set you'll be able to see the different types of records in here.
So we've got a record See name records of MX records Triple-A records et cetera.
So a record would point to an IP address.
A triple-A record of quadruple a record would point to an IP B-6 address et cetera et cetera.
So what we're going to do is we're going to create a address and we're going to use what's called the
naked domain name.
So what do we mean by naked domain name where we simply just mean I'm a cow.
Dot com rather than w w w dot I'm a cloud Gouri dot com.
And this is sometimes also referred to as the zone apex record.
Now in order to do this we have to use an alias.
I'd be interested what an alias is just hold your mouse over it says specify whether you want this record
set to be an alias for an AWOS or resorts an alias it is similar in some ways to a C name record set.
Well one of the differences is that you create an alias for the zone apex we create this for the naked
domain name and this it basically is only supported by a and quadrupole a record so IPV for IPV six
addresses so what we're going to do is in here we're going to click in here and we've got our different
targets so you can have an alias target for an S-3 Web site for an elastic load balance the application
load balance elastic load balance a classic load balance the elastic load balance and network load balance.
The cloud front distributions for lastic beanstalk environments etc..
So what we're going to do is we're going to have to go and create a load balancer.
And then what we're going to do is put out two instance behind that load balance and then we'll come
back here and basically create the DNS name so that when people go to out my name they'll be able to
see a little Web site.
So let's go back over two services are going to go over to see too.
We should still have our little E.S. to instance up and running that we created earlier.
I have no idea why but for some reason I'm in Oregon.
A little bit confusing so if you do not see for instance just check where you should be should be back
in northern Virginia and yet I can see my instance there.
And then what you want to do in order to create a load balance is if you go down to load balancing you
see it right here and just create a go to load balances and click on that link and you'll see that right
now we don't have any load balances in this region.
So go ahead and create a load balance.
So there's three different types of load balance as we have application load balances network load balances
and classic load balances.
Now application load balance is when you need to be you know basically using web applications for the
page.
And this operates at the request level network.
Lloyd balancers you would use when you need Oktar high performance and static IP addresses for your
application.
So we're going to go ahead and create an application load balance so in here you might want to give
it a name so I'm going to call up my base application load balance.
It's going to be Internet facing it's going to be using IP before.
So in here we have our listeners now listeners simply what to port our application load balance is going
to listen on Sohaib GDP is on port 80 and if you wanted to do to the best you can do it as well which
will be on port 443 just zoomed out my screen a little bit if you don't want to use SSL you can delete
that.
I'm going to take it off for now so I don't want to listen on SSL.
And here we have our availability zone.
So where do we want our application load balance to be based.
We're going to select all availabilities zones to get the maximum redundancy.
And next I'm going to go ahead and configure my security groups.
So it's going to give us this warning saying that it's not using a secure listener.
In other words we're not using AHCCCS.
That's fine.
Hit next.
And then we're going to assign a security groups let's assign the one that we created in the last election.
So I'm going to assign our my web DMZ and I'm going to go ahead and hit next to configure our routing.
So we're basically setting up Route requests to the targets in this target group so you can have a whole
bunch of different targets and you can route requests you know intelligently.
It's entirely up to you.
Might have like you know web servers in one routing group you might have application servers and another
you might have my Secord database service and another et cetera.
So going to create a new target group.
Nicole is my Webbs is great and we're going to do it on port NHT to pay on port 80.
The target type is simply whether or not the target's going to be registered using your instance IDs
the actual I.D. of the two incidents or using private IP addresses.
I'm going to use instance IDs as the default value.
And here we have our health check.
So what is it going to look for when it goes and you know does a health check.
So we're going to type in here though little web page that we created index dot.
Tim ELB I'll leave everything else as default and we're going to go in and register our targets.
So I'm going to add this to de-registered.
Great.
And then I'm going to go ahead and hit review and I'm going to go ahead and hit create now the health
check will take a little while to bring this load balance in to service is healthy.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to I'm going to take a while to provision.
So I'm going to pause the video and wait for this elastic load sorry application load balance to come
up online.
OK so that should hopefully be set up let's just hit refresh and we can now see the state has changed
to active.
We actually go into the target groups we should be able to see if that what targets are healthy so we
can see here we've got a registered target his our instance I.D. and that status is healthy.
So it has found that indexed not hiked yemo.
And so the very last thing we need to do is we need to go over to services.
We're going to go back to route 53 which is under network content and delivery and we're going to click
on there and what we're going to do is we're going to point our DNS to our application load balance.
So click in here and we'll go.
Just click on the link and you can see in here this is our host at Xyron So we're going to create a
record set and we're going to do an alias record and in here we'll be able to see the target.
So here it is my baby.
I'm going to click in there and I'm going to leave everything else as default and go ahead and hit create.
And so now what we're going to do is to open up a new tab and we're going to go to I'm a cloud guru
dot com.
OK so here we are I'm just going to open up.
Yeah I'm going to type I'm a cloud girl or dot com and if we minimize though we go says hello cloud
girl.
So we have now created a working Web site it's behind an application load balancer which is spread across
multiple availability zones.
And then when we go to resolve the name I'm a cloud Gouri that's basically sending traffic to our application
load balance which is sending traffic to our e c to instance.
So that is it for this electrolyze hopefully you've learnt a lot.
The next lecture what we're going to do is we're going to look into our easy to instance and we're going
to show you how to set up a user so that they can access S-3 using the command line and it's very important
to understand how to do that.
Going into your exam so if you've got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.