OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture in sexual way going to look at the CLIA it with the command
line interface.
We're going to interact with AWOS using the Selye inside out E.C to instance that we created earlier
so you're going to need to look into your E.C to instance.
OK so here I am in the AWOS console going to go over to services and I'm going to click on easy to um
to compute all I want to get is my public IP address because it or remember it's just going to copy
this into my clipboard then I'm going to open up terminal and connect to DCC to instance.
OK so here I am in my terminal window I'm just going to type in S-sh.
It's too high for news.
And then at a paste in my public IP address and then I think it's called My new keypad PM and going
to go ahead and hit enter.
And that has now led me into my Amazon Linux.
Am I going to elevate my privileges to route by typing sugur SU.
Then I'm going to go ahead and clear the screen.
So the next thing I want to try and do is use the command line.
So whenever you using the command line you always start with AWOS and then you start with the service
that you want to use.
So let's try AWOS S3.
I was gonna say.
LS We want to list everything now is three buckets now straightaway it says unable to locate credentials
you could configure credentials by running AWOS configure.
So if we run AWOS configure it's going to ask us for an Access Key ID and secret access key and an order
to generate these we need to go back to the AWOS console some back in the AWOS console I'm going to
go over to services.
And then I'm going to go down to security identity and compliance and I'm going to click on identity
access management inside here.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead and create a new user.
So click on user Wynkyn add user and the user name.
We're going to add let's call it.
So develop a one so developer one and we're going to give them programmatic access here.
So this is where we basically generating an Access Key ID and secret access to the ATO vs API CLID and
DKs and other development tools now using if I don't click this button Yeah.
They won't be able to log into the management console which is what I'm currently logged into right
now and I'm going to just leave it a programmatic access.
I'm going to go ahead and hit next to add my permissions now and here it says set permissions for development.
So you can add a user to a group.
Probably the best thing that we want to do is we want to create a group for our developers so let's
call this out developer group so developers and we need to then give them a policy.
Now in here administrator access is basically God mode.
So it gives you full access to AWOS services and resources.
Now whether or not you want your developers to have full admin access to the AWOS console it really
depends on your own corporate sort of governance.
The ease of this demo.
I'm going to go ahead and give them full access.
Of course you might not want to do that because they could go in and start doing anything inside the
AWOS console so it's really down to your company policy soon to create a script and that's created my
group called developers and then I'm going to add a user to this group.
So at a user group I can be a little bit tricky if you just scroll down and you'll see it.
Here's his next review.
And so we're going to review we've created our use develop a one we give them AWOS access type programmatic
access with an access key and we're going to add them to developers.
Let's go ahead and create our user.
So we have now created our user if we go over and click down go out sorry are here we can see the Access
Key ID.
So let's copy this into our clipboard and go back over to terminal.
So I'm back in terminal going to paste it in.
Hit enter you know tobacco and grab my secret access key.
So grab my secret access key and I'm going to paste it in here.
Don't worry I am going to delete this user soon as I've finished recording this video so that you won't
be able to log in and start mining Bitcoin using my credentials.
So I pasted that in here.
Default region.
This is the default region in which this user creates you know resources.
So if my default region was EU west one and then I decided to make an S-3 bucket that bucket if I don't
specify a region will exist within EU West one.
And if you just leave this blank I believe it is the default region is northern Virginia.
So what I'm going to do is just leave it blank and hit enter and default output format again I'm just
going to hit enter and leave that as blank.
So what I'm going to do now.
Going to.
Let's not clear the screen.
Let's try AWOS as three Ls s three Ls and run this command again and you can see now that it hasn't
given us any error messages just saying that there's nothing in our S-3 buckets.
So why don't we go ahead and create it.
So AWOS S-3 going to make a bucket that's going to be called S3.
And now we just need to give it a valid bucket names are going to call a cloud for one two three four
and then my initials are ok.
Hopefully that will.
There we go.
Make a bucket.
So if I now type in a B S S3 LS you'll be able to see my bucket.
A cloud girder.
One two three four.
Minus.
OK.
So there is the bucket.
And what I could even do now if I just do echo Hello cloud girders and then output that to hello.
Ticker tape that will create a little phone call.
Hello texta.
It takes t and inside that file will be hello cloggers.
And then what I can do is I can just do this S-3 and then copy and then I want to copy.
Hello.
DOT takes t to us 3 and then it was code.
A cloud.
One two three four and then hyphen are OK.
And that should hopefully not didn't work because you can see I've misspelt a cloud girs was going to
go over and fix that up.
So rather than there we go one two three four and there we go it's uploaded to our S3 bucket and we
can actually see it up by typing AWOS S3 and then ls and then Estrace the name of the bucket a cloud
Gouri one two three four.
And.
OK.
And that will basically list everything inside the bucket.
Let's go over and just have a quick look at this text file in the AWOS console some back in the AWOS
console.
I've come out of that I am screen and the one thing to note that when you do generate an Access Key
ID and Secret Access Key You only be able to see it once once if we go back in 2 a.m. we go over to
our users and if we click on or use the developer one we go over to security credentials we'll see and
here that we've got our access key I.D. but we can't see the secret access key anymore and there is
no way to see it again.
So when you do generate it.
Just bear in mind you only ever see it once.
You might want to save it somewhere very very safe in the next lecture will look at why you want to
save that somewhere very very safe.
So one thing I am quickly going to do is going to make is in active.
So that is now inactive.
What I can now do is I can delete it by clicking that little X..
Go ahead and hit delete.
And now that this particular user does no longer has access key idea or secret access key you can recreate
it just by clicking in here.
Create and that will generate it again and again you only ever see this once.
I quickly just go back over to my terminal window came back in my terminal window if I type in AWOS
S3 and then LS you'll see that we now have an error.
And it says Invalid access key ID then that's because I have deleted it.
So I now have to go back and run AWOS configure and then that will allow me to enter in an Access Key
ID and secret access.
And then to leave this.
Now let's go back over to S-3 case I'm back in the console.
Just going to click on S3.
So should be able to see it here it is in here.
A Clogher.
One two three four.
OK.
Note that the region is U.S. East one.
So is northern Virginia.
And if we click in here we'll be able to see out a little text file.
We haven't made this public so let's just make it public now and click on it.
You see up here it says hello pluggers.
Be a little bit hard to read but there we go.
So you just go over to Darkstar AWOS dot Amazon Dot com forward slash sealife Ford slash latest Ford
slash index dot hate mail or just type in Ajdabiya Selye commands into Google.
This will come up and then here you can get all your CLIA commands for all the different services and
you'll see there's an awful lot of them.
So we were using AWOS then followed by the service S3 and then you can click in here and you can see
all the different ones we used may Mbaye which was Mike bucket.
And we also use the copy command and you can go through and have a look at all the available comments
in here and different examples of how to use them now don't worry you're not expected to understand
the command line in any sort of very deep level going into your exam but you should definitely know
some of the basic commands certainly around S-3 especially if you're going to work with us regularly.
So what my exam tips say OK so what my exam tips will let's start with the least privilege you should
always give your users the minimum amount of access required so you developers might not need admin
access.
They might just need admin access so that S3 or admin access over s over to it's entirely up to you
at a Cogar we do give our developers a full administrator access to the AWOS console because we do trust
them.
But it's entirely up to your organization's sort of risk strategy.
The next thing is to always create groups and then assign your users to groups so we created a group
called developers and we put our first use in there who might have a separate group for our data scientists
we might have a separate group for our human resources people or people who you know using AWOS in other
ways.
So always create groups and then assign your users to groups and you users will automatically inherit
the permissions of the groups and the group permissions are assigned using policy documents so bear
that in mind as well.
In terms of your secret access you're only going to see this once.
If you do not say but you can delete the key pair.
So this is the access key ID and secret access.
And then regenerate it and you will then need to run AWOS configure again in order to configure the
CLIA and do not just use one access case so don't just create one access key ID and sacred access and
then share that around with all the VO developers because if someone leaves the company on bad terms
then you're going to need to delete the key and create a new one and every developer would then need
to update daks.
So instead just create one key pad per developer and something you should also bear in mind is people
have written scripts to scan get hub access ID and secret access.
So if you do put it in any of your code and you upload it to get hub assume straight away that that
has been compromised so do not save these sacred Access Key ID and do you know your access key ID inside
get highboy inside job code.
And we're going to come on to another lecture where we can see how to not use them at all.
And then finally you can use the same lie on your PC so you can actually go and install this on your
Mac Linux or Windows PC and then you can actually use S3 to store your files and I personally do this
up in the cloud.
It means that when I'm using my Mac or using my laptop or I'm at home using my Windows PC I always have
access to my S-3 bucket and all my files inside it in order to find out how to do that just type in
installing AWOS.
And then there's three different installation instructions depending on whether or not you using Macs
Linux or Windows PCs.
So bear that in mind so in the next lecture what we're going to look at is we're going to look at how
not to use X secret access and access key IDs and we're actually going to look at how we can use rolls.
We have gone into that little easy to instance and we did terminate that pairs that cape pair is no
longer valid.
I can no longer access the CEO or I can no longer use the Seelye in the next lecture what we're going
to look at is roll so if you got the time please join me in the next lecture.