OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture this lecture we're going to look at easy to with as three
roles.
So you might remember in the last lecture we created our secret access key access key ID.
We then ran AWOS configure and we were able to provision a bucket and a copy a file up to that packet.
We then basically went into the I-AM console and we went and deleted that Secret Access Key ID and our
access.
So now we are no longer able to communicate with the S3.
And so the next thing we're going to do is we're going to create a role and we're going to give that
S3 admin access and then we're going to apply that role to a running a C to instance.
So this is a lab and you will need to look into the AWOS console.
OK so I've looked into the AWOS code so I'm going to go over to services and I'm going to go down to
security identity and compliance and click on I am.
Now we've got our user in here and our users in our group we have a look at our user could develop one
and we can see if we click on developer one that they're inheriting the administrator access from the
group.
Click on security credentials we'll see actually generated an Access Key ID just for consistency.
Just go ahead and delete that.
So this you said no longer has any kind of access.
So what I want to do now is I want to go ahead and create a role.
So if we click on roles it says what roles have roles or a secure way to grant permissions to entities
that you trust.
Basically you allow you to row two resources within AWOS so you could give your E.C to instance you
know you basically create a role that allows you to instance to talk to S-3 where you create a role
that allows Lamda to execute or you create a role that allows Lamda to write things to S-3 or to dynamite
D-B.
If you don't know what Lamda dynamo Bay or any of that is just yet to worry we are going to cover it
in the course.
So what I'm going to do is going to go over here and create a row.
And in here we're going to create a role for an AWOS service.
You can create a role for another AWOS account.
You can also use it for web identity's.
So this be things like cognito or any open ID provide us like Facebook for example.
And then you can also allow your roles to interact with active directory.
So Semmel two federations so this would be your corporate directory.
We're going to do this for the AWOS service and we're going to do this for AC too.
This is the most common roles.
Let's go ahead and click on A.C. 2 and go ahead and hit next on our permissions and in here we've got
all our different policy types.
Now we could give our easy to instance administrator access but that would be pretty insane because
if that is easy to instance was compromised and somebody managed to hack it and they could then go in
and start provisioning stuff inside Al cloud.
They could go and create other E.C two instances they could go and delete things.
So we don't want to do that we want to have a policy of least privilege certain here.
We don't want to do is just type in S-3 and in here we can see that with a policy that is Amazon S3
full access so we can click on that.
You don't actually see what the policies look like.
You can click on the link and you can go in and look at that Jason.
And essentially this is a policy document.
It's all a whole bunch of just keep his so get a version and then we've got our statement and our statement
has some nested rules inside.
So we've got effect allow action S-3 resorts everything.
So essentially this Jason is saying are going to allow basically this row to do anything inside S-3.
So we're just going to go up here and close that and come back over so you can you definitely have to
understand how to read roles going into this exam so do be aware of that or how to read Jason policies.
So Amazon S3 full access is the one that we want.
Let's go ahead and hit next.
I'm going to call this my three admin access.
So that's my real name and the role description allows Acey two instances to code A.W. services on your
behalf.
You might want to change that to call AWOS S-3 on your behalf because that this row or only allow us
to interact with x ray we can't do anything else.
So let's go ahead and hit create.
And that has now created our role.
I've got a whole bunch of other roles in here from other courses just ignore that.
You can see the road down here.
My S-3 admin access so don't want to do now is I want to go over again too easy too.
So I'm going to go to compute and click on E.S. too and what I want to do is apply this row to my Acey
to instance.
But before we do that let's just look back into the two instance and make sure that we definitely cannot
access S-3 case here I am in my terminal window going to S-sh over to my Acey to instance going to elevate
my privileges to root.
And I'm going to clear the screen and just type abs s s.
LS get an error message saying invalid access ID when calling the list bucket action.
Now I could go in and type AWOS configure and do a whole bunch of new you know secret access case an
Access Key IDs.
I'm not going to do that.
What I'm going to do is just tap back over to the AWOS console.
So I'm back in the E.S. to console for eight of us are going to click on my little AC to instance I'm
going to go to actions and I'm going to go over to instant settings and you can see just over here a
touch replace a roll soon click in here and I'm going to go ahead and add my S-3 admin access road.
Now note that this box will earn the order to populate with two rolls we can't see any of my Lamda rolls
for example.
So my S-3 admin access I need to go ahead and hit apply.
So that operation has now succeeded.
I didn't need to stop my instance or return to it or terminate it or anything like that.
I just applied it to the instance.
Let's go back over to our terminal window.
OK so I'm back in my terminal window.
If I type in AWOS s three Ls I'm going to get the same error message and the reason for this is because
it still has access key ID and secret access keys saved in a little hidden directory inside our Linux
instance and it would do the same in Windows as well.
So in order to stop this just go see a search change directory and you want to go to your home directory
and then it's for Slashdot.
AWOS.
And that's a little hidden directory if you type in ls in here you can see the configuration and you
can see your credentials.
And in order to stop it from doing this just go in and remove credentials.
Are him credentials that will say remove regular file credentials.
Yes and then you may also just want to do the same with the COM fix or remove config.
Yes if we type Ellefson now will say that there's nothing in there.
So if we go back to our root directory and just clear the screen what we'll do now is just type AWOS
S-3 else it will see that it doesn't have any credentials.
But now the role has kicked in and we can see our S-3 buckets.
We've got a cloud Guri one two three four minus k and we can actually go in and have a look at the contents
of that.
So yes S-3 less than three and then a cloud Gary.
One two three four hyphen and then our K and you'll be able to see our Hello 0.60.
Then again we could go to an echo.
So hello cloud gurus too.
And we're going to put that out to help too.
It takes t takes t and them what we want to do is AWOS S-3 then copy hello to takes t over two three
and then a cloud Gary.
One two three four.
OK that should hopefully copy it up.
There you go.
It's been successful.
And again if we just run that command A.W. S S3 ls and have a look at the contents you'll be able to
see our second text file in there.
Now for Windows users if you want to locate way your configuration credential file is in your user profile
and then forwards Slashdot AWOS and you can go.
If you just go to Dacosta AWOS Amazon Dot com for slushed Zelaya for slushed latest vote Sless user
guide.
And then it's on to Selye hyphen com fake hyphen files start.
T l.
So what are my exam tips let's go over and have a look.
So my exam tips will roles allow you not to use Access Key IDs and Secret Access case.
And if you do lose your access key ideal secret access.
Maybe you accidently save it to a file that you publish and get hub.
Anyone can access your AWOS account and if you've given that account administrator access they can literally
do anything.
So they're not very secure.
They're difficult to manage.
You have to go and install them on every single easy to instance whereas roles are universal and you
can apply them across multiple E.C two instances and you can't compromise the roles or roles are always
preferred.
From a security perspective if you are given a choice in a US an exam scenario or between Access Key
ID and Secret Access case versus rolls always choose roles are also controlled by policies so we saw
we added the S-3 admin access policy policies just basically a whole bunch of Jason and it basically
has keypads and it states what you can and can't do.
You can change a policy on a row and it's going to take immediate effect.
So I could go in there and go into my S-3 admin access policy and start tweaking the Jason and that
will take immediate effect.
I could say OK I want to be only able to read from history I don't want that person to do any writes
As soon as you save that policy.
That would take immediate effect and then most improved that you can attach and detach roles to running
two instances without having to stop or terminate these instances.
It was certainly quite a recent thing.
Many many years that was a very popular exam topic.
You used to have to terminate your AC to instance and then recreate it with the role attached but now
you can attach and detach roles to running two instances.
So that is it for this lecture guys.
Remember if you do have a scenario question where you've got roles versus access key IDs and secret
access.
Kids always choose roles.
Do you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.