OK hello bloggers and welcome to this lecture you're going to look at audience 101.
What is audience sense for relational database service.
So I guess the best place to start with is what is a relational database or relational databases or
what most of us use to and the been around since the 70s and I want you to think of a traditional spreadsheet.
So in your spreadsheet you've got a spreadsheet is basically a database you've got the actual spreadsheet
itself which consists of workbooks and then a workbook is essentially a table so you can switch between
the different workbooks inside an Excel spreadsheet for example.
And then when you're actually in the tables they consist of two things.
They consist of rows and they consist of fields or columns.
So that's all a relational database is you have a database that will be filled with a whole bunch of
different tables and each table has rows and columns.
So here's a good example of that database.
This is a student database for example so we've got our ID we've got our first name our surname and
our gender.
So we've got four fields of four columns in this database and then we've got individual rows.
So a student ID one is myself and student ID 2 is John Adams.
STUDENT 3 is Julia Clark and student ID for is Erica stick here.
So this is the data that basically makes up a relational database it's pretty pretty simple.
So what are the different relational database types.
You can have with Amazon's Adia service.
Well first off we have Microsoft sequel server.
We then have Oracle.
We then have my sequel's server.
We then have postscripts So we then have Amazon's own database technology which is called Amazon Aurora.
And then we also have Maria de base.
So these are the six instances that you can provision within D.S. and in the next lab what we're going
to do is we're going to go ahead and provision a my Seacole instance Amazon Aurora is just worth noting.
It is Amazon's own flagship database technology.
It's fully compatible with my Sakal So if you've got my Silkwood database you can ship it over to Aurora
and we will cover Aurora in a lot more detail as we go through the course.
It's worth also mentioning what a non relational database is just so you know we're going to have a
whole section on non-relational databases and in particular dynamite Bay.
But basically a non relational database is a database and inside the database we have a collection.
We have documents and we have key value pairs.
So what's a collection collection is basically a table.
Think of it that way.
A document is simply a row in that table and the document comprises of a whole bunch of different key
value pairs.
Now the cool thing about non-relational databases is that you don't need to pre define the table structure.
So if you remember from the last one where we had the ID the first name the surname and agenda that
all has to be predefined before you can put data into it with non-relational databases you don't need
to pre-define your columns you can add them as you go.
So let's have a look at an example.
So this is some Jason or no see call.
So we have got our ID.
We've got our first name our surname our age and we've got our address and inside our address we've
got our straight and our suburb.
So if we look at the I.D. It's a key value pair and it basically within Jason it always will start with
this curly bracket and then followed by quotation marks and then you'll have a field in this field is
going to be essentially your column and then you going to have a colon and then we're going to have
more quotation marks and then the actual data itself.
So what is the ID.
OK it's this number here.
Then we close out the quotations and then we do a comma and then we start over again so we can add as
much info in here as we want.
And this will all form rower's inside our non relational databases.
And in some non relational databases you can also have nested fields in the address we can have this
straight.
We could have the Subah we could have the apartment number et cetera et cetera.
Now don't worry too much about this just yet.
We will have a whole section of the course on Amazon's known relational database flagship product which
is dynamite bay that is coming up.
Another thing to mention around databases is what data warehousing is so data warehousing is used for
business intelligence and tools like Cognos just pissed off sequel's server sorry sequencing or reporting
services Arko Hyperion and SAP NetWeaver are all business intelligence tools and what they do is they
pull in very large and complex data sets and is usually used by management to do queries on data such
as current performance versus targets etc. and you can actually build these databases specifically so
that they're not production databases but they're actually data warehouses that are used for reporting
only so your production database might push out all the information to a data warehouse.
And when you're running these really into queries you want to do that on your data warehouse and not
on your production database because you don't want to bring your production database down.
And so we also should look at online transaction processing versus online analytics processing and that's
basically coming back to that example so online transaction processing differs from online analytics
processing in terms of the types of queries that you run.
So an online transaction processing could be an example of an online store.
Somebody places an order the order number is 2 1 2 1 to 1 and it basically that's going to pull up a
row of data such as the name of the person who's placing the order the date the address to deliver to
the delivery status et cetera.
So it's going to write a piece of let's just say a row of data to a database so that's an online transaction
processing these transactions all happen much more frequently.
But they'll be very very simple transactions so just be insert into this table this data.
Whereas online analytics processing could be something much more complex.
Perhaps you are trying to figure out a net profit for a Maea and Pacific for a digital radio product.
And so you've got a pull in large numbers of records you've got to basically add up the number of radios
sold in Europe Middle East and Africa.
So Mia the number of radios sold in the Pacific and then you've got to come up with the unit cost of
the radios and age they'll probably be different than the sales price of a radio.
And then you basically have to figure out what the sales price is minus the unit cost and we also might
have some kind of foreign currency conversion as well.
So it's going to be doing an awful lot in one query.
So data warehousing databases use different types of architecture both from a database perspective as
a global is also down to the physical infrastructure layer to maximize the performance on these types
of queries.
So o pay will be very very simple transactions that happen very very frequently.
Well IP will be much more complex transactions that will happen very infrequently.
And then finally we're going to move on to elastic cash.
So less cash is basically a web service that makes it easy to deploy operate and scale and in-memory
case in the cloud and the service improves the performance of web applications by basically allowing
you to retrieve information from fast in memory Keisha's instead of relying entirely on slower disk
based databases.
So basically if you're going to a store and let's say you want to see the top 10 items that's on sale
you don't want every single user to pull that from your production database because you can just cache
that.
So you could cache that using elastic cache and then that way you take a load off your database and
typically what you're going to see in your exam is a whole bunch of what you know architectural changes
could you make in order to make your databases run faster.
So less to cache is a great way of caching frequently access information and so that when users go and
try and access that they don't have to pull it from the database they can pull it from elastic cache
and elastic cache actually supports to open source in memory caching engines.
So we've got memcached.
We've got rid us will have a lecture comparing the two.
Later on in the course.
So that is really it for this lecture let's just have a look at what we've learnt so we've learnt that
Adhya is basically online transaction processing.
It consists of sequel my sequel postscripts Kuo recall Aurora and Maria de Bay.
We've got dynamite Bay which is Amazon's no sequel offering.
And we're going to cover that off as a whole section in the course and then we've got a redshift which
is Amazon's online analytics processing.
And this is used for business intelligence and big data.
And then finally we have the elastic cache and this is in-memory caching and this is used to improve
the performance of the databases in the AWOS cloud.
And we have two engines inside that we've got memcached.
And we've got read us so that is it for this lecture guys and the next Lechuga we're going to do is
go in and provision a little DNS server.
We're then going to go ahead and make sure our little web server can connect to that audio server and
raid Fromont and then we're going to get a bit more hands on and start doing some more complicated stuff
with audio.
So if you've got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.