Okay hello bloggers and welcome to this lecture.
This lecture we're going to be looking at Amazon's relational database service.
And this is a lab.
What we're going to do is we're going to provision a very simple little RDX instance.
And then what we will do is we will go in and provision a web server.
We're going to use a bootstrap script so we're automatically going to install things like Apache EPA
HP and my sequel using that bootstrap script.
And then what we're going to do is we are going to go in and basically configure a connection string
connection string is just a username a password and the address to connect to our ideas for instance.
And if all goes well we should be able to connect to our audience instance.
So this is a lab and you will need to log into the obvious console.
Okay so here I am in the adobe us console.
I'm going to go ahead and click on RDX which is under database and then what we're going to do is we're
going to go in and create a database.
So this is a new UI and you can go back to the original one if you want.
I wouldn't recommend that you may as well get used to the new UI in here we can see our different options.
So we've got a raw my sequel Maria D.B. post rescue our Oracle Microsoft sequel server and Amazon obviously
make the default option Aurora because they're trying to push their home product but it is an amazing
product and I don't blame them.
We're going to do my sequel and we can scroll down here in here.
We've got our different templates you can do choose your different versions in here and our different
template.
So this is for production use which is going to basically put it across multiple Availability Zones
dev test and then free tier.
Now if you do click on free tier notice that you can't have Aurora on free tier it's not available just
yet.
So that could be an exam question.
So free tier we're going to use free tell with my sequel and scroll down in here we've got our database
DB for instance identifier.
So this is the name of our RDX instance inside a W.
And I'm gonna be a bit lazy I'm just going to type in a cloud guru and I'm going to copy that into my
clipboard and I'm going to use that consistently across the different you know credentials.
So my master username going to say a cloud guru my master password a cloud guru master password a cloud
guru he can actually order generate a password if you want as well you can actually use the command
line using AWOL secrets manager to generate really strong passwords as well that's just something that
I use in everyday and then down here we've got our DB instant size so we've got DB T2 micro so I'm gonna
do basically the cheapest ones who T2 micro is fine for me scrolling down storage we've got orders scaling
you can enable or disable it I'm just going to start off with 20 gigs of storage where am I going to
have a really simple database on here down here we've got availability and durability because we are
using free tier this is all grayed out right now if you wanted to click production then this would be
options that you could go ahead and select down here we've got additional connectivity configuration
so we've got our different subnet groups in here it's using the default one you can also say whether
or not you want this publicly accessible I'm going to say no VPC security groups let's create a new
security group we'll just call this RDX SMG something like that and then we're going to scroll down
and we've got our availability zones in here we've got no preference additional configuration just click
in here and give the initial database name a cloud guru.
So we are going to change the database name to be a cloud group and scroll all the way down we're just
going to leave everything else as default we've got our maintenance windows in here.
You can do it a particular time in which it's going to do upgrades and in here you can see your estimated
monthly cost so let's go ahead and hit create database so that is now launching it can take a few minutes
depending on the size of the instance can take up to five to 10 minutes to actually see the instance
if you click on your dashboard sorry if you click on instances you'll be able to see it just click on
ideas you can see here that it is creating while we wait for that to create let's go back over to services
and we'll go over to E2 and hopefully our little instance has now been deleted yes it has and what we
want to do is we're going to go ahead and launch a new instance I'm going to use the amazon Linux am
I gonna use everything as default and then we're going to leave everything here as default the only
thing that we are going to change is if we click on advance details in here we're going to run a bootstrap
script and a boot straps scripts simply runs at Route level and it executes commands in a chronological
order so let's have a look at our bootstrap scripts you can download this in the resources section of
the course bootstrap scripts always start with the shebang shebang is just the number and then an exclamation
mark and then this is the path to our interpreter.
So this is what's going to interpret all the commands that we do after this line so on line two.
We've got some in store Apache.
We're going to install PSP going to install pitch my sequel.
We're going to force it to install.
We're also then going to update the operating system where they're going to make sure Apache switches
on even if our easy to instance restarts we're then going to start the Apache service.
So it becomes a web server as soon as that service has started.
We're then going to create a little HP page which is just displaying hp hp info and then we're going
to output this child via dub dub dub.
Team El directory as index stop HP where they're going to go into that directory and then we're going
to go and get this little file which is a connect stop BHP file and that connect top HP file will look
just like this.
So it will say yes name a cloud guru password.
A cloud guru hostname.
And we're going to get the hostname when we go back into RDX and then we've got the database name a
cloud guru.
And in here this is the actual PSP to connect in to the secret database.
So basically it says connected to my sequel using username and then whatever the user name is password
whatever the password is and the host that the hostname.
And that's gonna be the ideas end point which we're going to supply later.
And so it will either stay connected to it or it will have an error message saying unable to connect
to my secret database check the database name and try again.
So that is all that we're going to do.
So let's grab this bootstrap script now if you just download it and open it up in your favorite text
editor we'll go back over to our Web browser just going to paste it in here and then I'm going to go
ahead and hit next to add my storage and I'm going to leave everything as default.
I'm gonna go ahead and hit next to add my tags.
I'm not gonna add any tags can configure my security group I'm going to do it to my existing one which
is my web DMC currently.
This just allows port HDB and each tick UBS over HPV for and HPV 6.
Gonna go ahead and hit review and launch and I'm gonna go ahead and launch my web server and I'm gonna
use my existing key pair which is called My new key pair and I'm gonna go ahead and launch that.
So that is now launching what I would do is probably just wait for five minutes and before we connect
into this you can however while you're waiting just go over to your ideas instance in here and we should
hopefully have our ideas instance ready.
So if we click on instances here it is a cloud guru and click in here get a nice little summary of all
my instances.
And here is my database end point.
So this end point is the DNS address.
You're never given an IP for address for your ideas instances you're always given a DNS address and
Amazon managed the mapping of that IP V4 address to this DNS address here.
And sorry I should be a little bit more specific when I say you're never given a IPTV for I mean a public
IP for address for your end point.
So copy that into your clipboard.
Let's go back over to services and go over to easy to you'll know that your bootstraps script has run
and is ready just by visiting the IP address.
So if you copy this IP address and open up a new tab and hit enter that will show this page.
So we've got our PSP info page so our web server is definitely up and running and ready to go.
All our scripts have finished installing and we're now ready to go in and configure our connection string.
So you need to go over to terminal now and we will go in and configure the connection strings so we
can connect to our ideas for instance.
Okay.
So here I am in my terminal window I'm just going to type SSA easy to hyphen user at.
And then I'm gonna paste in I've actually pasted this in from my web browser so I'm just going to remove
the DDP.
So now I've got the public IP address and then I'm going to do minus.
I think it's called my new key pair.
And go ahead and hit enter going to hit.
Yes.
And there we go.
Gonna elevate my privileges to root so pseudo Sue and I'm going to clear the screen and now I'm just
gonna go over to my bar dub dub dub HD here metal directory and I'm going to have a look in here.
We should have two documents we've got our connect up PSP we've got our indexed or PSP now indexed at
BHP was just the pitch IP info one that we saw that we created earlier with our little bash command
and then we did a W get to get this connect OP BHP.
So what I want to do now is I want to just open up my connect dot BHP to just type in nano connect dot
P HP and that will open it up and you can see we've got the user name a cloud guru we've got the password
a cloud guru hostname and then the db name a cloud guru is the only thing we need to do is update this
hostname to our ideas and point I'm just going to delete this out here and then I'm just gonna go back
over to the console and get my ideas standpoint point case I'm back in the console.
Just gonna go over to services and go down to two ideas under databases and a click in there and then
I'm going to click on my instances a cloud guru and I'm gonna scroll down and grab my instance end point
which is this one here and copy that into my clipboard.
Now let's go back over to our terminal window.
It's back in the terminal window.
I'm going to paste that in here.
So that is now my hostname.
What I'm gonna do is control X hit a yes to exit and then we're going to call it connect up p HP.
Now what you want to do is go back over to your web browser.
So I'm back in my web browser.
I'm gonna open this up and instead of going to the IP address I'm going to go to forward slash connect
dot P HP.
Now what this will do is it will hang for a little bit and eventually we're going to get an error message.
And the reason we're going to get an error message is there's still one last little thing that we need
to do.
When we created our RDX instance we created a security group inside that RDX instance and this is a
separate security group to what our easy two instances in.
So right now we've got two different pieces of the AWOL cloud in two different security groups and of
course they won't be able to talk to each other by default.
So he will need to go over to the basically to the security group section and we're going to need to
allow communication from one security group to another just going to wait for this to time out so you
can see the error message.
So I'm just going to pause the video and if you are patient enough to wait here you go.
Says unable to connect to my sequel.
So let's go have a look at how we can fix this.
We just click back over to this tab we can go over to our we can go over to our security groups which
is in here.
So we've got our security group in here.
We click on this security group that will launch us over to a security group sections.
It's going to close this.
So we've got our security group in here.
And what we want to do is we want to go ahead and we want to go to inbound and we want.
I'm just going to remove this filter so we can see all our security groups.
So what we want to do is we want to allow an inbound Security Group 4 3 3 0 6.
And we want it to allow this from our web server.
So we're going to go and click in here and we're going to go down to my circle which is port three three
or six.
Same with Aurora and in here what we can do is if we actually start typing SMG it will start to auto
populate and we want to wait list our web DMZ.
So whichever security group that you're web server is in some mines ending in 0 6 7 and that is it.
I'm gonna go ahead and hit save.
So can now see that rule down here.
If we go back over to this tab and if we hit refresh There we go.
Connected to my circle using username a cloud grew password a cloud guru host a cloud guru and then
it's the actual database endpoint so we have now successfully connected to our RDX instance we've connected
our easy to instance to our RDX instance.
So that is it for this lecture guys.
A common exam topic will be exactly what we just troubleshoot.
Troubleshoot it one way you've got an ac to instance in one security group and an IED incidents and
another security group and something's not connecting.
That's because you need to open up Pt. 3 3 0 6 to the security group that the RDX instances in.
You need to open up that to the security group where you're easy two instances in.
So hopefully that makes sense you go into the security group that you have your audience instance in
you open up my circle and you just point a you allow this security group that you're easy to instances
then to talk to your yes instance.
So that is it for this lecture guys in the next lecture we're going to look at a combination of multi
easy as well as read replicas and it's going to be a mixture of theory as well as hands on practical
lab.
So if you've got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.