Hello Clockers and welcome to this section of the course and this section is all about advanced identity
axis management and we're going to start with web identity Federation.
So what is web identity Federation.
Well it lets you give your users access to AWOS resources after they have successfully authenticated
with a web based identity provider like Amazon Facebook or Google.
Following successful authentication the user receives an authentication code from the web I.T. provider
which they can then trade for temporary AWOS security credentials which will then allow them to access
I ws resources.
So for example imagine that you are developing a web based application and you want to make it available
to Facebook uses.
You can actually use web identity Federation to handle the authentication of the users on your behalf
and may provide the service called Amazon cognito which enables web identity Federation with the following
features.
Firstly it gives you sign up and sign in to your applications.
It provides access for guest visas.
So it enables you to handle users who don't already have an account.
It acts as an identity broker between your application and web I.D. providers.
And that means you don't need to write any special code to integrate your application.
And the web identity provider it synchronizes use that data across multiple devices.
So for example if I access an application using my mobile phone I could change to my use data or my
profile data.
Next time I log into the same application and I'm using a tablet or a PC I should see the updates that
I made for my mobile phone.
So you should get a seamless experience across all different devices.
And finally cognito is recommended for all mobile applications which run on IWM services and cognito
is the recommended approach for weap identity Federation using social media accounts like Facebook Google
and also Amazon as well.
So just imagine a mobile shopping application and it's using S3 for product data and Dynamo IDB for
customer data and you want to enable customers to log in using Facebook and then to be able to access
the product data on their own profile data within the customer database.
So first of all they'll need to look into Facebook and after successfully logging into Facebook Facebook
will give them a web token and cognito it will take the Web token and exchange it for temporary AWOS
credentials.
And it's these temporary credentials which allow them the access that they need to see the contents
of your three pocket and also to request an update data in the database.
So a company toke brokerage between the application and Facebook or Google to provide these temporary
credentials and then it's these credentials which map to an identity access management role and its
role allows them access to the required resources.
So this means that there's no need for the application to embed any ws credentials and you don't need
to store credentials locally on the device on the mobile phone or the tablet.
And another benefit of cognito is that it can also give users a really seamless experience across all
mobile devices.
So you can logon using multiple different devices and you should get the same user experience no matter
what device you are using.
So let's take a look at some of our exam tips for web identity Federation.
Remember Federation allows users to authenticate with a web identity provider like Google Facebook or
Amazon.
They use a authenticates first with the web I.D. provider.
They then receive the authentication token which gets exchanged for temporary AWOS credentials allow
them to receive an identity crisis management low Kokanee to an identity Broca.
It handles the interaction between your applications and the web I.D. provider and you don't need to
buy any of your own code in order to do this.
It provides sign up sign in and guest user access sinks they use the data for a seamless experience
across all your devices and Kokanee is the AWOS recommended approach for web I.D. Federation particularly
for mobile applications.
So that's the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.