Hello Clockers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about cognito you suppose.
So let's get started.
So what are you.
Applause.
Well these are directory's which are used to manage sign up and sign in functionality for mobile and
web applications.
Users can sign in directly to the user pool or in directly for an identity provider like Facebook Amazon
or Google and Kokanee type acts as an identity broker between the ID provider and AWOS successful authentication
generates a number of Jason web tokens known as J.W. ttys and there's also this notion of identity pools
and identity PPO's enable you to create unique identities for your users and authenticate them with
identity providers and with an identity you can obtain temporary limited privilege AWOS credentials
to access other AWOS services.
So let's take a look at an example.
We call our user here.
And the first thing she does is she looks in via Facebook and receives her JWT tokens.
Then the cognito identity pool exchange is the JWT token for AWOS credentials.
And these are temporary credentials which she can then use to access AWOS resources and cognito handles
all this for you.
You don't have to write any special code for your application.
It manages receiving the JWT tokens from Facebook and the exchange of those tokens for AWOS credentials.
Cognito also tracks the association between user identity and the various different devices they sign
in from and in order to provide a seamless user experience for application.
Cognito uses a technology called Push synchronization to push updates and synchronize user data across
multiple devices Amerson S.A. or simple notification service is used to send a silent push notification
to all the devices associated with a given user identity.
Whenever data is stored in the cloud changes.
So what are the exam tips for cognito remember cognito use is use up polls to manage users sign up and
sign in either directly or via a web identity providers.
Think Facebook Amazon and Google.
It also acts as an identity broker handling all interaction with the web by dead sea providers and it
uses push synchronization with Asinus to send a silent push notification of use of data updates to multiple
device types associated with the same user ID.
So that is the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thankee.