Hello Clockers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be a lap and we are going to
be configuring a company to use a pool and we're going to take a look at the built in sign up and sign
in functionality provided by cognito which allows you to manage your users who need to sign into your
web applications and your mobile applications.
So if you've got time please join me in the U.S. consul.
So here I am in the AWOS consul and you'll find cognito and security identity and compliance.
So just click on cognito click on manage user polls and create a usable.
So the first thing we need to do is give it a name and I'm just going to call it test poll.
Click on review the votes and we can just keep to all of the defaults that you see here.
And there's various things that you can change and you can configure for yourself things like the password
length the policy you can enable multi-factor authentication but we can stick with the defaults.
I'm going to go ahead and click Create pool.
So that has been created successfully.
And I'm just going to scroll down to app clients and click on Add app client and the app client is what
we used to call the various IPs on our behalf.
For example the API to register a new user or to sign in a user so click on Add app client and we need
to give it a name.
I'm just going to call it my test client.
And once again just stick to the default.
So you should have generate secret selected.
So just click on Create a plant and now we need to configure the app.
So just click on uptalk settings and we need to enable an identity provider for all application.
And so just select Kokanee toat use a poll and then next thing we need to do is we need to configure
a Colback you Oreilles and a Colback QOL is really is just going to be the you RL that your users are
going to be redirected to after they have successfully signed in or signed up just for this demo.
We're going to use HTP s Fulwood slash example dot com.
So it's just going to be a dummy Web site but in reality if you have your own web application you could
use whichever Web site you want your users to land on.
Once they have signed into the application we don't need to configure us you around.
So I'm just going to leave that blank now.
And then under the oath to section I'm going to select the first two options.
So authorization code grants so that it's going to configure cognito to give you back an authorization
code which you can provide back to your to your backend authorization process and the implicit Graun
but just gives you the JWT token.
So that means when we go to test the configuration we'll be able to view that JWT token and under a
cloud.
Scope's I'm just going to select everything.
So the phone an e-mail that is just for user verification.
So when you first sign it sign up they'll send you an email just to get you to verify your e-mail is
correct.
And then we're going to select these three as well.
And if you're not familiar with o'th it is simply an open standard authentication framework and by selecting
all of these old scopes this is just going to grant access to the cognito API.
So all of the API operations like the sign in and sign up.
And also it's going to give us access to the JWT token that cognito will return.
You can learn more about the water flows and scopes.
If you click on this link here just open up in a new tab.
And it just takes you straight to the computer documentation so you can read all about that at your
leisure.
But it is out of sight for the exam you do not need to learn it for the exam.
So I'm just going to go ahead and click save changes then head over to domain name and we need to create
a domain prefix for Amazon company type domain and you can just make one up.
I'm just going to call it ICG test.
Click on check availability and if it's available then we can go ahead and site changes.
And this just applies this domain prefix to the cognito domain that it's creating for you.
And then the last thing I'm going to do is you customization so you can customize cognito or the look
and feel of the sign in and sign up page as you want so you can add a logo.
You can customize the labels the input fields text descriptions Banas et cetera et cetera.
So I'm just going to add a logo to all sign up page.
I'm just going to add the cloud good logo.
Select that file keep everything else as the default and click save.
So now we have configured everything we need for cognito.
So cognito is going to create a built in sign up and sign in page based on our configuration.
So let's test it and see if it's working.
So the first thing I'm going to do is go to app integration grab my cognito to my name.
Copy that to a new tab and just paste that.
But we need to add a few additional parameters as well in order to test this properly.
So I'm just going to type in slash in question mark and then response underscore type it ECOs token
because you want it to respond with a token then ampersand.
And clients underscore already equals they're going to come back to cognito go to my client settings
grepped my ID and don't worry.
There's quite a lot to type into the browser here but that will all be provided in the resources section
of the course.
The next thing we need to do is ampersand and redirect underscore you or I ECOs.
I'm just going to copy and paste it from my client's settings to make sure I spell it exactly the same.
You want to make sure this is really the same because if you accidently type it differently it's not
going to work.
And then I'm going to hit enter on if that's worked correctly for you.
This is what you should see.
And this is the sign up and sign in page that cognito has created for us and it's all completely in.
We don't have to write any of the code for this.
It's just all based on the options that we configured within all user poll.
And when we set up our app client so we don't have any users yet in on user poll.
So we need to create a new use us.
I'm just going to create a new account and I'm going to call it fe at my email address in Crais a password
and you'll see it's making sure that we adhere to the password policy then hit sign up and because we
were selected to send a verification code by email.
So it's going to send a verification code to the email address that I've used to sign up with.
So I'm just going to go and check my e-mail now.
And there's my e-mail with my verification codes just going to keep it up.
Come back to my site in page paste in the verification code and click confirm account.
So there we are we've signed in and it's taken me to the test domain the example to mine.
And if you look at the top of your browser you'll see the I.D. tokens are the JWT token that cognito
has generated for you.
Now if we go back to our use the pools go into users and groups hit refresh.
You should see the user that we just created and we think Kokanee you can also set up groups as well.
So you can go and you can create a group and you can also select an identity access management role
as well.
So for example you could select a role to give access to S-3 create that group and then you could actually
add users in.
So you can add your company to users into that group.
So you can actually build out groups of users within your cognito directory and you can assign them
an identity access management role associated with a specific cognito group.
So these roles can then be used to access AWOS services like files in S-3 dynamite Eby tables that kind
of thing.
And if we move down to Federation and click on identity providers you'll find the different identity
providers the cognito confederate with on your behalf as well.
So you've got Facebook Google Amazon Sammul which refers to any small compliant directories that could
be active directory for example and also open ID and configuring all of this is really beyond the scope
of the exam.
The main thing you really need to know is what is cognito a high level.
So just remember it allows you to manage user identity for your mobile and web applications integrates
with Facebook Google Amazon and other identity providers.
And is the recommended approach for users sign up and sign in for mobile applications.
So that is the end of this lab.
If you'd like to delete all of your cognito sets up the first thing you need to do is delete your domain.
So just go ahead and delete that domain.
And then once you've done that it will allow you to go to general settings and then you can delete your
pool as well.
So that's the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank ye.