Like lurkers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about in line managed and custom policies
within identity access management.
So let's get started now.
Identity access management is used to define user access permissions within AWOS and we've used.
I am a lot throughout this course.
Now there are three different types of policies available.
Firstly manage policies then customer manage policies.
And finally in line policies.
So let's take a look at those three different policies in a little bit more detail now.
A managed policy is an eye and policy which was created and administered by AWOS and they provide managed
policies for really common use cases based on job function.
So for example don't MIDP full access code commit power user.
Easy to read only access etc. and we've used these roads many times throughout the Lap's that we've
done so for example when we've created an easy to instance needs to create or query a tiny IDB table.
We use that Dynamo ODP full access managed policy in combination with a service role to give our easy
to instance access to the Dhanam IDB tables and these ws provided policies allow you to assign appropriate
permissions to your users groups and rows without having to write the policy yourself and the policies
are all written in Jason.
Are all fairly complex and comprehensive.
So it just takes away that heavy lifting of creating a policy yourself.
And a single managed policy can be attached to multiple users groups or rows within the same IWM accounts
and across different accounts.
But there's one important thing to know about the Mohnish policies is that you cannot change the permissions
defined in an AWOS managed policy.
Moving on to customer managed policies and a customer managed policy is a standalone policy that you
create and administer inside your own AWOS account you can attach this policy to multiple uses groups
and rows but only within your own account and to create a customer manage policy you can take a copy
of an existing AWOS manage policy just copy the gyse on code and customize it to fit the requirements
of your organization.
And this is recommended for use cases where existing AWOS manage policies don't quite meet the needs
of your environment.
Finally we have policies and an in line policy is an identity access management policy which is actually
embedded within the user group or role to which it applies.
And there's a strict once one relationship between the entity and the policy that means you cannot attach
an inline policy to multiple users groups or rows.
And when you delete the user group or role in which the inline policy is embedded the policy will also
be deleted.
Now in most cases AWOS recommends using managed policies over inline policies.
However they are useful when you want to be sure that the permissions in a policy are not inadvertently
assigned to another user group or role than the one for which they are intended.
For example if you're creating a policy which must only ever be attached to a single user group or row
for security or technical reasons and if you come into the WS console you can take a look at the different
types of policy that are available.
So scroll down to identity access management click on policies and you can filter based on policy type
and it's showing me either customer managed or AWOS manage.
So first let's take a look at my customer managed policies and these are the different policies that
I have created myself.
And if you go into these policies you can actually edit the policy and actually change the Jason code
that makes up the policy.
So I'm just going to click.
So go back to my policies and click on AWOS managed and you can see they provide lots of different managed
policies for various different types of access.
So depending on whether you need Read-Only or full access or down to administrative access and they
give you lots of different policies for all different types of services.
And the interesting thing about these policies is if I select one it's not going to let me edit it so
I cannot change this just on code.
And that's the important thing to remember about a managed policy does not give you the option to edit.
And in fact it says down here on the bottom right hand side it says read only.
So let's go back to my dashboard.
And I don't actually have any inline policies at the moment but let's go ahead and create one so if
I go to my user and because it's an in non-policy and it is associated with either a user group or role
you have to be in the User Group or role in order to actually create the policy.
So if you go into a user you will see this option here to add an non-policy.
So we're just going to choose a service and we're going to add a policy for Athena and I'm going to
add right access for Athena click on review.
Give it a name
and click on create policy.
And that is my in line policy and it will show here as being an in line policy.
And if I want to for example create a new user I'm not going to call my user ropa going to give programmatic
access next and I'm going to try and add that in line policy and if I try to search for that policy
it doesn't come up in only my customer managed policies come up a filter based on in policies.
I've only have the choice of either the customer managed or the WS managed.
So let's take a look at exam tips for the three different types of I am policy.
Just remember the managed policy is the AWOS managed default policy like Dynamite's be full access et.
The customer manage policy is one managed by you created by you and managed by you and you can apply
it to multiple users groups or rows and the inline policy is managed by you.
But it's embedded in a single user group or row.
And there is a one to one relationship between the line policy and the user group or row to which they
are embedded.
And finally in most cases I ws recommends using their own banish'd policies over in line policies.
Well that's the end of this lecture.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move onto the next lecture.
Thank you.