Hello bloggers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is all about SARS and the assume role with
web identity API.
So let's get started.
So what is assume a role with web identity.
Well it's an API which is provided by S T S. which is the security token service and it returns temporary
security credentials for users which have been authenticated by either a mobile or web application using
a web identity provider like Amazon Facebook or Google.
And of course for mobile phone applications they recommend Cockney toe and underneath Cockney toe is
actually making the SD as you roll with web identity calls on your behalf.
So when you use Cockney Toad you don't explicitly need to use this API.
However for regular web applications where you're not using Cockney so you can use this sd s assume
role with web identity API.
So let's take a look at an example workflow and we have our user on the left hand side here and she's
going to authenticate using Facebook Google or Amazon.
And once she's successfully authenticated the web I.D. provider passes back a JWT token to the application.
The application then makes the assume role with web identity API call to SDF and as part of that API
call it provides the JWT token SDF then exchanges the JWT token for temporary credentials so an access
key and secret access key.
Finally the application can use those temporary credentials to access a W resources.
For example dynamo DB tables or the contents of an S3 bucket.
So let's take a look at a sample response that you might see when your application makes a call to assume
a role with web identity.
Now the main two things that you need to know about the sample response are that firstly it responds
with this assumed role user a R N and the assumed role I.D. and both of these are simply a R and or
Amazon resource.
Name identifiers and these can be used if you want to refer programmatically to the temporary credentials.
So if your application code needs to later on refer to the temporary credentials.
These are the identifiers that it's going to use and it can be a little bit confusing because it's referring
to roles and I.D. It's nothing to do with identity access management roles.
Just remember it's the specific a or an identifier that you can use to programmatically refer to the
temporary credentials and then the next section that I've highlighted is the credentials themselves.
So you get a session token and then you get a secret access key and access key and these are temporary
and by default they're only going to last for one hour before they expire.
There's an expiration time stamp included as well.
So let's take a look at some of our exam tips for assume role with web identity.
Just remember it's part of the security token service.
It allows users who have authenticated with a web identity provider like Facebook Google or Amazon to
access a resources temporarily.
Once the user has authenticated with the Web I.D. provider the application then makes the assume role
with web identity API call.
And if it's successful SPSS will return temporary credentials enabling access to a W US resources.
And just remember this assumed role user a R N and the assumed role I.D. those are used to programmatically
reference the temporary credentials.
They're not related to an identity management role or user they are simply a are NS used to programmatically
reference the credentials.
So that is everything that you should need to know for the exam about assume role with web identity.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.