Hello and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is the advanced identity access management summary.
So it's the end of this section of the course and it's going to be a summary and exam tips for advance
identity access management.
So let's get started.
Remember identity Federation allows users to authenticate with a web identity provider.
So I think Google Facebook or Amazon they use the authenticates first with the web I.D. provider.
They then receive an authentication token which is then exchanged for temporary AWOS credentials allowing
them to assume an identity access management role.
And the I AM role allows them to access AWOS resources company.
So it's an I.T. Poca and it handles the interaction between your applications and the web provider.
So you don't need to write your own code to do this.
It provides sign up sign in and Guest User Access and syncs user data for a seamless experience across
multiple devices and company tohe is the recommended approach for web I.T. Federation.
So if you see any exam questions asking you which technology to use if you want to authenticate your
applications against a web identity provider like Facebook Google or Amazon if there's any questions
around that asking you which is the best technology.
Well Coquito is the recommended approach particularly for mobile applications and cognito use is use
suppose to manage users sign up and sign in either directly to the user pool or via the web identity
provider.
And it uses push synchronization to send a silent push notification via As an as simple notification
service of use updates to multiple device types.
So your mobile phone tablet and laptop for example all associated with your user ID.
So in our example we had our user authenticating against a user poll which then receives JWT tokens.
So gyse on web tokens from the web.
Identity providers like Facebook Google or Amazon the company identity so then exchanges the JWT tokens
for AWOS credentials which enables the user to temporarily access AWOS resources.
For example S-3 IDB RDX easy to etc..
Moving on to inline policies managed policies and custom policies.
Remember the three different types of I and policy.
So we have the managed policy and this is the AWOS managed default policies so the ones that we can
search for when we go to create a role or when we want to assign a policy to a user group or row.
And these are the policies like Don MIDP full access code deploy full access S-3 full access et cetera.
And these can be assigned to any number of users groups or rows across AWOS the customer manage policy.
So thats for any policy that is not catered for by the managed policy you can create your own and its
managed by you and it can be attached to multiple users groups or rows.
And then finally there's the in line policy and that is managed by you and embedded within a single
user group or.
So it's a one to one mapping between the policy and the entity to which it's embedded.
And when you delete the user group or row the policy is also deleted.
And in most cases I ws recommends using managed policies over inline policies.
So that is the end of this lecture.
And that's the end of the section.
So well done for completing the section if you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.