Hello Clockers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is called Identity access management.
One on.
And I am is the best place to start with AWOS because it's all about setting up your uses and granting
those users access to the IWM.
So let's get started.
So what is I am.
Well essentially I am allows you to manage uses and also manage that level of access to the AWOS console
and it's really important to understand I am and how it works both for the exam and for administrating
companies I ws account in real life.
So what does I am give you.
It gives you centralized control over your AWOS account.
It also gives you shared access to AWOS account.
It gives you granular permissions.
So this means you can enable different levels of access to different users within your organization
it enables identity federation including with Active Directory Facebook and linked in etc..
So this means it can enable users to log in using credentials stored in an Active Directory Facebook
or linked in.
It allows multi-factor authentication and this is where a user is granted access only after successfully
completing multiple independent authentication mechanisms.
So for example providing a username and password as one authentication mechanism and then providing
a software token site that could be via a token generator like Google authenticator as the second authentication
mechanism.
It also provides temporary access for users or devices and services as necessary.
So for example if you developed a web or mobile phone application you can configure identity access
management to enable users to have temporary access to AWOS resources within your account for example
to enable access to store or retrieve data located in an Esrey packet or within a dynamo D-B database.
It allows you to set up your own password rotation policy it integrates with many different IWM services
and it supports PCI DSS compliance for any applications associated with the payment card industry.
So there are some cool concepts that you need to understand before going into the exam.
So first of all we have users.
So this is the end users and just think people say these are the people logging into the AWOS Consolo
and also interacting with AWOS by running IP like commands.
We didn't have groups which are collections of users grouped together with a common set of permissions.
So for example your marketing team might need access to read and write certain files stored in an S3
bucket and that might be logos or images et cetera and they're going to need a specific set of permissions
to allow them to do this.
So it makes sense to create a group with the required permissions and then all you need to do is add
the relevant users into that group and they will all have permissions to read us three buckets.
And similarly you might have a database administration's team and they need to create Modibo tables
and run queries on the database.
So in that case you can create a group with the relevant permissions for Dynamo IDB and then add all
of your database admins into that group.
And we also have roles.
Now you can create rows and then assign them to AWOS resources.
So a role is used to define a set of commissions for example S-3 bucket access and then that role could
be assumed by either uses or AWOS services such as AC too.
So you might have an easy to instance which needs to query a database or access files in S-3 and you
can configure that using a road.
And finally we have policies and a policy is a document that defines either one or more commissions
and a policy can be attached to either a user group or role.
And when we attach a policy the user group or row will then have the permissions defined within that
policy.
And it's possible for a user group and wrote to all share the same policy.
So the quickest way to learn Identity Crisis management is actually to start using it.
And that's what we're going to do right now.
So if you've got time please join me in the next lecture which is an identity access management lab.
Thank you.