Hello Clockers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be an identity access management
lab.
So we're going to configure our user account.
We're going to set up multi-factor authentication and we're going to create a first user group and set
up a role as well.
So you're going to need to log into the IWM console.
So if he got time please join me in the console.
Here I am in the console and this is a brand new AWOS account that I've set up specifically for this
lab.
So it has not been used before.
When you first walk into the console you'll notice that there's a few different wizards here.
There's also some tutorials and videos here some of which are free.
Then if you come to the top of the screen on the right hand side you'll notice that we have a list of
different regions here.
And normally the best thing to do is select the region that is closest to you.
So I'm located in London.
So London is my closest region.
And that's the one I generally try to use either that Orlando Frankfurt.
And they're all very fast for London.
However when they launch a brand new service in WS they don't launch it to every single region at the
same time.
So you may find that if you're looking at my screen certain services that appear on my screen that don't
appear in your screen.
And the reason for that could be that if you're in a different region it may be that that service is
not yet available in your region and generally when they launch into service it normally gets launched
to us East which is the North Virginia region.
Generally that's the place where they launch the new services that get lost that first and then overtime
it later on gets made available throughout the other regions.
So if you see something on your screen that you're expecting to see or that you can see on my screen
the best thing to do is simply change regions and see if you can point to in another region.
So let's get started with identity access management and the first thing I'm going to do is come to
the top left of the screen and click on services and you'll see there are loads of different services
provided within AWOS and identity access management comes under security identity and compliance.
So go ahead and click on I am and the first thing that you should see is a splash screen similar to
this.
Welcome to identity access management.
It also shows you a site in Menke and this number here is your customer account number and it's a personalized
link that you can use to log into the console.
And if you want to you can actually customize it to make a much more friendly you or else I'm going
to go ahead and see if I can customize this.
I'm just going to call mine a cloud guru Fay and see if I can use that name yet.
So that is changed my sign in link.
So next time I want to look into the console I can just simply use that link instead and it will take
me straight to my console and we can say here on the I am resources that we don't have any users groups
or policies or rows or identity providers created and in the security status section they give you this
checklist of the minimum kind of security baseline that they recommend you apply to every single account
and the first one is delete your access case.
With that they've already done that for you.
The second one is to activate multi-factor authentication on your router account.
So that means to enable another level of authentication beyond the username and password that you use
to log into your account with the next step would be to create individual identity axis management uses.
Because we don't want everyone within our organization to be logging into AWOS using the root account.
It's best practice to only use that account when you really really need to when there's no other way
to do the tasks that you're trying to do.
Instead you'll want to restrict access to your users and only gives them access they need to do that
job.
So we would create individual identity access management uses them to a relevant group and assign permissions
on a group by great basis according to the job function that your users are doing.
For example your database administrator is my only need access to the databases running in a W-S and
your teams might need access to certain S-3 buckets within ws whereas your systems administrators would
again need a completely different level of access and we'd need access to administer various resources
within a WS.
So it's best practice to create individual user accounts for your users then group them into logical
groups.
For example our database administration systems administration etc. and then assign the relevant permissions
to each of those groups on a group by group basis.
And then the final thing it advises you to do is to apply a password policy.
So that's all about password complexity and lifecycle management as well.
So let's go ahead and activate multi-factor authentication on our account.
So if you click on the arrow here the then click on manage MFA and there's two different types of MFI
device.
But we're going to use the virtual MFA device make sure that one is selected and click on next.
And now to activate the MFA device you first need to install an MFA compatible application and we normally
install that on a smartphone PC or other device and you can find a list of the MFH compatible applications.
If you click this link here so let's just click on that
scroll down and the supported virtual MFI applications.
There's a few different ones supported for Android iPhone Windows phone and BlackBerry.
But I have an iPhone so I'm going to be using Google authenticator.
So depending on which device you're using download the relevant MFA application and then come back to
the console.
So once you've downloaded the relevant MFA application just click on next step and then it will show
you this QR code which you need to scan using the MFA application on your device.
So on my phone here I'm going to select scan barcode and it gives me the six digit authentication code
which I need to type in my web page
and then I need to wait until that code expires and it's going to give me another code.
And there it is.
And I'm just going to type it in here.
And click activate and you should get this message that the MFA device is successfully associated.
So now if that was successful you should have a green tick next to your activate MFA on account.
And if it was successful and you don't see the green tick just refresh the browser on that quintic should
show up.
So the next thing we're going to do is create some identity access management eases.
So click on users on the left hand side
click on Add user and again to create a user code Fe and there's two different ways to access AWOS.
The first access type is programmatic and this enables access using the AWOS API come online interface
and developing toolkit as well.
And we call that programmatic access.
This is how applications will access AWOS and it's also how you can access the command line on your
local machine.
So I'm going to select programmatic access it and then the second method of accessing AWOS is by the
console.
And that's what we're doing right now.
So I'm going to select console access as well.
And I'm going to keep the default to an auto generated password for the console and also require a password
reset when the user looks in.
So just keep those last two to the default and click on next and now it's asking us to set permissions
for our new user.
So we've got a choice of how we can actually set these permissions.
Firstly we can add user to a group so if we had groups already existing We could add them to an existing
group or we can create a new group we can copy permissions from an existing user.
And also we can attach permissions directly to the user.
But for now we're just going to go ahead and create groups or click on create great and we need to give
our group a name and I'm going to call the group this admin
and then next thing it's asking us to do is to add a policy and it's these policies which define the
permissions that are going to be granted to the group.
So this is going to be osseous Hopman group.
I'm just going to search for Azmin and there's a whole load of default policies that you can choose
from.
So let's have a look at the administrator access policy and if you click on this arrow and click on
Jason and you can actually look at the Jason code which makes up the policy.
So we've got a version on an underneath that a statement and then the effect of the policy which is
to allow and then action is everything.
So that means you can run any action on any resource.
So basically this is giving the user full access to AWOS and he can take a look at all of these policies
or look at the permissions that they give you.
So if you click on the arrow select make sure Tyson is selected and you can look at the the Jason code
and it's really just a key value pair so you can see for example in this policy allows you for cloud
trial to list the tags Look-Up events for code commit it allows you to do a poll and a get push etc..
So I'm just going to go back into administrator access make sure that that is selected and click on
Create group.
So that's our group created.
We've attached our policy.
I'm going to review and this just shows us all of the choices that we've selected so we've got my user
with poker Matic and console access with an auto generated password requiring a reset on first logon
and our user is going to be a member of this admin group and by default they're also going to be giving
this permission to change their password.
So let's go ahead and create the user so a user has been created.
We can also say that I've been given this access key and say access Kate.
And if we click on show it show was that secret access came on this access key and Secret Access Key
are needed when we lock in using the command line interface.
So when we want to interact programmatically with AWOS we can only do that using the access key and
seek access key whereas if we want to log into the console that's when we would use our username and
password.
And it's really important to remember that the only time you get to see the same access key is when
you first create the user and we move away from this page we might be able to see the secret access
key again and you can download it as a CSJ so you can download it and keep it on your machine keep it
somewhere safe.
Because if we lose this secret access key We're going to have to regenerate it.
That's really important to know.
And it's also important to remember the difference between access and seek 6K and name and password.
So let's go ahead and hit close.
So now I'm going to go in and create another user and this user are going to call John the guy and give
him programatic and console access and click on next I'm going to add him to the same.
It's this great.
Click on review and create Eiza
and close.
Now John he is going to work for the H-L team I'm going to create a new group called H.
So he can create great Nicollet Shaw click on next.
Anthropology type.
Now the whole team we're going to give them access to S-3 to read files in S-3.
So for policy type I'm just going to search for a policy containing S-3 and we've got one here S-3 read
only access.
So I'm going to select the next step and create group.
So now we've got two groups.
We've got one for say submarines giving them full access within AWOS and there's two users who are members
of that group.
And we've also got our second group called H R with read only access to S-3 and then the next thing
I'm going to do is I'm going to add John into my group so I'm going to go back to John and click on
his name.
Click on groups.
Add use to groups and then select our H.R. group and click add to two groups.
And I can also hear if I want I can delete him from the CCBN group.
I'm going to do that because he's not a systems administrator.
He works for H.R. So we're going to take that position away.
Click on remove from group
and if we go back to permissions
and click on Add permissions for John we can also add permissions directly to John.
Without it being on a per group basis.
So for example let's say he needs to specifically access Lycia because he's in charge of archiving as
well in our company.
So let's click on at existing policies directly and search for Lycia are we going to give him Lycia
full access.
Click on next and at permissions and then in the summary for John we can say that he has Amazon glacé
a full access which we've attached directly and then he also has this S-3 read only access which is
attached by the group.
So if we go back 12 dashboard we can say we've got four out of five ticks here.
And then the last thing we need to do is apply and identity excess management password policy.
So if we click on then click on manage password policy and here is where we can set up a password policy.
And this is simply a set of rules defining the type of password.
And I am using of set so we can define the minimum password length.
So I'm going to change that at 12.
We can set it to require at least one up uppercase letter one lower case letter one number.
We can set password expiration in a period of days so we can set it to expire after 90 days.
So whatever password policy you have within your organization you should be able to reflect that here
within AWOS as well.
So then just click on apply password policy and then if we go back to our dashboard We've got five green
ticks now the last thing we're going to do here is we're going to create a roll click on Rose
and I am rose or a secure white to grant permissions to entities that you trust.
And the examples they give are and I am used in another account application code running on an easy
to instance that needs to perform actions on AWOS resources and be a service that needs to act on resources
in your account to provide its features
and uses from a corporate directory who's you who are using identity federation with Sammo.
So we don't need to worry about that last one.
That's something that we're going to revisit in a little bit more detail later on in the course
but right now we're going to create a roll allowing an easy to instance to write files to S-3.
So let's click on Create role and we need to select the AWOS service that we want to create the profile.
So make sure AWOS service is selected choose the service that the role will use.
And we're going to select easy to click on next.
And now from the default policies we need to search for a policy relating to S3.
So just type as 3 in the search box
and I'm going to select as three full access and this will give any easy to instance which has this
role attached.
We'll have full access to S-3.
So I'm going to go ahead and click on next gif or roll a name
and click on Create row.
So now we've created that row we're going to be able to apply that row to an any new E.S. to instance
that we create and if we go back to the dashboard we can say we've got two uses two grapes and we got
one roll.
So that's all we're going to do with I am at the moment but you're going to be using it quite a bit
throughout the course.
So you're going to become very familiar with I am.
As you progress throughout the course
and that's the end of this lecture.
So if you have any questions please let me know.
If not please feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.