Hello Cocker's and welcome to this lecture and this lecture is going to be a summary of identity axis
not a human one.
I won.
So we're going to cover off everything that we've learnt and also are going to be telling you some of
the exam tips that we have for the section as well.
So let's get started.
So what if we don't so far identity access management consists of uses groups browes policy documents
and if you remember the lab we created a couple of uses.
We also created a couple of groups and we use those groups to apply permissions policies to those uses.
And we also applied policies directly to the uses and we have an example of a policy document here written
in Jason and the document is written as a series of key value pairs.
So under the version we don't have the statement The effect is allow and the action is to allow all
actions across all resources.
So this policy document would give full access to everything within us.
And then finally in our lab we also created a role and we created a role which can be used by an EASY
TO instance to allow access to read and write files within S-3 since the access management is universal.
It doesn't apply to regions at this time.
So what does that mean.
It just means that identity access management is global and anything you set up within I am can be viewed
and utilized by any region.
The root account is simply the account you created when you first set up your AWOS account.
So that's the email address that you used when you first registered your account with AWOS and it has
complete admin access.
So of course for day to day activities we shouldn't be using the root account.
Instead we should be creating identity access management uses and making sure those users have the permissions
and privileges they need to do their jobs.
New users have no permissions at all when they first created.
So we need to explicitly ask the permissions they need to do their role.
For example in the lab we added commissions for S-3 and glazier for our H.R. user to enable them to
access those AWOS services.
New users are assigned the Access Key ID and seek access key when the very first created and these are
not the same as a username and password.
You can't use the access key and secret access key to log into the WS console but you can use it access
AWOS for the API and come online interface from your local desktop and you only get to view and download
the file containing your access key and secret access key.
One time when you initially create them and after that you can still view the access key but you cannot
view the secret access key again.
So if you lose your secret access key you're going to need to regenerate ukase.
So to make sure that you save your secret access key in a safe location always sets up multi-factor
authentication.
Or if a on your root account and that's another thing that we did in the lab.
And finally you can create and customize your own password rotation policies.
So that's the end of this section.
Well done for completing the section.
If you have any questions please let me know.
Otherwise please join us in the next lecture.
Thank you.