AK helicopters and welcome to this lecture So hopefully you're learning an awful lot in the course so
far and you're starting to understand how complicated AWOS is now Harry Cleetus of a faceless was an
ancient Greek philosopher and he once famously said everything changes and Nothing stands still.
And as you start learning AWOS you going to realize how much it changes all of the time.
There's literally thousands of new product updates and releases each year and can be really really hard
to keep up.
And we have a web series called AWOS this week which is basically a weekly show discussing all the new
updates to AWOS for the week.
It's five minutes or less so when won't take a lot of your time.
We have an explain it like High-Five approach of something really complicated comes out we'll try and
break it down and help you understand what it is and what it means to you as either solutions architect
a developer This admin or a business leader or whatever it is whatever role that do.
So the best way to stay up to date with AWOS and all the constant changes.
The link is below the on our YouTube channel where you can subscribe through the A Calgary Web site.
It is seriously the best way to stay up to eight of us.
And like I said it's five minutes or less each week.
So make sure you check it out and kipping awesome let's go into the next lecture.
Thank you.