KLA cloggers Welcome to the very last lecture.
In the course hopefully you've really enjoyed it and you've learnt an awful lot.
It is now ready to book your exam.
So let's go ahead and have a look how you can do that.
OK so here I am at the AWOS training landing page.
So the address is just AWOS dot training.
And I want you to click up here and go sign in then ask you to sign in using your credentials so I'm
just going to do that now.
So I've now signed in I'm just going to go over to certification and click up here then I'm going to
click AWOS certification account and in here it's launched me into my AWOS certification account.
You can see here.
So all I need to do now is go over to Szechwan you exams.
They used to be to assessment bodies webisodes the old one PSII is the new one you want to do it through
PSII but just go ahead and hit should you and your exam you can't do it through Websense or any more
it will redirect you to the pier side training site and you can see here you can go ahead and shed all
your exams.
So here is the A.W. a certified developer associate.
Do you read it carefully.
There will be one that says for the 2018 this is actually the old one.
And eventually they'll get rid of this one entirely.
So go ahead and hit Cheryl your exam and you should be able to find an exam center near you and show
use your exam.
So really really good luck.
So once you pause please I've learned the difficult feelings in an attack.
And this just lets us know how many people are pulsing and so that we can congratulate you or you can
also tweet us the ticket and tag us.
You can also actually upload your certificate to the A Calgary phone.
This will unlock your badges and it will also allow you to show off your certificates to other uses.
So what are the next steps.
Well there are still the solutions architect associate if you haven't already done it.
Assistants administrators are shit.
I would recommend doing those too before going on and trying something like solutions architect professional.
We also have the specialty certificate so we've got security at big data or events networking the certificate
of follows directly after the developer associate certificate is dev ops.
So soon as you pass your developer or associate you will be able to go and sit the developer.
I would recommend however that you do sit ups administrators sociate first before going on to doing
the Devil's prayer.
If you're sick of that's vacations check out all platforms other great content including release Rudi's
may collapse and AWOS this week.
Yes remember that getting certified is just the first step in your journey to cloud AWOS changes all
the time and there are other clouds out there like as you and Google.
So it's really important to keep up and a great way to keep up on the go is by getting our mobile app.
It's available on the Apple app store as well as the Google Play store.
You'll be able to go ahead and watch all our content and you'll be able to download it and watch it
online so you don't need an internet connection.
We really hope you enjoyed the course.
We've had lots of fun teaching you we hope to see you in one of our other courses so keeping all somehow
yours.