OK.
Hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture this lecture is on simple queue service or Eskew.
And if you remember from the history lecture where we're talking about the history of AWOS this was
the first ever AWOS service that was publicly available.
So this is the oldest AWOS service now where this comes up in the exam is you need to understand what
obscurest is at a very high level and then you need to understand various different components of it
and it makes sense that this is in the exam because it is the oldest AWOS service.
So what is Eske us.
Well it's a web service that gives you access to a message queue that can be used to store messages
while waiting for a computer to process them as cueist is a distributed queue system that enables web
service applications to quickly and reliably queue messages that one component in the application generates
to be consumed by another component.
AQ is a temporary repository for messages that are awaiting processing.
So all that sounds a bit complicated Don't worry.
The easiest way to learn what Eskew excuse is is by looking at an example.
So let's say you've got a Web site that generates main's.
So hey you know you've got your user and they want to upload a photo.
So let's say we want to turn this into a main.
So we're going to upload this to a Web site and that a Web site might store this photo in S-3.
Now as soon as that's finished uploading that might trigger a lambda function.
And what lambda does is basically it sends all the data about this particular image to ask us.
So what kind of data.
Well it's going to send the data as to what's the top of the Maime should say what the bottom of the
Mayme should say.
It might give date her about the S3 bucket location so which S3 bucket has it been uploaded to.
It might pass state her around the user et cetera.
And this sits in Eske us as a message while it's waiting to be processed.
Then you might have a fleet of two instances.
And what they do is they poll the rescue rescue looking for messages looking for jobs to do essentially
think of obscurest as yet basically a way of assigning jobs.
It's like you put a job into the rescue rescue then you see two instances when they're ready constantly
poll that Hugh looking for work.
And so they find this message and then.
OK great.
I'm going to create the main So I'm going to encode it.
So here it is.
It says Hello cloud jurors and it then stores the two instance then writes that to the same as bucket.
Or it could write it to a different S-3 bucket and then once it's finished that job it goes back to
the rescue rescue again and looks for work looks for jobs to do.
And you can actually have auto scaling groups that sit behind us so that automatically scales based
off the rescuers.
Q So how many messages are in the queue could trigger you provisioning more and more easy to instances.
Now the great thing about this is that if you lose any C-2 instance you're not going to lose that job
it's still going to sit in the cueist.
Q And another AC to instance can go in and pick that up and we'll talk about that in a couple of slides
from now.
So to give you another example think of a travel Web site might be something like Skyscanner or Google
flights or something and basically or go out and scan a whole bunch of different airlines and get you
the best deal.
And if you if you actually work at Skyscanner.
Big shout out to you guys they use you all the time.
So here we are we've got our user and they looking for a holiday.
They want a package holiday and they want to get the best possible flights so they type a query into
their browser.
This then hits in the C-2 instant.
So these are easy to web servers.
And essentially what they do is they take what the user is looking for and they put package that up
as a message in and ask us.
Q The q then gets polled by in these two incidents so by polling its polling the message is down and
this is really key because some exam questions will say that you need a pool based system rather than
a push based system.
ESC is always a broad based system if you want to use a push based system you use something like simple
notification services which we're going to cover off in a couple of lectures.
So you've got your AC two instances here.
They constantly polling the rescue queue looking for messages looking for a job to do.
They could then get that job and they process it and they say OK this user wants to fly from London
to lay eggs so to L.A. for example let's go and interrogate all the you know the airline's servers as
to what the best flights are.
Once it's got this information it then sends that back to the web server who sends it back to the user.
And then they use chooses the best flights for his or her budget or his or her needs.
You know I hate flying out really really early in the morning I like to fly out at like 9:30 or something
like that.
So I want you to think about this if we didn't have ask us and let's say the web server passed the information
of to an application server.
The application server then queried the airline's servers.
And let's say that application server crashes what's going to happen will your user is going to lose
that queery great thing about Ask us is that if that application server crashed the message will still
be in the queue it'll be marked as invisible.
And this is called the visibility timeout window.
But as soon as that timeout runs out that message will appear in the queue again and essentially another
application server will pick that message up and process that job.
So that's the great thing about rescuer's is you're removing dependencies it's a great way of decoupling
your infrastructure.
So using ex-U.S. you can decouple the components of an application so that they run independently and
with the rescuers easing message management between components any component of a distributed application
can store messages in a file say queue messages contain up to 256 kilobytes of text in any format so
you can have Jason you can have XM now you can have it plaintexts whatever any component can then later
retrieve the messages programmatically using the cueist API.
Dequeue acts as a buffer between the components producing and saving the data and the component receiving
the data for processing.
This means the queue resolves issues that arise if the producer is producing work faster than the consumer
can process it.
So you think about that.
The great thing about this is let's say you've only got two E.S. two instances that are polling the
cueist Q And suddenly getting a ton of messages.
What you can do is you can configure auto scaling groups to monitor the SU rescue and if it goes over
a certain number of messages let's say it goes over 10 messages in the queue.
You then can start provisioning additional E.C two instances to process the messages in that queue.
Likewise you can have cooldowns say the number of messages in the queue drops down to 1.
Maybe And they want to have one easy to instance so you can build auto scaling in with this.
So this basically brings to city to your application.
And so let's move on.
So there are two different types of queues.
The standard queues and now there's FIFO queues and FIFO queues actually only just came out last year.
So it's not a standard to use US office standard as the default queue type.
So by default all queues would be a standard queue and extended queue lets you have nearly unlimited
number of transactions per second.
They guarantee that the messages get delivered at least once.
However occasionally because of the highly distributed architecture that allows high throughput more
than one copy of the message might be delivered out of order so stand accused don't have any kind of
order to them.
They provide best effort order adding which ensures that messages are generally delivered in the same
order as they are sent.
But they can't be guaranteed.
OK FIFO queues however do guarantee exactly that.
So first in first out the messages will be delivered be sent and received in the order in which they
arrive.
So the order in which the messages are sent and received strictly preserved and a message is delivered
once and remains available until consumer processes and deletes that duplicates are not introduced to
the queue so Faith queues also support message groups that allow multiple or message groups within a
single queue.
Another thing to note about FIFO queues is that they are limited to 300 transactions per second.
They have all the same capabilities of standard TOS.
Typically you're going to be asked around standard TOS and really where are you going to be quizzed
on.
Is just understanding what they ask us is at a high level and then these key facts are always remember
that Eskew is a poll based not a pushed based system messages 256 kilobytes in size.
Messages can be kept in the queue from one minute all the way up to 14 days and the default is four
days and then visibility's time out is the amount of time that the message is invisible in the U.S..
Q After a reader picks it up so we put a message in the queue.
And then the two instance pulls that message down and has a job so it might be to create a Maime it
might be to go and query the airline and so that message is still in the US.
Q But it's invisible now provided the job is processed before the visibility timeout expires.
The message will then be deleted from the queue if the job is not process within that time the message
will become visible again and another read a will process it.
This could result in the message being delivered twice.
So if you have your visibility timeout to let's say 1 minute.
But the job that it's doing is something.
Let's say it's doing some big data analytics or something like that.
What you know what's going to happen is the message is going to come back into the queue because it's
going to take over a minute.
Let's say it takes five minutes to actually process that big data.
The message is going to become visible in the queue I should say not come back to the cube but it's
going to come visible in the queue.
And then another easy to instance will pick that up so you could be delivering your messages multiple
times because your visibility timeout is too low.
So you got to think about that when architecting you know your applications.
And then finally the visibility timeout maximum is 12 hours so you can only you know the 12 hours is
the configuration maximum.
So if something is going to take over 12 hours then executes is probably not a good choice for you because
you're going to be delivering messages multiple times as cueist guarantees that your messages will be
processed at least once.
However you have to bear this in mind when architecting could be pro-ISIS a couple of times especially
if your visibility's timeout is lower than the amount of time that it takes for that to instance to
do the job.
And then finally there's a thing called askew long polling and this is a way to retrieve messages from
your ask us cues.
So normally you've got regular short polling and it returns it immediately so you've got your A.C. to
instance sitting there going is there a job.
Is there a job.
Is there a job and keep doing that even if the message queue is empty.
Now long polling doesn't return or responds until a message arrives in the message to all the long pole
times out.
So the great thing about long polling is it's going to save you money because you're not constantly
polling an empty queue.
You know poll it is going to wait it's going to wait the time out and then it turns out it was going
to return a response saying look there's no messages in the queue if you don't have long polling enabled
easy to just consistently hold the cue going is their message is their message is their message.
And that can increase your costs.
OK so what my exam tips would just remember what cueist is distributed message queuing system that allows
you to decouple the components of your application so that they are independent.
So let's say in easy to instance files.
And while it's trying to process a message another easy to instance we'll pick that up and the message
will stay in the queue.
Remember that ask us is poll based not push based.
You have two types of cues your standard cues which are to folk cues.
And that offers best effort ordering and the message is delivered at least once and then you have your
FIFO queues.
And this is where order is strictly preserved and your messages are only delivered once there's no duplicate.
And this could be good for banking transactions with things need to happen in a strict order.
We don't have visibility time out.
The default is 30 seconds you need to increase this if your task is going to take longer than 30 seconds
to complete.
Also remember that the maximum is 12 hours.
Now we have two types of polling we have short polling which is default and basically returned immediately
even if there are no messages in the queue.
We then have long polling and early poll the queue periodically and only return a response when a message
is in the queue all the time out is reach.
So that is it but this actually goes if you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.