OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture this lecture is on Kinesis and this is a high level overview
of the consensus consensus has started appearing in the certified solutions architect associate exempt.
So we've created this section to give you a high level overview and then some practical hands on experience
with the Kinesis.
So what is streaming data.
Let's start with streaming data.
Because in order to understand consensus you have to understand streaming data so streaming data is
data that is generated continuously by thousands of data sources which typically send the data records
simultaneously and in small sizes and we're talking about kilobytes.
So this could be purchases from online stores for example.
So think of Amazon Dot Com people buying stuff on there every single second and that generates streaming
data.
So that would be the transaction that will be the product that they've bought.
Cetera.
Stock prices could be an example of streaming data Game data.
So this could be like Angry Birds as the player is playing Angry Birds that device so that application
could be streaming data back you know to the central servers about what the user is doing and what their
scores are etc..
Social Network Dator is another example of the streaming data.
So every time you go onto Facebook can you update your status so you post something to your friends
Wolds.
That data could then be streamed and then a really good example of streaming data is geospatial data.
So just think of the dot com.
I'm actually recording this right out the front of his offices in San Francisco right now.
I'm in town for a tech conference and I'm staying right next door to them.
I'm actually looking at that building right now so geospatial data.
If you think about when you are using your devices connected the Internet and it's constantly saying
where your driver is and where you and then it's you know interrogating the maps to give you the fastest
route possible to where it is you want to go.
So that is another good example of streaming data.
Another fine example be Io.
And the sensor data that I O.T. collects.
So this could be sensors all around the world monitoring temperatures for example.
So what is Kinesis well can exist as a platform on J-ws that you send your streaming data to.
It makes it easy to load and analyze streaming data and also provides you the ability to build your
own custom applications for your business needs.
So this three call can access services can access streams this can a cease fire hose and then there's
Kinesis analytics and in the exam you're going to be given a whole bunch of different scenario questions
and you have to identify which service you should use in order to best fit the scenario.
So you need to have a key understanding of the different aspects of the Kinney's to service.
So why don't we start with Kenenisa streams because it's the easiest place to start down off to the
left.
We've got an easy to instance we've got mobile phones we've got laptops we have physical computers we've
got IPTA And these are data produces so these are the ones that are producing the data for us.
They are then sending this data over to Kinny streams.
Now Kenny says streams basically stores this data.
By default it's stored for 24 hours but you can increase this for seven days.
Now this data is actually stored in these things called shards and explain what they are in the next
slide but basically your data is sent to aces.
It's stored in shards.
And by default it's stored in those shards for 24 hours.
But you can increase that to seven day retention.
Once the data is stored in the shop you don't have a fleet of two instances which you called your data
consumers and they basically take the data from the shot and turned it into something useful.
So it might be aggregating the data or it might be running sentiment analysis on social media feeds
it might be some kind of algorithm you've got to predict the you know the stock market or to predict
the cost of commodities et cetera.
And once your data consumers have done their calculations they can then send that data to be stored
in a variety of AWOS services so things like Dynamo D-B S-3 elastic that produce redshift etc. so quickly
just on streams so it can easy to stream's consists of shards and Achad basically gives you five transactions
per seconds for reads and up to a maximum total data read rate to make it bytes per second and up to
1000 records per second ferrites and up to a total data right.
Right.
A one megabyte per second and that includes you partition case.
Don't worry you don't need to remember those figures going into the exams but just understand what a
shard is and you can have multiple shards in a stream so the data capacity of a stream is basically
a function of the number of shares that you specify for the stream where the total capacity of the stream
is the sum of all of the shots that you have within that string.
So that's the architecture of Kenenisa streams.
So what does a cease fire hose.
Well can I specify hose is very similar in that we have our data producers we've got our E.S. two instances
that could be a web fleet of Acey two instances like Amazon Dot com for example could be a mobile devices
when you using Uber it could be your laptop it could be either way and they're sending the data into
the system firehose.
So the cool thing about Kinney's this firehose is that you don't have to worry about shards.
You don't have to worry about streams you don't have to worry about manually adding in shards to keep
up with your data et cetera.
It's completely automated and you don't even have to worry about data consumers going in and mining
that data.
You can analyze that data using lambda in real time.
And once that data has been analyzed You can then send it over directly to S3.
Now the actual analytics of that data is completely optional.
The other thing about Kinney's has firehose is that you know you'd like data to automatic data retention
window.
So in cases streams you can retain data by default for 24 hours but you can extend that up to seven
days.
Five hours doesn't work like that.
Essentially as soon as the data comes into firehose it's either analyzed using lambda or it's sent directly
on to S3 or other locations.
So what other locations Well it could be things like redshift if you are sending data to redshift via
the firehose you have to write to S-3 first and then that data is then copied in to red shifted from
S3.
You can also use Kinesis firehose to send things over to elastics search cluster.
So you can also write your data directly into elastics search cluster so hers is a very automated way
of doing Canisius.
So it would just compare.
This is Kinney's to stream again.
So you've got your data produces the sending the data into the streams the streams consists of shards.
The data itself is contained for between 24 hours or up to seven days.
But by default it's 24 hours.
Your consumers then go in and consume that data analyze it do whatever it is that you need to do to
transform that data and then your consumers can send that data on to things like Dynamo D-B S3 elastic
map reduced or red shift.
But if one were using fire hose for example we it's completely automated so you don't need to worry
about your day to consume as you just send it to firehose Fairhurst then sends it to S3.
You can optionally go ahead and analyze that data using lambda but it's a lot more automated and you
don't have to worry about the management of shards.
And you know data retention within Kinesis itself.
So let's move on to consensus analytics.
This can come up just as a high level concept as to what it is.
So down here we've got Al can says fire hose and we've got our Canisius streams can ysis analytics allows
you to run sequel queries of that data as it exists within firehose all streams and then you can use
that Sakal query to store that data inside S-3 redshift or elastics search cluster.
So it's essentially a way of analyzing the data that's inside Kinesis using Sakal type querying languages.
And you can use it above across both Kinesis streams as well as can a cease fire is sort of my exam
tips going into the exam about Kinesis what you need to know the difference between Canossa streams
and Kinesis firehose.
You're going to be given scenario questions and you must choose the most relevant service.
So just remember the core architectural differences if you say a question talking about shards you know
straight away that that's going to be Kinny streams because firehose doesn't have shards whereas if
it's talking about analyzing data automatically using Alamdar and not having to worry about data consumers
then that's going to be Kinney's this firehose.
Also I understand at a high level just what can access analytics is not we're just going to quickly
do a hands on lab so you can see consensus in action.
We're going to use a cloud formation template to build this out.
So if you've got the time join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.