OK hello cloggers and welcomes this lecture lectures on consensus and we're going to go ahead and set
up our own Kinney's to stream.
So it is a lab and you're going to need to log into the AWOS console and the cloud formation template
that we'll be using is available in the resources section of the course.
OK so I in the AWOS console and I just want you to go up and change your region to Northern Virginia
so U.S. East one.
Because basically we're going to be using a confirmation template and we want to make sure all the resources
within that cloud formation template are available if you're using it in a new or a region like London
for example it might break the lab.
So once you've done that we need to go over to cloud formation and cloud formation is under our management
tools and we click on cloud formation and now what we're going to do is we're going to go ahead and
we're going to create a new stack and we're going to instead of using a template we're going to specify
an Amazon S3 template to our own.
Now I will paste this into the resources section of the course or just copy and paste that link and
then paste it into here.
Well go ahead and hit next.
That stack will give it a stack name of Mike nice stack and we will leave everything else as default
if you want to use and easy to keep in order to be able to S-sh into your to instance that's doing both
the data consumption and production.
You can I'm just going to leave it.
I'm going to leave it as T-2 my career.
And we're going to use the application archive this get hyperlink in here that's contained within the
club formation stack.
You don't need to worry about getting that.
Well go ahead and hit next.
Optionally you can put in tags I'm just going to leave everything else as default.
Go ahead and hit next.
And we'll go ahead and create our stack.
Now don't worry about this error message up here.
Just scroll all the way down.
Acknowledge that the club promotion is going to create I am resources and go ahead and hit create.
And now what will happen is your confirmation template will start creating your kidney system.
And this can take anywhere from or up to between 10 to 15 minutes.
I'm just going to pause the video and wait for this stack to be created.
OK so it says My status is create complete.
I just hit refresh and click on events.
I can see all the different events that has happened in within that stack and now what we want to do
is we don't click on outputs and it's giving us a u r o here and this you our show is essentially both
our data producer and our data consumer So it's both artificially creating the data fitting it into
the streams and then it is essentially connecting back up and taking that data and consuming it.
And if we actually click on the link it will create this nice little graph.
So this is essentially just simulating the number of hits on different Web sites.
It's not real data at all it's just a simulation and it's just using random numbers.
You can leave this running you know for a couple of minutes and see you know the visualizations but
essentially all you're going to see is these different lines moving up and down randomly across a time
stamped map.
So I'm back in the console in the cloud formation stack.
Let's go ahead and have a look at what's been created so we can go into a C to be able to see our AC
to instance that is running the CC to instance like I said it's both the data producer and the data
consumer.
If we go back over to here and if we actually go down into Isas psychoanalysis is down the bottom and
it's under the analytic section we click into consensus.
We can see in here if we go over to Canossa streams will be able to see how can the sustainment says
Mike in a systemic Canossa strength.
We can actually click in here.
This gives us all the details so we've got to open Shad's right now.
Our data retention period is 24 hours and we can increase this up to seven days or 168 hours and then
our Shaab level metrics.
Basically instead of it being every five minutes we're producing our metrics at every one minute.
If we were going to enable it's are very similar to detailed monitoring we click up into the monitoring
section we can actually monitor our sheilds now so we can see what is going on inside our can ease the
strain and can have a look at all the different data there and what is sexually doing's it's storing
this data in Dynamo database when we come back here and go over to our dynamo D-B database.
You'll be able to see in tables if you click in tables you can see our our different tables are being
created.
So let's just click on this one and go over the items and you can see in here the large amounts of items
that is being stored every second.
Inside our dynamo D-B table so this really is just a high level view of Kinney's is to give you a little
bit of hands on experience really going into the exam you expected to know the difference between can
streams and the cease fire hose.
You also need to know what can he say analytics is at a high level and that's about it.
So now if you just click back Hurby here we're going to go and delete everything so we just need to
go back into cloud formation.
Click on here and just go actions and then delete stack.
And we're going to go ahead and delete this stack and all the resources that exist within that stack
and now going to be deleted as well.
So that's it for this lecture guys if you have any questions please let me know if you see anything
in your exam on Kinesis that you felt the course hasn't covered.
Please also let me know and I'll create additional contact.
But like I said content.
But like I said the two things you really need to understand the difference between Kinesis firehose
connects to streams and can ysis analytics.