OK helicopters welcome to this very quick lecture I just wanted to tell you about our may collapse.
Nightclubs are about 20 to 40 minutes in length and they're basically a hands on and fun way to learn.
Cloud computing and the great for beginners.
So basically we've got a whole bunch of different make collapse on the platform.
We've got a main generating IO table and we've got a lab that uses a security camera Lamda recognition
an S and S to tell you if you've left a washing on the washing line.
I've got another lab that basically scans Twitter and uses camisa lammed dynamo eBay and Amazon comprehend
to do sentiment analysis to see if Twitter uses hate cats.
And we've got a whole bunch of others I'm about to film one using deep blends I'm just waiting for my
deep lens to arrive so you can watch these labs on the go while using our mobile app and you can try
building the LEDs yourself when you get home.
Make sure you check it out.
Great way to learn cloud computing and have a lot of fun in the process as well.