I say hello cloggers and welcome to the summary of Section 8 so we're going to summarize what we've
learnt about the other AWOS services so you've done really well you're almost at the end of the course
so let's start with QSA SkyWest is a distributed messaging system that allows you to decouple the components
of your application so that independent it's pool based it's not pushed based.
There's two types of cues you've got your standard Qs which is basically going to give you best effort
ordering and your message will be delivered at least once then you have your FIFO queues which is basically
the exact opposite ordering is strictly preserved and messages a deliberate once with no duplicate.
And this could be good for banking transactions which need to happen in a strict order other ask us
things to remember is visibility time out by default.
This is 30 seconds.
You need to increase this if your task is taking longer than 30 seconds to complete the maximum visibility
time out for us is 12 hours.
Well so we have two types of polling we have short polling which returned is returned immediately.
Even if there are no messages in the queue.
But that can be a little bit expensive if you especially if you're not using Yochi as much as you should
be.
And then we have long polling and this polls the queue periodically and only returns a response when
a message is actually in the queue all the time out period is Rached s and s s n s is a scalable and
highly available notification service which allows you to send push notifications or S and S is pushed
based a variety of message formats are supported.
So you've got s.m.m text messages we've got emails we've got ask us QS or any hate TDP and point.
It's a pub sub model where users subscribes to topics.
It's a push mechanism rather than a pull mechanism.
And so example architecture let's say if you go to a company that wants to send notification to multiple
customers they could use in essence to fan out multiple messages in s s format and then using a dedicated
as cueist Q per customer.
If you did it that way you'd always be able to guarantee that each message would be delivered to each
customer at least once.
So as an s versus s remember that s.c.s is for IMAO only.
It can be used for incoming and outgoing emails as well.
And it is not subscription base you only need to know the email address whereas S and S Qaeda's various
formats so it is for s m s s q SH TDP and points e-mail etc..
It is push notification only it does come with the pub submodel So consumers must subscribe to a topic
in order to receive emails from as soon and you can fan mass messages and you can fan out messages to
large numbers of recipients or multiple clients each with their own us.
Q Moving on to Kinesis you need to know the difference between the three core services so we have Kinesis
streams.
These are videos streams so you can securely stream video from connected devices to AWOS for analytics
a machine learning.
We then have data streams.
This is where you can build custom applications and process data in real time.
So those are the two different types of streams Volkan the streams.
We then have Canisius firehose.
This allows you to capture transform and load data streams into AWOS data stores Phania real time analytics
with business intelligence tools and then also remember that you can configure Lamda to subscribe to
a can to stream and execute a function on your behalf when a new record is detected before sending the
processed data on to its final destination.
Moving onto a plastic pane Stoke we did do quite a few labs with the lastic beanstalks.
It allows you to deploy and scour your web application including the web server platform where required.
It supports a widely used programming languages like Java ph PE Python Ruby go Daka dot net and no genius
as well as application server platforms like Tomcat passenger Pluma Apache Isiah's etc..
And what provisions the underlying resources for you you can fully manage the two instances your self
or elastic beanstalk can take control of it for you and you can apply updates monitoring metrics and
health checks as part of your lastic beanstalk environment.
Remember that when you're updating elastic Bonestell there four different types of deployment approaches.
This is supercritical going into your exam to remember the four different types you will get different
scenarios and they will ask you what type of elastic been stalked deployment would best suit your situation.
All at once.
This is where basically you have a service interruption while you go in and update the entire environment
at once and then to roll it back.
You have to perform further all at once.
Upgrade as well.
So do remember that this is probably a good fit test and Dev.
Or with the business that you're working for can have downtime when you do an update and then have rolling
rolling on its own will have reduced capacity so do up to it.
Let's say we've got 10 easy two instances in a fleet rolling might update two of those at a time.
So you would only have eight on line.
So you are going to have reduced capacity but you're not going to have any downtime rolling with additional
Bachche allows you to maintain full capacity so it will add additional AC to instances apply those updates
and then delete the older ones and to rollback.
You need to perform perform a further rolling update.
We then have immutable.
This is the best option for mission critical production systems.
It allows you to maintain full capacity.
It will set up a completely separate orders scaling group and start you know doing the updates.
There is a rollback.
You just need to delete the new instances and auto scaling group in terms of advance silastic beanstalk.
Just remember that you can customize your lastic beanstalk environment by adding configuration files.
These files are written in YAML or in Jason.
They can have the dot com Ficke extension.
You can call them any file name that you want but the config files have to be saved to the Eby extensions
folder and the EPA extensions folder must be located in the top level directory of your application
source code bundle.
Moving onto D.S. and elastic bands.
So we have two different options for launching your G-S instance you can launch it with elastic beanstalk
or you can launch it outside elastic main stalk.
If you launch it within an elastic band Stoke when you terminate the elastic beanstalk environment the
database will also be terminated.
It makes it quick and easy to add your databases and get started but it's really only suitable for Dev
and test environments only if you launch your instance outside of elastic bands.
There is going to be some additional configuration steps required you are going to need to add a security
group and you're going to need to configure the connection string or the connection information so the
user name the password the database and point the database name the table etc etc. and then it's suitable
for production environments.
Gives you a lot more flexibility and it means that if you terminate a plastic beanstalk environment
you know your production instance will not be terminated.
It also allows you to have connections from multiple environments as well so bear that in mind.
So that is it for this lecture guys and this section of the Course you've done really really well.
Hopefully we've covered everything.
If you do see something around other application services such as SOSIAS or even simple workplace service
which we haven't covered Do let us know and we will update this section of the course.
So that's it for me.
If you have any questions please let me know if not feel free to move on to the next section.
Thank you.