OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture we're going to look at S.N. s or simple
notification service.
Now we have used this before we use this in the X-ray lecture that was part of our surplus application
that was broken but we're just going to go into the theory behind S and S So what is S and S basically
it's a web service that makes it easy to set up operate and send notifications from the cloud and it
provides developers a highly scalable flexible and cost effective capability to publish messages from
an application and immediately deliver them to subscribers or to other applications.
So you can have push notifications to all your different devices so it could go to Apple devices Google
devices fire iOS devices Windows devices as well as Android devices and devices in China with Baidoo
cloud push.
So besides pushing cloud notifications directly to mobile devices you can use s and s to deliver notifications
via SML text messages or to email or to ask us or to any hige TDP and point and S and S notifications
can also trigger a lambda functions and when a message is published to an S and S topic that has a lambda
function subscribe to it.
The lambda function is invoked with the payload of the published message and we saw this when we created
this web site using poly.
We're actually using as soon as to pass the actual text to another lambda function which then basically
went in and used the poly service and then took it and stored it in S3.
See Lenda function receives the payload as an input parameter can manipulate the information in the
message publish the message to another Asinus topic or send the message to other A.W. services such
as Polly or S-3 which is what we did in the poly section of the course.
So as n s allows you to group multiple recipients using topics and a topic is an access point for allowing
recipients to dynamically subscribe for identity copies of the same notification.
So one topic can support deliveries to multiple types So for example you can group together iOS Android
and SS recipients.
And when you publish once to a topic as NSA is going to deliver the appropriate Eely formatted copies
of the message to each subscriber so you can have multiple subscribers to a topic using different technologies.
Now to prevent messages from being lost all messages publish to S and S are stored redundantly across
multiple availability zones and some of the benefits that you get from essence is that you'd get instant
tannish push based delivery.
So there's no polling required as soon as you you know send that out.
It will go out to all devices yet simple API eyes and easy integration with applications flexible message
slavery over multiple transpo protocols.
So like I said before you know we could send it to as curious as we could send it by a text and then
using push notifications to multiple mobile devices.
We get Nick we get inexpensive pay as you go model with no upfront costs and you get a web based a AWOS
management console and office the simplicity of a point and click interface.
So what is the difference between and S and S Q S will both a messaging services in AWOS S and S is
push whereas as s polls or polls.
So just bear that in mind if you see some scenario questions asking if you want to implement a push
based one you want unless the one poll based one you want ask us in terms of the pricing the user pays
50 cents per one million Amazon s and s requests so it's incredibly cheap.
You also charge 6 cents per 100000 notifications deliveries or behave TDP and 75 cents per 100 notification
deliveries over S and then $2 per 100000 notification deliveries over email.
So Amazon s s follows the Publish subscribe or sub messaging paradigm with notifications being delivered
to clients using a push mechanism that eliminates the need to periodically check or poll for new information.
So that's the difference.
Like I said between Essence and ask us with simple API is required minimal upfront development effort
no maintenance or management overheads and pay as you go pricing as an S gives you as a developer easy
mechanisms to incorporate powerful for notification systems within your application.
So onto my exam tips so just remember what in essence is it's scalable and highly available notification
service which allows you to send push space notifications from the cloud.
You have a variety of message formats so you've got to mass text messages.
You've got e-mails you've got ex-U.S. and any HDTV endpoint it's a pub submodel where users subscribe
to topics and it's a push based mechanism rubrum pole base mechanism.
So you have to use s and s twice in this course so far we've used it when we were creating poly poly
Web site and we used it when we were doing X so it is in the services section.
If you do want to go and create an S and S topic you can but really you just need to know what it is
at a high level and how it's different from us as soon as it is pushed base.
Q As is pool based.
So is it that this lecture guys if you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.