OK Heller cloggers just a quick break from the calls.
I wanted to tell you about our awesome app so we've got this app.
It's available for iPads.
It's available for tablets as available for smartphones.
It's only Google Play or the Apple App Store and allows you to watch and download lessons you'll be
able to watch content on the go while traveling.
You don't need an internet connection so you can watch it while on the tube or on the subway or on a
flight and you'll be able to learn on the go.
You can also get optional notifications for when new episodes of shows like AWOS.
This week a published and is absolutely free for a cloud remember.
So go check it out on the App Store.
The link is on your screen right now.