OK hello cloggers and welcome to this very quick lecture comparing s.c.s versus asinus.
So what is s.c.s.
Well as he stands for simple email service it's a scalable and highly available email service designed
to help marketing teams and application developers send marketing notification and transactional emails
to their customers using a pay as you go modals So it's basically sending out marketing emails.
It can also be used to receive emails incoming e-mails can be delivered automatically to an S3 bucket
and incoming mails can actually be used to trigger lambda functions and S and S notifications.
So s.c.s is email only right as soon as you can do things like text messages.
You can do things like you know add to ask us Qs published a hasty and points et cetera s.c.s is email
only.
And when you think of marketing e-mails.
Best way to remember it.
So it's for automated e-mails.
You can have purchased confirmations shipping notifications or status updates et cetera.
So you could have a mobile phone company that needs to send an automated confirmation email every time
a customer purchases a prepaid mobile phone.
You know how two minutes it's used for marketing communications advertisements newsletters special offices
office et cetera.
And this could be an online retail business that needs to let its customers know about what sales promotions
its got on as well as discounts.
So a quick comparison s.c.s again like I said email messaging service Estan as it's a pub sub messaging
service and it has a whole bunch of different formats and not just email but S.M. s TDP Eskew cetra
s.c.s can be used to trigger lambda functions or S and S notifications.
Same with s and s it can be used to trigger lambda functions and then it can also be s.c.s can be used
for both incoming and outgoing mails whereas S and S can actually fan out messages to a large number
of recipients and you can replicate and push messages out to multiple endpoints and formats and not
just e-mails but like we said as MSH TDP ask us and as well as e-mails with s.c.s an email address is
all that's required to start sending messages to a user with S and S consumers must subscribe to a topic
in order to receive the notifications.
So s.c.s is essentially asynchronous whereas essence is synchronous so someone has to go in and actually
subscribe to a topic to get those notifications.
So one of my exam tips just remember that s.c.s is for emails only can be used for incoming and outgoing
mails.
It is not subscription base.
You only need to know the person's email address whereas S and S supports multiple formats as ask us
TGP as well as e-mail push notifications only it's a pup submodel So consumers must subscribe to a topic
and you can fan messages out to large number of recipients.
So multiple clients each with their own s Ask Qs.
So that is it for this lecture guys if you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.