OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture.
This lecture is on elastic beings beanstalk one on one and we have already used plastic Beanstalk in
this course.
But over the next few lectures we'll use it and a lot more detail go into advanced silastic things can
we look at how you can use elastic things with.
Yes.
So before we get started.
What is elastic Bonestell.
Well it's a service for deploying and scaling web applications developed in many popular languages or
Java dot net page pain O.J.'s Python Ruby.
Go and Daka onto widely used applications of platforms like Apache Tomcat or engine X or passenger or
I I.
And so this means that developers can focus on writing code and don't need to worry about any of the
underlying infrastructure needed to run the application.
So essentially what elastic beanstalk is is you just throw away at some code in a zip file and it will
go in and detect or go in and configure an environment for you.
So go in and configure the Web servers might put them behind in order scaling great.
It could go in and configure Yes or you could manage phrenologists environment will cover that off in
the audio section.
So that's all it is it's basically a provisioning service very sort of similar to cloud formation in
that you know you use it to provision environments except cloud formation is all Jason based and club
promotion you upload cloud formation templates whereas with elastic beanstalk it's very much using the
GUI you see go through click you know different buttons and then you go in and provision your environment.
So we will do that in the next lab.
So basically what you do.
Like I just said you upload the code an elastic beanstalk Stokoe handle deployment capacity provisioning
load balancing or scaling and the applications health and you still contain full control of the underlying
AWOS resources power your applications and you pay for the only you only pay for the AWOS resources
required to store and run your application.
So this could be easy two or three.
And essentially when you create a new elastic beanstalk deployment it will create a new S3 bucket and
it will save every version of your code in that S3 bucket.
And again we're going to have a look at that in the lab so elastic beanstalk is the fastest and simplest
way to deploy your applications in.
AWOS it automate automatically scows your application up and down you can select the easy to instance
type that is optimal for your application.
You can retrain full administrative control over the resources parrying your application or you could
just have elastic beanstalk do it for you.
You can actually go through and do manage platform updates.
So this will automatically update things like your operating system Java page.
Pay no japes even Apache et cetera.
You can monitor and manage application health var dashboard and it's integrated integrated with cloud
watch and X-ray so you're going to have good performance data as well as metrics.
So what are some exam tips for elastic.
We'll just remember that it's basically a way of deploying your web application and it will provision
all the resources behind it.
That includes the servers could include the yes etc..
It supports a widely used programming technologies like Java page PE Python Ruby go Daka dot net and
no genius and also supports applications of platforms like Tom-Kat passenger buma etc..
Previsions the underlying resources for you.
You yourself can fully manage the E.S. two instances or elastic beanstalk can do that for you and then
you can do updates.
You can do monitoring and metrics and health checks.
And this is all included.
So the best way to literalistic penstock is to go ahead and get our hands dirty so that's what we'll
do in the next lecture.
So if you've got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.