OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture this lecture we're going to look at how we can deploy
applications with elastic beanstalk.
So I've created two very very simple web sites.
We've got version one and version two.
You'll be able to download version one in this sleb and in the next lab you'll be able to download version
to it's in the resources section.
So do you go ahead and download that.
Basically it's an index dot page pay photo and a photo of a shirt that we have called AWOS this week
which is a show we run every single week to keep you updated with AWOS it's on our YouTube channel.
So what we're going to do is we're going to deploy this app in a PH P Apache stack using elastic beanstalk.
So once you've downloaded it just keep it as a zip file.
You don't need to unzip it unless you want to have a look at the files and then you need to log into
the AWOS console.
OK so here I am in the console consul going to go over to services elastic beanstalk sits under a computer
you can see it here and cloud formation actually sits under management tools cloud formation as a way
of scripting your infrastructure whereas elastic beanstalk is a way of provisioning your environments
using a Cooey effectively.
So we're going to click on elastic Bhain Stolk and you'll see this splash screen if you haven't used
it before.
I'm currently in the Northern Virginia region.
I'm going to go ahead and get started and I'm going to call this application name let's call it hello
cloud gears.
Now the platform I'm going to choose ph pay and then I'm going to instead of using a sample application
I'm going to upload my code to I'm just going to click upload and then it says source code origin local
file choose file and you can see my two files in here we've got version one and version 2.
I'm going to use version 1 for this.
Gonna go ahead and hit open then I'm just going to go over here and hit upload.
That is now uploading it is actually uploading it to and S-3 bucket which it's going to create and then
I'm going to go ahead and hit create application.
So this can take a little bit of time.
It can take about basically five or six minutes.
So I'm just going to pause the video and wait for my lastic beanstalk environment to come online.
A case that took about four minutes you can see here it says successfully launched environment.
Hello cloud gurus EMV.
So if I could go and click on applications I'll be able to see it in here.
Hello cloggers.
Ian Vink.
And then if I click in here I'll be able to see that it's up and running.
And hopefully if I click this link we should get a live web site.
And here we go hello cloggers.
This is version 1.
Ms.
Fey doing AWOS this week so deep Lyn's is now general availability.
We actually just ordered one into the office so expect some courses on that soon.
And if you actually click on the link you'll be able to see our YouTube channel and you'll be able to
subscribe I would recommend subscribing because it's the easiest way to keep up to date with AWOS every
week you can see that the videos are between two to three minutes long.
So very easy to watch on your way to work.
So back in the AWOS console I'm back in my elastic store environment in here we've got our configuration
so this is how we go and configure our environment.
Right now we're just using a T1 micro.
It's a very basic instance.
We could go in here and add additional instances going here and can figure out load balances in here
we've got our deployment policies.
How do we do updates to our Web site.
And we're going to cover that off in a lot of detail in the next lecture because that is basically the
main thing you're going to be tested on going into your developers so shit.
Exam on elastic Bane's still.
Over here we have our logos health monitoring alarms managed updates manage updates basically where
you can configure updates to your operating system updates to let's say page Fe or two you know Apache
or something like that.
And you do this during it to find predefined configuration window.
So might be at 3 a.m. every Sunday in town here with events and tags as well.
So let's go back to what dashboard.
I am going to end the lecture here.
We are going to go ahead and learn all about updates like I said that that is pretty much the most important
thing to know going into the developer associate exam.
So if you've got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.