OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture.
Actually going to look at updating elastic band Stolk and this is really critical to understand going
into the exam because you are going to get questions on the different types of updates and you will
be expected to know the differences between them.
So what is an elastic band Stokoe abs deployment policy not to be confused with you know elastic block
storage so elastic beanstalks supports several options for processing deployments.
You have four options essentially.
So this is how we update our code.
We can do all at once we can do rolling.
We can do rolling with additional batch and we can do immutable and see how to configure this a little
bit on later on in this lecture.
So let's look at the differences between them all at once is pretty easy.
It basically all at once deployments updates and deploys the new version to all instances simultaneously.
All of your instances are going to be out of service while the deployment takes place.
So you will have downtime with an all at once deployment you will experience an outage while the deployment
is taking place.
And this is not ideal for mission critical production systems.
And if the update fails you will need to roll back the changes by redeploying the original version to
all your instances.
So that's an all at once deployment.
You probably want to do this in your test in Devon varment you definitely do not want to do this in
your production environment unless your business is prepared to have some downtime.
We then have a rolling deployment policies and this basically deploys the new version in batches so
each batch of instances is taken out of service while the deployment takes place and your environment
to capacity will be reduced by the number of instances in a batch.
While the deployment takes place.
So let's say that you've got 10 instances in your environment and you've got you know you're going to
have batches of two essentially those two batches will go down and you still have eight instances in
service.
Once those two instances have been patched or back up another two will go back out.
So you have some instances that are taken out of service.
So this isn't really ideal for performance sensitive systems.
And if the update does fail you're going to need to perform an additional rolling update to roll back
the changes.
We then have rolling with additional batch policy.
And this is basically it launches an additional batch of instances and it deploys the new version in
batches and this maintains capacity during deployment process.
And if the update fails you're going to need to perform an additional rolling update to rollback the
changes.
Now if you get a exam question where saying look you know it's really performance sensitive.
You basically cannot have any downtime and you need to maintain full capacity than you want rolling
with additional batch policies.
If you can afford downtime then you either want all at once or you could have rolling updates where
your system can have some instances out of service while you do the updates.
We then have a mutable deployment policies and this deploys a new version to a fresh group of instances
in their own new auto scaling group.
And when the new instance is passed the health checks that then move to the existing auto scanning group
and then finally the old instance is terminated.
And this maintains full capacity during the deployment process and the impact of failed update is far
less and the rollback process requires only terminating the new auto scanning group.
So this is the preferred option for mission critical production systems.
So do know that for differences going into your exams it is extremely important because you are going
to get multiple scenario questions and I'll ask you which for updates you should use.
OK so here I am and the console is going to go over to services and click on elastic beanstalk which
is under compute and here's my Hello cloggers environment that we created in the last one.
If I click on it it's going to load the actual environment itself.
If you click here though these are out different environments so we could go in and provision additional
environments.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to go in and click on application versions and you can see here.
Hello pluggers source.
And here's the source zip file.
This is actually saved in an S3 bucket which will have a look at it a little bit later.
And what I'm going to do is going to go ahead and I'm going to upload a new application.
We're going to call this version too.
So make sure you download version 2 in the resources section and the description again version 2.
And I'm going to go ahead and upload this application so version 2 and hit upload so that I will now
upload it and it's going to save it to an S3 bucket that is used by lastic things still can if you actually
click on services and go over to S-3 you'll be able to find your elastic Bonestell buckets and they
are on a per region basis.
My one is this one here.
Aced one because I've been doing this out of Northern Virginia.
I click in here.
I can actually see the uploaded files his version 1 his version 2.
This is the configuration for elastic bands still dot elastic beanstalk.
We can go ahead and leave that we will come back on to something similar to that in the advents elastic
band Stolpe lecture which is coming up.
So let's go back over to services and go back over to plastic pain Stolk.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to click into my application say hello cloud jurors and click
on my application versions and you can see version 2 is here.
It's all ready to go but it hasn't been deployed to any environment.
So what I can what I could do before I do this I just want to show you how to change the deployments.
So if we click on all applications click inside our environment and go to configuration if we want to
change our updates or our deployments we click into rolling updates and deployments in here.
And this is where we can change our deployment policy.
Now at the moment I've only got two options all at once are immutable.
The reason for that is because I've only got one easy to instance if I had a fleet of two instances
behind an elastic load balance or I'd get more of those options.
I'm just going to K-8 this lead simple whether I really want to go into it because it's going to take
an awful lot of time and to be honest it's only with a few marks on the exam the most important thing
that you need to remember for your exam is the four different deployment policies and what scenarios
you'd use them in.
So let's go back over to hello.
Cloggers go to our application version.
Let's click on version 2 and I'm going to go ahead and deploy this.
Now this is going to cause me to have some downtime because it's all at once deployment and I'm going
to go ahead and hit deploy.
And that is now deploying my new version and I'm just going to pause the video here fact or click on
the events page so we can watch it happen.
And I'm going to pause the video and wait for this new environment to go live.
OK.
It's been a few minutes.
I'm going to go ahead and just hit refresh.
And here we go.
Environment Health has transitioned from info to OK application update completed 78 seconds ago and
took 19 seconds.
So we should be able to click on this and hopefully get a new version.
So hello cloggers this is version 2.0.
There's my lovely face.
We go back to the elastic beanstalk environment and click on here.
We've got our environments in here.
We click on application versions we can now see the version 2 has been deployed to this environment.
All we could do is click on version 1 go ahead and click deploy and we could then deploy that back to
our helo cloud juror's environment.
If you see an error message just saying environment not ready it's just cause you're doing it a little
bit too quickly just give it a couple of minutes so that we could just roll back to version 1.
If we decided to do that well we can also do is we can also go in here and create new environment so
we could actually create environment and then deploy version 1 to that environment and have version
2 in another environment.
It's entirely up to you but that's how we do versioning in side the console how we do visioning inside
elastic beanstalk.
And like I said it's a really important exam to understand for different types of updates.
So before we move on to the exam tips or we need to do now is go in and delete this environment.
All you have to do is just click on actions and go delete application and go ahead and hit delete.
And that will go through and delete your Basically your easy to instance as well as whatever other hits
elastic beanstalk has provisioned.
So what of my exam tips.
Ok so that brings us onto our exam tips.
So just remember the four different deployment approaches and where you would use them.
So it got all at once.
This has a service interruption while you update the entire environment at once.
So the one we just did to roll back you have to perform for the third the all at once upgrade.
So bear that in mind with go rolling.
This basically will reduce your capacity during deployment but you're not going to have downtime.
And to Roback you need to perform a further rolling update rolling with additional Bache maintains capacity.
So if the question is asking you how you can do this without you know while maintaining full capacity
you need additional Bachche and then to rollback.
You need to perform a further rolling update and then we have immutable.
And this is the preferred option for mission critical production systems.
It's going to create an entire new fleet of E.C to instances and apply those updates to it and it will
only delete and switch over to those instances once they've passed all the health checks so it allows
you to maintain full capacity and then to rollback.
You just delete the new instances and auto scaling groups so they with the mutable behind a completely
different auto scaling.
Great.
So just remember those four different ones going into the exam and you will do well.
So that's it.
But this lecture goes if you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Thank you.