OK hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture this lecture is on advanced elastic veins.
Now this is just going to be a theory lecture because we're just going to keep it simple.
But it's really important to understand going into your exam that you can customize your elastic beanstalk
environment using a plastic beanstalk configuration file.
And this means you can define packages to Instow you can create Linux users and groups you can run show
commands you can specify services to enable all you can even go in and configure your load balance so
much you can do.
These files are written in either in YAML or in Jason format and they can have a file name of your choice
but they must have a dot com fake extension and they'll all be saved inside a folder called Dot E B
extensions so you can have any filename that you want but it's got to have a dot com fake.
And though these files all have to be saved inside the folder dot Eby extensions.
So where is the extensions folder.
What must be included in the top level directory of your application source code bundle.
So this means that the configuration files can be placed under the source control along with the rest
of your application code.
So you probably will get a question going into your exams about how to configure elastic beanstalk deployments.
You just use the config files and they all must be saved in the dot.
Ebay extensions photo which must be in the top level directory of your application.
Remember that.
Here's an example of my health check.
You r l dot com.
So in this example way using Jason and in this example we're telling our lastic load balance the application
health check you are ill and we're just saving this in a config file with code up my health check our
old config and this would be saved in the IP extensions folder in our root directory.
So that's really it.
That's my advents elastic beanstalk tips.
So just remember that you can customize your elastic beanstalk environment by adding configuration files.
Files are going to be either written in Yemen or in JSM the files can have any name that they want but
they've got to have the dot config extension and these dot config files are all saved to the DOT Ebby
extensions folder.
And this must be located in the top level directory of your application source code bundle.
So if you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the very last elastic things Stuart lecture where we talk about elastic
bands with D.S..