OK hello club yours and welcome to this lecture this lecture we're going to look at audience and elastic
beanstalk so elastic so stalk supports two ways of integrating an audio database with your beanstalk
environment and you can launch the audience instance from within the plastic bins store console which
means the audience instance is created within your elastic beanstalk environment.
And this is a typical use case with this would be for Debb and test deployments.
However this might not be ideal for production environments because it means that the lifecycle of your
database is tied to the lifecycle of your application environment.
So if you go in and terminate the environment the database instance is going to be terminated too.
So just remember if you couple audience an elastic beanstalk together it means that when you go in and
delete your elastic beanstalk environment it is going to go in and delete your.
Yes.
Instances well and that could not be ideal for production systems.
So for production environments the preferred option is to decouple the yes instance from your your elastic
beanstalk environment.
So you should launch it outside of elastic beanstalk directly from the RDF section of the AWOS console.
And this gives you a lot more flexibility it allows you to connect multiple environments to the same
database.
You could have multiple lastic beanstalk environments connecting into your instance and it provides
a wider choice of database types because you can choose any database that is supported by audience and
also allows you to tear down your application environments without affecting your database instance.
So how do you do this.
Well you need to do two things essentially two additional configuration steps required.
The first is that an additional security must be added to your environments or Terschelling group and
then you'll also need to provide the connection string configuration to your application service.
So this is going to be your database or your address and point the password and the user name and then
just the connection parameters in order to connect into that database.
So that is it you just need to remember that going into your exam that there's two different options
for launching your instance you can launch it within elastic band Stolk but do remember that when you
terminate the elastic beanstalk environment the database is also going to be terminated.
It's quick and easy to add your database to elastic things still can get started.
But this would typically just be suitable for Dev and test environments only.
The other option is you can launch outside of elastic stork's you do this by going into the D.S. console
and provisioning your instance additional configuration steps are required.
You're going to need to create a security group and you're going to need to parse the connection string
to your application.
This is definitely suitable for production environments because it gives you more flexibility and it
also allows you to have connections from multiple environments and you can tear down the application
stacks without it impacting that database.
So you have done really well you are at the end of this section of the course and the next one we're
just going to rehash everything that we've learnt in this section of the course and then we'll be able
to move on to the next section.
So if you got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.