OK hello cloudburst and welcome to this lecture.
This is one of my favorite sections in the Colts this is the Sevilla section and this lecture is called
Savalas 1 1.
Now before we talk about what Servilius actually is let's go through the history of cloud computing
and I'm going to try this in approximately two minutes so I'm going to try and summarize the entire
history of cloud computing So a lot of developers and solutions architects like me we really don't like
computer hardware.
It's heavy it's cumbersome it breaks all the time.
We've basically spent the last few decades building layer of abstraction layer of obstruction in code
to shield ourselves from the ugly truth of what's actually running our code.
And first we decided hey just chuckle is hardware in a data sent us somewhere and someone else can be
responsible for making sure it's turned on it's connected to the network that there's fault tolerance
et cetera.
And hooray we no longer needed to get out of our chairs but provisioning the infrastructure wasn't fun
we had to talk to people we had to place orders with suppliers we had to get the supplies to provide
the hardware to the data center provider.
We then needed to get it ready.
We needed to get it network we needed sysops administrators to go in and give us you know install the
operating systems or at least give us remote access so we could do that.
And I worked direct space in 2010 so over eight years ago now but when I worked it would take anywhere
from 10 days from when the customer placed an order three to 20 days depending on the customer segment
and so that is quite a long time and space are actually really fast compared to other providers in the
industry.
One of the other places that I worked it could take us anywhere between three to six months from when
a customer placed an order to him we actually delivered all the hardware for them to be able to access.
So it hasn't been fun but things have gotten a lot faster.
So in 2006 Amazon released E.C too.
And this was the birth of infrastructure's a service suddenly you could provision machines with API
calls from the command line or from a web browser and it was absolute heaven and infrastructure's a
service was born and developers and solution's architects and technical people all around the world
cheered and AWOS is basically infrastructure is koj you can go in and commissioning machine anywhere
in the world and have it do your bidding with a single API call.
Now if I went back in time to 2010 and told you in 2006 lets say and told someone that they would be
able to spin up virtual servers in the cloud from anywhere on earth.
They would have thought that I was crazy.
So this is why AWOS is so far ahead of the game.
They were one of the very first people to market with this service but theres still a problem with this
right this infrastructure to run but this still a problem with this right.
You still have to worry about infrastructure it still exists in basically something you could still
go wrong at any moment.
Its always going to be in the back of your mind what if it crashes or what happens if it gets hacked
or goes off line cetera and then Microsoft as you came out blazing with platform as a service and Amazon's
version of PAHs is basically elastic stalk and what it does is it allows you to you know its a nice
way of saying Give me a code and we'll spin up the machine for you and we'll even push the code into
it and run it for you.
And that was great it was one less step that you had to perform.
You didn't have to worry about the architecture but again you still had a server that you had to control
and where things could go wrong.
And that was still your responsibility as a customer.
Then containers came along and containerisation has gained a lot of popularity in the last few years
and although it's not exclusively related to cloud containers are popular in cloud environments and
containers little lightweight alternatives to full blown virtualization.
They're isolated and lightweight but they still need to be deployed to a server and they are an excellent
solution when dependencies are in play.
But they have their own housekeeping challenges you still have to worry about keeping your containers
running stuff to worry about scaling and response to load etc..
They are still your responsibility.
And then Lamda comes out and Cephalus computing was born and basically lammed allows you to take you
code and run it without any need to previsions servers install software deploy containers or worry about
any low level details and your code can be run in massive parallel parallelize way in response to events.
So the cloud provider takes care provisioning and management of the infrastructure and the developer
doesn't even need to think about it.
And if you have an Amazon elex or at home every time you say the word X or every time you're talking
to your Lexar device guess what's actually what you're communicating with you're actually communicating
with lambda lambda talking back to you.
Even now you know in 2000 from basically since the first Alexa's came out so 2016 you'd have been able
to talk to Alamdar and Lamda talks back to you.
And the great thing about this is you don't have to worry about managing servers.
So this is a blog written my brother this was written on October 21st 2015 and it talks about survivalists
and I would argue that we were certainly one of the first startups in the world to fully embrace Vellis
if not the very first start up with certainly the first startup to build a service learning management
system.
So we've been doing service for awful long time.
I'll show you a brief network diagram of how you know our platform in a second.
We're also the founders of service.
So we had the very first a service call which was in New York in 2016 in Brooklyn.
We then did one in Tokyo and one in London last year we did one in Austin one in New York and then another
one in Tokyo.
We've already had one in Paris this year and we have a another one in San Francisco coming up.
So if you want to check that out just go to several askant.
I always I mean the conferences are amazing it's all the cutting edge people in cloud talking about
how they're using service and how it's you know what impact it's having on their business.
And this is the platform the cloud architecture.
So we have here.
Angela J.S. running across the bridge in the browser across all devices it could be your iPhone could
be your iPad could be Android tablets could be your PC or Macs whatever.
And then basically it's running in the browser the browser then sends requests to API gateway and then
that's also two different lambda functions.
So it might be that you know you're on our discussion forums asking a question or it might be that I'm
uploading a video to the platform an updated lecture and that's going to kick off a whole elastic transcoding
pipeline et cetera et cetera.
And then when you're actually watching the videos they're stored in S3.
We actually use cloud front to stream them down so cloud front is Amazon's CDN service.
We use Auth. 0 for authentication.
So when you sign in with Facebook with Google or with the linked in or whatever that's author zero or
we use firebase as our back and database is now owned by Google.
So we multi cloud as well and we use Strype we use pipo we use brain tree etc. for credit card payments
and we send all our emails out through a campaign monitor.
And what's unique about this entire architecture is we don't have any easy to instances we don't have
any D.S. instances don't have anything to manage.
And this scales automatically so we could have 100000 or you know a million people on the platform at
any given time and lambda is just going to scale automatically to make that demen.
So it is very very scalable.
And the great thing is it's very very cost effective.
We actually only just started paying for our Lamda invocations.
I think at the beginning of this year and we just turned 3 just actually just a few days ago.
So we've basically been running on free to lambda for the last two years and we are at currently about
600000 students.
So it gives you an idea as to why service is so disruptive anyway so that is an introduction to several
US in the next lecture we're going to cover off Lamda and what it is and how it works from a theoretical
point of view then we're going to start getting our hands dirty so if you've got the time please join
us in the next lecture.
Thank you.