R.k Hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture.
So hopefully you're enjoying the course so far.
You are Fareway into it by now and you are learning an awful lot about AWOS Hopefully you're enjoying
it as well.
What does that tell you about a competition we run every single week.
It's called gure of the week.
What we do is we post a professional level questions are really really hard question each week to our
Facebook page and what you can do is click through and go and answer that question on our discussion
forums each week what we do is we choose one.
And so that's correct.
And also that has the best explanation as well.
And what we do is we then send an exclusive Taisha.
So this is the T-shirt here.
Seriously I don't even own one of these.
It's only for when is of the week you get a sticker and you get a hand signed card by me and you also
go into the draw to win a free ticket to reinvent for 2018.
This will give you lots of practice for answering professional level questions.
So if you do want to go on and do your professional certifications this is a great way to practice as
well.
And it's completely free to enter.
And like I said you can win really awesome prizes and a free ticket to re-invent 20:18.
So make sure you check it out.
We announce the winner every single week on our weekly TV show AWOS this week.
So that's it for me guys.
Awesome I'll see in the next lecture.