Okay.
Hello closures and welcome to the very last lecture in this section of the course.
So this is the server summary.
So let's go through all our exam tips and we'll start with Lambda.
So remember that lambda scales out and not up.
So you scale it out automatically.
So this just simply means that you can have many many different concurrent lambda functions running
at once lambda functions are all independent.
So one event is going to equal one function.
Lambda is service and you should know what services are serving us.
So things like dynamo D.B. things like S3 things like lambda things like elastic beanstalk have servers
easy to has servers etc. lambda functions can trigger other lambda functions.
So one event can equal X number of functions if the functions trigger other functions.
So you can have an infinite number of functions in theory and then architectures can get extremely complicated
with the lambda and AWP as X-ray allows you to debug what is happening.
So we saw that in our lab we're able to go in and see x ray are using x ray we're able to see all the
updates to dynamo D.B. our S.A. notifications and it was failing there were able to go in and troubleshoot
that and make it better.
Also remember that lambda can do things globally so you can use it to backup S3 Buckets to other S3
Buckets in other regions.
But each lambda function will is on a regional basis.
So if you're doing it in Northern Virginia that's a separate area then obviously if you're doing it
in USD 1 and then also go into Lam into the exam knowing the lambda triggers that is really important
to understand all the different services that can trigger lambda.
Remember what API Gateway is at a very high level and remember that API Gateway has caching capabilities
to increase performance.
So I use that example of a waiter sorry at McDonald's you know when you're at McDonald's you get big
macs and cheeseburgers very very quickly but if you're going to order something like a fish burger or
a salad it can take the kitchen a longer kitchen has to actually go out and make it just like that API
Gateway can cash.
The most common requests so you get it a lot faster API Gateway is very low cost and scales automatically
and you can throttle API gateway to prevent attacks and Amazon do throttle API Gateway themselves anyway
we'll get to that in a few slides and you can log results to cloud watch if you're using JavaScript
AJAX that supports multiple domains with API Gateway you have to ensure that you've enabled cause on
API Gateway and cause is enforced by the clients so across origin resource sharing.
Moving on to version control with Lambda you can have multiple versions of your lambda functions the
latest version will always use the dollar latest qualified versions we'll use dollar latest and unqualified
versions when I say qualified versions it will be the ARVN and then at the end you'll have the colon
and then latest as unqualified will not have the latest at the end of the R and versions are immutable
they cannot be changed and you can actually split traffic using aliases two different versions B cannot
split this traffic with the latest.
Instead you have to go and create an alias to the latest and then you can split your traffic from there.
Remember you can only split it two ways you can't do it three ways.
Step functions was a great way to visualize your service application and step functions automatically
triggers and tracks each step step functions logs.
The state of each step.
So if something goes wrong you can track what went wrong and where and then x ray or so x ray we used
again to just see what was going inside our service applications just see the performance and if there
was any errors.
The x ray SDK provides three things.
You've got your interceptors to add to your code to trace incoming TTP requests you've got your client
handlers to instrument AWB says declare key clients that your application uses to call the other AWB
services and then you've got to reach DTP client to instrument calls to other internal and external
GDP Web services with x ray remember that it integrates with Elastic Load Balancing lambda API Gateway
easy to and elastic beanstalk and then also just remember the languages that are supported so Java go
no J.S. Python Ruby and dot net.
So that is it for this section of the course goes perfectly you've had lots of fun building out our
services website.
We then went on to build out our own Alexis skill using the service application repository.
We then went on to learn about x ray about step functions about lambda about API gateway.
Now remember we do two service conferences all over the world check out servers.
Oh if you want to check out where the nearest one is.
Service is a huge revolution in software architecture and its really is most applications will become
service sooner or later.
In my opinion so that is for this lecture goes if you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next section of course.
Thank you.