I k Hellyer cloggers and welcome to this lecture.
Hopefully you're enjoying the course so far.
If you do want to learn more about syphilis.
A cow has a number of great courses on our platform that helps you understand similis better and how
to build reliable and scalable architectures.
These courses include a more detailed course on AWOS lambda.
We've got a service for beginners course which is course where you learn how to build a portfolio using
Servilius and react.
We also have a course about using similis architectures with Grof.
Q Well these courses are all available on the platform today so make sure you check them out.