OK bloggers and welcome to this lecture lecture we're going to be looking at Lambda.
So this is going to be a theory lecture in the next lecture we're going to look at API gateway which
is also a theory lecture.
And then what we're going to go ahead and do is we're going to go and create our first Services Web
site which will just show our names so that we'll be using lambda an API gateway.
We'll then go on to create a far more sort of complicated web site.
This will be a civil list Web site that uses a combination of three uses lammed it uses API gateway
uses dynamo D.B and it uses the poly service and that lecture will basically enable you to take your
notes any notes you've taken throughout this course you'll be able to put it into this Web site and
it will generate those notes into a voice using the police service and then you'll be able to listen
to your notes on the girls.
You could download them to your phone and you could hear your notes read out to you as you know travel
so help you study and then what we're going to do to top it all off is we're going to take those notes
and we're going to create an extra skill that will actually go and reach old notes out to us so it is
going to be extremely hands on.
You're going to learn an awful lot about survivalists as well as about lammed and as well as about API
gateway.
I would say this though if you are having trouble with lammed or an API gateway in this lecture in the
next lecture definitely still what should go ahead and build out all these Web sites get some hands
on experience and then come back and watch Lamda and API gateway again and then you'll definitely be
able to grasp the concepts a lot better.
So let's go ahead and get started.
What is LAMDA.
Well before we get started with what is Lam to think about what is going on right now when you're watching
this video how do you think this information is being you know relate to you.
Well first of all we host everything most of it almost everything on AWOS we do use some GCP services
as well but we're mostly on AWOS.
So all of our videos and the video files that you're watching right now are stored in S3 and we actually
use cloud front as LCD and provide.
So these videos are stored actually in U.S. aist 1 and that's where most of our S-3 buckets are.
So these videos are stored inside a data center and in your data centers you have your hardware.
So you have things like sands.
You have your servers you have your switches you're routers your firewalls your load balances et cetera
et cetera and all of those devices are using assembly code or protocols.
And I don't know if you've ever written anything in assembly it's like pretty much a nightmare.
So what most almost all developers do is they learn high level languages these are the languages such
as go or no JSL Python etc..
And in order to use these languages you know we basically have operating systems so we have windows
we have Linux we have OS X et cetera and we are actually as you're watching this now you're probably
watching this in crime hopefully not in Internet Explorer.
And that is running inside your operating system.
And when you go into the AWOS console you're actually your browser is interacting with the AWOS API.
And the final layer of extraction is lammed.
So whenever you're using our site you're actually making API calls to a API gateway which is triggering
a whole bunch of lambda functions in the background so lambda is almost like the ultimate AABs abstraction
layer as least it's the latest abstraction layer.
And the cool thing about lambda is that you don't have to worry about data centers.
You don't have to worry about hardware you don't have to worry about assembly Kodo protocols or any
high level level languages you don't have to worry about you know running the operating systems.
You don't have to worry about the actual application layer or even to some extent the API.
All you have to worry about is your code AWOS take care of everything else for you.
So that's what lambda is and if that doesn't make a lot of sense don't worry who you're going to get
a lot of hands on experience with lambda.
And we will like it come back and watch this lecture and we'll hopefully make a lot more sense.
So what is LAMDA.
Well basically it's compute service where you can upload your code and create a lambda function and
AWOS lambda takes care of the provisioning and management of the servers that you use to run your code
so you don't have to worry about operating systems patching scaling etc. and you can use lambda in the
following ways you can use it as an event driven compute service where AWOS lambda runs your code in
response to events and these events could be anything could be changes to your data in S3 or it could
be a change to your data in a dynamite db table etc..
These code triggers will have a look at those and a lot more detail as we go on.
And you can also use it as a compute service to run your code in response to TZP request using Amazon
API gateway or Amazon API calls using the A.W. SDK case and this is what we do it a plugger.
This is exactly what we're going to be doing in later lectures are we going to use that to compute services
going to response respond to HTP requests using Amazon's API gateway.
So let's have a look at our user we've got our user Let's pretend this is you and you want to create
a name and see what you do is you store that main in S3 and that then triggers a lambda function and
that lambda function will basically take your picture and take the text that you sent to the service
and it will put the text over the name saying Y.
And that will then trigger another lambda function which would then return the information back to use.
This is the complete main.
So this is a typical Maime Web site and so sort of a service.
Well not the typical site but disappears Servilius main web sites so that would be what the architecture
looks like.
And perhaps it then triggers another lambda function which then takes the name that's in that S3 bucket
and it replicates it across to some other S3 buckets elsewhere in the world.
So you've got some redundancy.
So the lambda functions can trigger other lambda functions putting things up inside S-3 can trigger
lambda function et cetera et cetera et cetera.
So that's at a very high level.
The other way Lamda works is if you are sitting here and you're watching of course and you're making
HTP request that's going and hitting API gateway API gateway is then taking that information and passing
it to lambda lambda then responds and processes that information sends back to API gateway which sends
it back to the user.
So that's the second way in which we use lammed and you can actually do this in massive sort of parallel
so you can have too many requests that will trigger two separate lambda functions and when I say separate
the actual code is the same but the function is being triggered in parallel.
So you're going to have one function responding to one request and one function responding to another
request it's going back through API gateway and it's sending it back to the user.
So what languages does is supported by Alamdar.
Well we have a whole bunch of high level languages we've got no yes we've got Java we've got Python
we've got safe shop and we've got go.
It is important to remember those going into your exams to memorize those and I'm sure they will add
more and more languages later.
So how is Lamda price what's priced on the number of requests and the first one million requests free
and yes you did read that right.
The first one million requests free and that's on a per month basis.
Now when at a club girl we actually only just started incurring a lammed bill at the beginning of this
year.
We were able to build our entire business using AWOS Lamda inside free tier and it was only the beginning
of this year that we started getting over a million requests per month.
So that gives you an idea as to you know how cheap is Duras and even now I think how below is well under
a dollar that's just Lamda don't want to pay for other things so it is very very cheap.
It's also priced on the duration.
And sorry is 20 cents per one minute request softer.
It's also priced on duration.
It's calculated from the time that your code begins executing until it returns or otherwise terminates
rounded up to the nearest 100 milliseconds and the price depends on the amount of memory that you allocate
to your function.
And we're going to go have a look at that.
So why is Lamda call and forget the cheesy sort of image that was the best thing I could find.
That looked cool.
Well lambdas cool cause there's no service.
You don't have to manage any servers you don't need System Administrators you don't need network administrators
or database administrators.
You know you're literally your code just executes automatically.
You don't have to worry about scaling automatically Asare scaling manually.
You don't have to worry about orders Skaven groups.
It just scales continuously as the solutions architect.
Things that used to sort of keep me up at night.
You know whenever we're going to have a massive sort of event for one of my customers whether or not
the infrastructure would scale or would do with or an old fall over Lamda doesn't fall over its scales
automatically unless there is an outage and there has been some Lamda outages it can be frustrating
for some reason the outages always seem to occur in USA U.S. East one.
I have no idea why we actually put all that production stuff in one but every time there's a Lamda outage
the a club site goes down.
Fortunately it's not very common.
Probably a once in a year and two once in every 18 months and lambda super super cheap.
Like I said you know we were able to build our entire business in free here.
And even now I think how Lamda bill is under a dollar a month.
So it is extremely cheap and that's why lammed is super cool.
And one thing to bear in mind is that every time you use an Amazon echo when you talking to Alexa and
she responds you are talking to Lamda that is basically taking your voice turning it into techs running
it through the it's called the natural language understanding and it basically turns your voice into
text and passes that text back to Lamda and Alamdar then decides how to respond.
So when you using alecks are you speaking to Lamda us speaking to the cloud and we're going to build
Aaron Alexis skill in a few lectures coming up.
So what are my exam tips for LAMDA.
Well remember that lammed scales out not up automatically so it will scale out so you can have millions
of functions running in parallel at the same time.
But if you run out of memory you need to update the you know the amount of memory that that lambda function
uses and will show you how to do that later on lambda functions are independent.
So one event equals one function.
Lambda is Servilius.
Also remember that it's compute service sometimes that can come up some say which of the following is
a compute service will Lambros the compute service.
What servers services are service.
So things like Lamda things like API gateway things like.
Three things like Dynamo D-B et cetera and things like.
Yes definitely not Servilius.
You can get Servilius Aurora just to further complicate things.
But we'll talk about that a little bit later.
But almost all of our D.S. is is as you know uses servers and things like AC to obviously a service
because it is a physical server and then lambda functions can trigger other ledum functions.
And one event can equal any number of functions.
I just put a variable called X if functions trigger other functions so I could have one event which
triggers a lambda function which then triggers three other lambda functions which each in turn and they
trigger three other lambda functions et cetera.
So you can fan out lambda as well.
Do you remember that architectures can get extremely complicated and it can be starting to get very
difficult to debug.
That's where we use AWOS X-ray to debug what it is that's happening.
So if you're asked to debug lambda which service you should use you're going to use AWOS X-ray and then
remember that lambda can do things globally so you can use it to back up and S-3 bucket to other S-3
buckets etc. it's not stuck in one region.
You can use it all across the AWOS ecosystem.
And then finally no Ulam to triggers.
And again we're going to see this in the console a lot.
You should remember as many lambda triggers as you can because this can be a very popular exam question.
Well that is it.
But this lecture guys if it does seem a little bit complicated don't worry we're going to get our hands
dirty.
I would suggest coming back and watching this as well as the next lecture on API gateway.
Once you've got all your experience and then it will make a lot more sense if you've got the time please
join me in the next lecture to cover off API gateway.
Thank you.