OK.
Hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture we're going to look at API gateway.
Now I'm assuming that some people will know what API is and what API gateway is but not everybody does
know.
And in order to pass your exam you do need to have a good understanding of this going into it.
So I thought I'd start with defining what an API is and if you type in what is an API into Google you're
going to get a whole bunch of very complicated sounding text and you it will take you a while to figure
out what it is it will take quite a bit orating API just stands for application programming interface.
And rather than throwing it sort of heavily technical definitions at you I thought we'd start with something
a lot more simpler.
So I should imagine a restaurant you've got a couple who've gone out to dinner they've looked at the
menu and they know what it is they want to order and then you have a kitchen.
So you have all the chefs in the kitchen in the backend and they're ready to basically go ahead and
make whatever it is the couple want.
The problem is is that the couple doesn't really want to go into the kitchen get the chefs the order
and the chefs don't really want to come out of the kitchen to ask the couples what they want because
they're busy preparing food for other people so how do you solve this issue.
Well of course you have our waiter and I'm sorry for the cheesy images but it will help you remember
it you know as you go forward in life.
So here is our waiter our waiter is essentially an API.
Our waiter basically takes our order from the customer passes that to the kitchen the kitchen then goes
ahead and processes orders.
They get all the wrong ingredients.
They make the salad they make.
You know I don't know the stew or whatever it is the couple have ordered they think give this back to
the waiter who then brings it out to the customer.
So whenever you hear of an API or API gateway I want you to imagine a waiter that will make it a lot
easier to understand what's going on.
So let's look at a more technical examples.
Here we are we have our views and our user wants to go on holiday.
So they go over to a Web site could be Skyscanner dot com could be Expedia.
Both of those customers have a cloggers a big shout out to the team at Skyscanner and Expedia and what
you do is you go in and you enter all your details you enter in what airports you're going to travel
from what airports are you going to travel to what date what class of ticket that you want.
How many tickets that you want.
Et cetera et cetera.
And then what these Web sites do is they go and make a series of API calls could be to the airlines
themselves it could be two hotels could be a combination of all both of them could be car rental companies
et cetera and these you know external companies will process the information request and then they will
send it back to the Web site.
The Web site will then collect all of this and essentially you know make it look pretty and often order
it in relet in terms of relevance of what the user wants.
And by the way this data that's sent back from the airlines or from the hotels or whatever is generally
in the Jason format we have a look at that in a couple of slides.
And basically once the Expedia website or the Skyscanner website or whatever has purchased this data
it then sends it back to the user in nice easy to read hate mail back to the user's browser.
The user will go on and make a choice as to what they want and hopefully have a really good holiday.
So that is how you guys work in real life essentially.
You know you have some Web sites who basically go out and make API calls to a whole bunch of other different
Web sites get the information back and correlate it and then present it back to the user.
So use 80 eyes every single day and you as a user might not know that your web site that you're using.
So let's say it is Expedia or Skyscanner you don't know how many API calls it's making you don't know
to which companies but it is making those API calls on your behalf.
So that's all AP eyes are.
Hopefully that is easy enough to understand.
So let's look at the different types of API and there are many different types.
But the two that are most commonly used we have restful API is now restful API sense though representational
state transfer.
And this is used by about 70 percent of the Internet.
This is a much newer API and it was actually designed to replace another API which we're going to come
to in a second but this is pretty much what everyone uses.
And when you're doing a restful API typically it's going to use Jason.
So we're going to have key value pairs as you can see below.
We then have search API.
Now surp stands for simple object access protocol.
The problem was this has been around since like the late 90s.
Problem is it wasn't actually all that simple so restful API eyes were invented to make it a lot easier
to use than sorry.
And so it uses SML so very similar hatred Timo and use again example of SML down that the bottom.
Now when we're going through and doing the rest of this course we're really going to be focusing mostly
on restful a prize or risk a prize because that is what API gateway runs on.
So what is API Gateway.
Well Amazon API Gateway is a fully managed service that makes it easy for developers to publish maintain
monitor and secure API.
Is it any SCO with a few clicks in the AWOS management console you can create an API that acts as a
front door or as your waita for applications to access data business logic or functionality from your
back in services such as applications running on E.C to code running on lambda or any web application.
So basically allows users to connect into an API or connect into your data and you know you can tell
your way to what it is you want from this particular AWOS account that will then be passed back into
you know any kind of service that supported by API gateway so it could be Lamda could be easy to copy
other services as well.
So let's look at this visually.
We've got our users that using any kind of device that makes a request over to our AWOS environment
to API gateway and then depending on that type of request API gateway can then fold that request to
different services such as lammed or two or dynamo D-B et cetera.
So what can API gateway do.
Well it exposes TTP endpoints to define a risk for API.
So what do we mean by that.
Well let's quickly just go ahead and Virdi S-sh into an AC to instance of not running just to make it
easy.
So let's quickly go ahead and have a look at that.
But first I'm just going to go back to Google.
OK something Google if I quickly just type into Google where the API something like that will get an
API.
Here we go open where the map API and what we're going to do is we're going to make a quick API request
to this API to get the weather in London.
So if you click on API doc you'll be able to scroll down and you'll see examples of API calls or API
open where the map dot org for slushed data for slushed 2.5 for such weather.
And then you've got this little question that little question mark just means you're about to parse
a variable and the variable is Q And that equals London.
So let's go ahead and copy this into a clipboard.
Now I'm in a little easy to instance.
You don't need to fire one up unless you really want to.
But what I'm going to do is I'm going to type in CO.
And then I'm going to paste in that that address and then what I'm going to do is just go ahead and
hit enter.
And we can see that it has given me back some Jason it's basically saying invalid API K please see blah
blah blah blah.
So actually what I'd need to do is sign up.
So I'm just going to quickly sign up and grab an API case I'm going to clear the screen get this command
back up and I'm just going to add in my API key here.
OK so I've added in my API key you can see it's this other variable called app ID and that is my API
key and if I go ahead and hit enter now I get a API response and it's basically giving me the coordinates
in terms of latitude and longitude and it's telling me that the weather is drizzles surprise surprise
surprise.
So let's go back to the slide that we were just on.
So when you say what can API gateway do expose hatred.
And points to define a risk for API.
Essentially what Gateway does is it gives us a GPS address that we can make calls to and then we can
configure how the API responds to those calls.
So if we had a you know weather service perhaps we have a whole bunch of weather data sitting in Dynamo
D-B we can configure API gateway to go and retrieve that information from dynamo d be using the variables
in the Hague.
Oh yes get requests that we just sent.
So that is all it is.
So basically it allows you to serve Ellerslie.
I love that word connect to services like Lamda and Dynamo D-B.
You don't need to worry about running any two instances you can just use API gateway and that will then
connect up to Lamda and Dynamo d Bay and you can send each API endpoint to different targets so you
could have one end point going to Lamda one implant going to dynamite Dubay one endpoint going to AC
2 et cetera et cetera runs very efficiently with very low cost.
It scales effortlessly just like lambdas.
You don't have to worry about auto scaling groups or anything like that.
You can track and control usage by using an API.
As we just saw I was using an API case you can actually track and control usage on API Ickey basis and
you can actually throttle requests to prevent attacks so you can stop people from trying to detox your
API gateway.
You can actually go ahead and throttle API gateway and you can connect to cloud watch to read to log
all requests for monitoring and you can actually maintain multiple versions of your API.
So how do you configure API gateway Well first of all you have to define an API.
This X is basically a container.
You then define resources and nested resources.
Basically you are all paths and for each resource you have to select a supported HDTV method and these
are.
So this could get.
This could be post Skippy delete.
This could be a you know other ones so.
Anything that is supported by any HTP method that supported by API gateway You can also set your security
and you can also choose your targets such as easy to Lamda dynamite D-B et cetera.
It can also set request and response transformations and you can deploy your API to a stage so you can
have Prague's you can have test you can have different stages within your API and it's important to
remember that it uses API Gateway's own domain by default but you can use your own custom domain.
So if people were going in and looking at your code they wouldn't even know that it was an Amazon web
service product.
They could think that it was your own custom domain or your own custom API and it now supports A.W.
a certificate manager so you get free SSL and tell us it's with API gateway if you have bought your
domain using route 53 and you've set that up in certificat manager.
So what is API caching so API caching in a gateway allows you to cache your endpoints response.
So let's say you're sending the same request.
The request has been sent many many times and it's always the same response that caching you can reduce
the number of calls made to your end point and also improve the latency of requests to your API.
So when you enable API caching for a stage API gateway caches a response from your end point for specified
TTL time to live period in seconds.
So let's take an example at a restaurant.
But instead of it being a fancy restaurant let's imagine it as McDonald's.
Now I don't know about you but if you go into McDonald's and you order a cheeseburger or you order a
Big Mac typically those burgers are already made and they are literally behind the person serving use
the person just has to turn around grab the Big Mac all that cheeseburger put it in a bag and give it
to you and boom you've got it.
They don't have to pass the order to the kitchen and the kitchen has to go in and make it.
And the reason for that is because a lot of people ordered cheeseburgers of Big Macs at mcdonalds so
effectively the burgers cashed.
Now if you go into McDonald's and order a salad or maybe you order of Philipe fish burger or something
something that is not commonly ordered.
McDonald's that order is not going to be cashed.
It's going to need the kitchen to go in and make it so the waiter will have to actually pass the order
back to the kitchen wait for the kitchen to build the order and then you know pass it over to back to
the way to and then pass it over to you in your bag.
So API caching is just simply that.
It means that the most commonly used API calls are going to be cached in API gateway for a specified
time to live period or a TTL period.
So let's go ahead and have a look at this visually Sukkur to our users.
They send an API request to API gateway if it doesn't have that request cached it then sends that request
over to the service.
In this case it's Lambda Lambda then returns that response another user It sends exactly the same response
to API gateway.
That response is already being cached and that's been cache for it's time to live.
And it can be returned to the user very very quickly doesn't need to go back and do the same query again
to Lamda.
So we're almost done.
There's a couple one more thing I just need to talk about which is Colazal cross origin Brazos sharing.
Before we do that let's talk about same arge and policy so in computing we have same origin policy and
it's basically an important concept in the web application security model.
And under the policy a web browser permits scripts contained in a first web page to access data in a
second web page but only if both web pages have the same origin.
And this is done to prevent things like cross-site scripting attacks and it's enforced by web browsers
and it's ignored by tools like postmen and Co.
Now Cross origin Rizzo's sharing all cores is one way that the server at the other end is not the client
code in the browser but can relax the same origin policy as silts away for API gateway to talk to S-3
for example cross origin reserve sharings a mechanism that allows restricted resources to be fonts on
a web page to be requested from another domain outside of the domain from which the first resource was
served.
So this will become important later on we're going to see some examples of cause in the laps going forward.
But just be aware that cause is definitely a hot exam topic around S-3 and API gateway and we're going
to cover it off in the lab a lot more detail.
But essentially what happens is a browser makes a hasty TDP options call for you arrow and options is
the DP method just like get put and post and the server returns a response that says these other domains
are proved to get this you aro.
And if you ever see the error message origin policy cannot be read at the remote resources it just simply
means that you need to enable calls on an API gateway and we are going to again see this in the labs
coming up.
So that is it for this lecture guys hopefully it made a lot of sense.
Hopefully API and API gateways doesn't seem too scary to you any more.
So what are my exam tips just remember what API gateway is at a high level is the way to who's going
to take your orders to the kitchen and back.
So probably one of the easiest ways to remember it and API Gateway does have caching capabilities to
increase performance.
API gateway is low cost and scales automatically so you don't need order scaling groups or anything
like that with API gateway.
You can throttle API gateway to prevent attacks and you can log results of API or you can log your results
to cloud watch.
So if you are using javascript or Ajax that uses multiple domains with API gateway then you're going
to need to ensure that you have enabled cores on API gateway and cause is enforced by the client.
So that is it for this Lexus.
You know what lander is you now know what API gateway is we are now ready to go ahead and build our
first servo's Web site.
So if you've got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.