Okay.
Hello clunkers and welcome to this lecture and this lecture we're going to build our very first service
web site with Route 53 API Gateway lambda and S3.
Let's have a look at how it's going to work.
We've got our user.
They want to go ahead and get the IP address for help me study AWOL Polycom which is domain I'm about
to register with the route 253.
Route 53 will return that IP address to the user's web browser.
They then want to go ahead and actually get the web page from S3.
So they're going to be able to navigate to that S3 bucket.
It's going to return a web page but the actual web page has static and dynamic content and they need
to get the dynamic content the dynamic content will simply be my name or your name and it will then
their browser will then send a GET request over to API Gateway API Gateway it will then send that over
for that get request on to Lambda Lambda will then respond and then we will send that user's name back
to them.
So really really simple site.
And it's going to use basically three or four different components.
So API Gateway Route 53 S S3 and lambda.
So let's go ahead and get started and log into the obvious console.
The code for this is all in the resources section of the course.
So please download the code now and unzip it.
Okay.
So I'm here in the aid of US console.
Now when we're registering a domain name and using static web sites for in S3 you need to check two
things you need to check that the domain name is available.
You also need to check that the bucket name is available and the bucket name and the domain name have
to be the same.
So I'm going to register help me Polly help me study AWOL Polly dot com first thing I'm going to do
is make sure that's available in S3 you check S3 first because it's free to register bucket names with
domain names it's not free.
So help me study Adobe us Polly dot com and I'm going to create that in the Northern Virginia region
and I'm just gonna go ahead and hit create and that is available so if providers available on Route
53 this is all going to work.
So I'm just going to click in here and I'm gonna go over to properties and I'm going to enable static
web site hosting for this bucket.
So use this bucket to host a Web site.
Quickly just go over and have a look at our code.
So this is where I've unzipped the code.
It's just index dot hated him out an error dot hasty to melt this python is what we're going to use
for our lambda function.
So we're gonna type in here index each temple and then era dot HMO.
We're gonna go ahead and hit save and that has now created our bucket.
Now I can't do anything yet because we do need to edit our code the very next thing I need to do.
I can't upload our Qatar S3 bucket yet because I'm going to need to put in my API Gateway endpoint into
that code at some point.
Okay so that is now an S3 static website bucket.
The next thing we need to do is go over to Route 53 so you go over to services and we scroll down we'll
see Route 53 here under network and content delivery.
And then what I'm going to go ahead and do is going to register this as a domain.
Help me study AWOL is Polly and just check that that's available.
Hopefully it is.
And yes it is.
So you have to make sure that the bucket name is available and the domain name is available if they're
different it's not going to work your bucket name always must be the same as the domain name.
And by that I just mean that this this top level you don't have to have the bucket name with dot com
but the top you know this this level here not top level but then the next level down so help me study
AWOL Polly after I have that is the bucket name as well as the domain name is going to add that to my
cart I'm just gonna go ahead and register this now it's gonna cost me 12 dollars.
This is completely optional if you want to do this or not you can just use the S3 you are all for the
rest of this course if you don't want to spend the money simply go ahead and register this now and just
pause the video.
Okay.
Now have registered that sometimes it says it can take up to three days to complete that really you
know some very rare cases it takes that long usually should have it in about 10 or 15 minutes or sometimes
even less.
So pause the video and just updated it and my helped me study AWOL Polly is now registered so with configured
our S3 bucket as a Web site we have gone in and configured route 53 or bought a domain name and we've
made sure that our bucket name is the exact same as our route 53 domain name including the top level
domain so help me study Polly dot com.
Help me study AWOL Polly dot com.
Next thing we need to do is configure our lambda functions.
Let's go over to services and we'll go into the lambda which is under compute.
If you haven't had a lambda function before you're going to see this splash screen just click on Create
a lambda function.
So we're going to be using this author from scratch later on when we go and build our Alexa skill using
the service application repository so there's three ways of doing lambda functions author from scratch
blueprints which are pre configured templates as a starting point for lambda functions so these are
just lambda functions that are pre configured.
And then we have the service application repository.
And this is basically cloud formation templates that builds service applications automatically for you.
So we're going to use some Alexa service application repository skills later on or at least one.
And if you do are interested in learning more about Alexa development we do have a course on the cloud
guru platform where we'll teach you how to build three skills.
And again we use the service application repository for that as well.
So in here.
Let's call this my server lists Web site.
So that's gonna be our function name gonna be using Python three point six.
If you haven't used lambda before we're going to have to create a new role and the role is essentially
just allowing lambda the permission to execute.
So we'll call this.
I like to call up my lambda role and we're just going to use a policy template and the policy template
you want is simple micros service permissions.
So this allows lambda to execute that's all it does.
So there we go.
Go ahead and hit create function and that should now create our function and we should be ready to go.
Okay.
So my function has now been created.
Now if we scroll down this is the this is what lambda looks like.
So we've got our configuration in here we've got our monitoring.
Here's our designer.
If we scroll down we'll be able to see our function code.
So here's our actual function.
This is an acquisition Amazon made which you used to be called Cloud 9 which is a Integra.
It's basically a cloud integrated development environment or ADT.
So you can actually write your code now directly into lambda which is really really cool.
And what we're going to be doing is we're going to be changing this code here to our own code.
So all we need to do is just go over to where you downloaded your code.
Okay.
So in the directory where I've unzipped my code hopefully you've done that in the resources section.
I'm just gonna go ahead and open that up with my favorite.
Nope.
Yep.
My favorite text editor which is text wrangler on Windows I use Notepad plus plus.
And in here we've got our function.
So basically all you want to do is change the name.
My name at the moment is the body is Ryan Kronenberg.
You want to change this to your own name.
Once you've done that copy it into your clipboard and go back over to lambda and here we are back in
the console.
I'm just going to delete all these lines and paste in my own.
So make sure it is your own name.
Go ahead and click up here and go save and that will now save our function.
If we scroll all the way back up the top we're almost ready to go.
What we need to do is add in our triggers now triggers a really popular exam topics in both Solutions
Architect associate as well as developer associate.
So triggers are API Gateway AWB society.
The Alexa skills care the Alexa smart home cloud front cloud watch events cloud watch logs code commit
cognitive sync trigger dynamo DB can access S3 and S.A. seriously you will probably get a question saying
which of the following is not a lambda trigger c it is worth trying to memorize or memorize all this
going into your exam.
So we gonna add API gateway as a trigger.
It says in here configuration required if you scroll down you can see here configure triggers so it
says we'll set up an API Gateway endpoint will.
Which will trigger your integration.
And in here pick an existing API or create a new one.
We're going to create a new API the API name just enter it in here so I'm going to call my API my server
this website may maybe my service.
Why not website.
And then the deployment stage.
This is going to be in production and in here says configure the security mechanism for your API endpoint.
So do you want it to have IAM.
Do you want it to be open.
Or do you want it to be open but you have to supply an access key before you can use it.
I'm just gonna make mine open and it gives you a warning here saying your API and point will be publicly
available and can be invoked by all users.
That's fine for this particular one.
You could if you wanted a little bit extra security to open with access key but we're not going to keep
this anyway we're going to delete this once we go onto the poly lab anyway so just go ahead and do open.
Go ahead and hit add that has now created our API you click up here and just save your function it's
going to you know save everything so click this little button here we're actually going to get the invoke
U.R.L. you can try copying paste that into your browser but it's not going to work just yet.
So we need to go in and configure what you can do is click on my service web site and that is going
to open up the API Gateway page and you can see or API Gateway is in here.
So what we now need to do is go ahead and configure this.
First thing I want you to note are round the API gateway as this UI and I really like this UI.
Cause it actually helps you visualize exactly what's going on.
You got your client which is our little user.
They're going to send a method request at the moment it could be any but we want to make it only a get.
So they're going to send a get request.
This is then going to be basically proxy it over to Lambda here's our lambda function in here we could
click on this on and open up our lambda function and then that lambda function is going to process that
request and then do a response.
So then going to send that back to API Gateway and API Gateway is going to send a method response back
to our client which will hopefully be our name.
So what we want to do is we're going to change this over to a get request let's just start by deleting
this method.
So I'm gonna go ahead and delete this and then I'm gonna go and create a new method and the method is
going to be a get.
So these these are all our valid email methods.
So I'm going to make mine a get in and click the little tick.
And that's going to give us our setup.
So in here we've got the integration point for a new method.
So what do we want to connect this method to do we want it to be to a lambda function or to hate CTP
do we want to give it a mock response maybe this is a development you know API that we're testing.
Do we want another aided AWOL service.
Do we want to link this into a VPC.
We're gonna select lambda functions and then we're going to use proxy integration.
So we're going to allow it to proxy this across to lambda and here's your region if you actually type
in your function here and it's only going to be the functions that exist within that region.
So make sure you note to the region in which your lambda function exists.
So mine's in USD one click on my services website and I'm gonna go ahead and hit save.
And this then says you're about to give API Gateway permission to invoke your lambda function and here
is the R N of our lambda functions so the Amazon rule resource name of Alameda function going to go
ahead and click Okay.
And that has now set it all up.
So it will be almost ready to go.
And next thing we need to do is go ahead and deploy our API so let's click in here and go deploy deployment
stage.
I'm going to deploy this into production and this deployment description will be my first prod deployment
something like that.
I'm gonna go ahead and hit deploy and you'll see now that we're in stages.
So if you ever need to get back to this screen go over two stages click on prod and then click on get
you will have your invoked you arrow.
So if we click on this we should hopefully be able to get our name and there we go.
It's its API Gateway is triggering a lambda function and lambda function is responding with my name
and you can see it there if you click back and you want to get that you are L again just click on stages
and then prod grab the arrow quickly show you what it looks like as well if we were to do a call command
in you know an easy to instance.
So here I am in an easy to instance I'm just going to CO.
And then that and then I'm going to output it into something like My name dot Tex T.
Let's say.
So if we nano my name dot Tex t there we go we can see it's my easy to instance has called API Gateway.
It has gotten my name and it has then saved that to a text file.
So now that we've done all this we're ready to upload or edit our code and then upload it to S3 so go
to where you downloaded your code.
Case I'm here where I downloaded it my code or we want to do is open up indexed each to mail with our
favorite text editor so Tex wrangler or notepad plus plus.
And so we've opened it up or we need to do is change this line of code here from your API Gateway link
here and just paste in your API Gateway and hit save.
And quickly just go through what it is this code does so it's reached UML.
I've got our header here in our header we've got some of JavaScript which has a function called my function
and then we've got the body in here we've got a header which says hello.
And then it says the ideas my demo cloud gurus and then we've got a button and on click it's going to
execute this function.
And the button says Click me and we're going to end our button.
So the function in here you can see the function basically what we're going to do is a heap TTP request
the TTP request is going to be a get request.
It's going to go to our API Gateway U.R.L. and if it's successful so if the status is 200 then it's
going to display the response and then we've got an image and you'll see what this images at the end
of the lecture it's one of my favorite photos in the whole wide world.
So let's go ahead and save this and go back over to the database console.
So back in the adobe s console I'm going to go over to services and I'm going to go down to S3 which
is under storage so down in here.
So I mean S3 there is a slight UI has changed since I first started recording this.
But if you just scroll down and go to your bucket says help me study Polly.
You can see in here it says objects but and objects are not public.
We need to change that.
You need to click in here and go edit public access settings.
Then you just need to make sure these four checkboxes are unchecked.
Go ahead and hit save and go ahead and hit can type confirm and then that means that objects in this
bucket can now be public.
You see that has changed.
Objects can now be public.
So if you ever have access or if you ever have permissions issues trying to do stuff with S3 make sure
you edit your public access settings.
Let's go ahead and click in this bucket and want to go over to upload.
Going to upload my files so let's add our files in here.
So it's era and index reached here all going I'll go ahead and hit upload and then the very last thing
we need to do is make these public.
So if we just go more and click on make public and make public that will now make our each team able
file public and our index dot each team out and our arrow dot each team all the very last thing we need
to do is we need to go over to Route 53.
So go down to networking Route 53 Route 53 and click on hosted zones and in here I've got my hosting
zones help me study AWB stop poly and I'm going to create a record set and this record set is going
to be an alias record.
So it's just gonna be the naked domain name.
So it's not going to have a W WW or anything like that.
So just click on Alias.
And in here you've got your target.
So if we click in here you should be able to see your S3 Web site in here.
If you can't if it says no targets available it means that your S3 bucket name and your your route 53
a domain name are not the same.
And it does include the top level domain name as well so you do definitely need that.
Let's go ahead and click in here and go ahead and hit create.
And that has now created my my a record and it's an alias and it's pointing back to my S3 Buckets.
The next thing I need to do is just go over to help me study at AWB stop Polly case.
I'm just going to type and help me study Adobe stock Polly dot com and I'm going to go ahead and hit
enter and there we go it says hello cloud gurus.
And it says click me click me that will then send a request off to API Gateway which will trigger a
lambda function which will return the our name back to API Gateway which should hopefully come back
to our browser.
There we go.
Hello Ryan Kronenberg and you might be wondering what this picture is.
This is my favorite photo in this whole wide world so this is my son Ethan.
This is me.
It's the sixth of February 2000 and 18 and that is the Falcon Heavy taking off sending a Tesla to Mars.
So I was lucky enough to take a week off to go see that we're at Cape Canaveral and we watched the Falcon
Heavy which is the world's largest rocket ship.
In terms of thrust take a Tesla into space it's seriously was one of the my favorite days of my whole
life.
So I figured I'd just chuck that up there and we do have any Space X engineers or Tesla engineers watching
the course.
Big shout out to you please tweet me.
Massive fan.
Anyway you have done really really well.
You've taken your first step into a service world.
This was a very very basic Web site.
You can configure it any way that you want.
So before we go on and build our Alexa scale using the service application repository there's one thing
I want to show you which is how to use version control in LAMBDA.
This is a very popular exam topic it will come up an awful lot in your exams.
We're gonna do that and then we're gonna go ahead and build our Lexus skill which uses the service application
repository and we're going to convert our notes using the police service.
Store them in as three and get Alexa to play them.
So if you've got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.