OK.
Hello cloggers and welcome to this lecture this lecture we're going to look at Version control with
LAMDA.
We're just going to look at this before we go ahead and build our search service web site using Poley
and where we will use version control away you should use it in real life is when you're developing
Alexa's skills when you're making changes to your Alexa's skills because if you break something you
can just roll back to a previous version.
So versioning when you use versioning and AWOS lambda you can publish one or more versions of your lambda
functions.
You can have version one version to version 3 et cetera et cetera.
And as a result you can work with different variations of your lambda function in your development workflow.
So you could have development you could have Bayda you could have production et cetera et cetera.
Each lambda function version has unique A R N.
And we'll see that in the lab as we go.
And after you publish a version it's immutable that just simply means it cannot be changed.
You won't be able to go in there and edit it.
The one you can go in and edit will always have that dollar sign latest and the don't sign latest is
basically the most is the latest version of your function.
And again we're going to see that in the AWOS console shortly.
And then we have qualified and unqualified A-R and so basically there's two types of A-R ends when you're
referring to your functions.
Qualified A-R and has if we have a look at and end here we've got our A-R and code hello world and then
we've got the latest that a qualified A and an unqualified A-R and is just the name of the function.
We don't have any version after after it.
So that's all Litta unqualified A-R is.
And then finally with versioning we can create aliases.
So basically an alias is just a name that points to particular version of your function.
So let's say we create version 1 so that we could then create an alias called production and that points
to version 1.
And then what you can do is you can use things like if you are using S-3 or you've got a whole bunch
of other lambda functions you could point to to the production A-R and so be your version name and then
Prod. and then that will automatically map back to the latest one.
Now when you update your latest code let's say you publish version 2 you can then change the mapping
of that alias over to version 2 so that you don't have to go through and update all your functions in
other lambda functions or S3 or whatever it's still using the production alias and all you're doing
is changing the mapping.
And then that way if something does break you can change your alias back from version 2 to version 1
and your code will then work.
So that's what we use aliases for.
We're going to have a quick look at that in the console.
So let's go ahead and get started.
OK here I am in the AWOS.
So go to services and we'll go down to Lamda which is the computer.
It is a compute service and you get the splash screen if you haven't created a function before.
Go ahead and create a new function will call this function my new function or something like that.
You can do it in no.
J.S. it really doesn't matter what the runtime environment you have.
And then I'm going to use an existing roll which is my lambda roll which we created in the lambda lecture.
Go ahead and create the function.
So that has now created the function.
And you can see it in here it just says hello from lambdas from Lambda.
So what we're going to do is we're going to go ahead and create three different versions of this function.
The first one is going to say hello.
So we go here make a change and then I'm going to hit safe.
Now straight away if we click up into qualifiers you'll see two ones you'll see versions and aliases
so we click on versions.
The latest Dala dollar latest version is here.
And you can see here now where this function are in.
And we've got Dala latest at the end.
And this means it is the latest version of function and it's just saying hello.
Now what we want to do is we want to save this as a publish it as a version.
So we're going to publish this as a new two hole version.
You can't go in and make any changes.
So call this version description version 1 and go ahead and hit publish.
And you can see up here version 1 and it's even We've got the error and mine you function.
And at the end we've got the colon and then one and if we actually scroll down you can see the text
in him but we can't go and edit it and it says code handler.
Editing is only available for the latest versions.
Click here to go to latest.
You see up here are Ayran has now changed to latest.
We are now able to go in and edit out code.
So let's go ahead and make a new version.
So Hillary cloud going to hit save.
And then what I'm going to do is going to click in actions publishes a new version.
I'm going to call this version to go ahead and hit publish.
And then finally going to again you can see up here we're now Colan to the end of the hour and can't
go in here make any edits.
I want to go back to my latest version I just click in here on diversions and then what I want to do
is write a third version Geary's say hello cloggers which will now.
My latest one going to go ahead and hit save.
And again I'm going to publish as a new version and I'm going to this version 3.
So there we go publish.
So now we can go back through our different versions so we can look at version 1.
It's immutable so we can edit it just says hello version 2 say hello cloud and then version 3 which
is also our current latest version.
Hello Klau curers.
But we can also go in and have a look at our latest version.
So let's have a look at some aliases.
Go ahead here and go create alias and we can call this one.
Let's say version and then one can't have spaces.
So this is my version 1.
And then we're going to point it at which version.
Well again in point version 1.
Go ahead and hit create.
So now with the alias you can see the actual alias name up here.
Version 1.
And as a way of mapping to our versions that's all alias's are doing then mapping to our versions.
So what you might want to do in the real world is go ahead and create an alias for your latest version.
So let's call this latest version and latest version of my code.
And instead of doing it to version one two or three we're going to point it at latests and then we can
actually reference this in elsewhere in AWOS.
And we know that it's always going to be pointing to the latest version of our code because this is
mapping it to the aliases mapping it to later versions.
So that's how visioning works.
One last thing I should show you.
You can use versioning to create splits between traffic.
So let's say let's say you want to do blue green testing.
Oh and base testing is blue and green deployments.
So say my split traffic something like that.
And so what we're going to do is we're going to send let's say 50 percent to Version 3 which would be
our latest one.
We do 25 percent to let's put in 25 percent.
And you'll note that we can't go in and add an additional version so we can split traffic between our
lambda functions.
It's always going to add up to 100 percent as we decrease one.
The other one will increase.
And one last thing I should point out is you can't do it to the latest version.
So if I go to latest and then additional version 2 and I try and hit create it's going to give us an
error.
So there was an error in creating the alias latest is not supported for an alias pointing to more than
one version.
He can't have the latest in there.
So the way you get round that is you just you know publish all latest as a particular version so version
3 in version 2 20 80 percent and go ahead and hit create.
And there we go we can now split our traffic using this alias.
This is going to split it between two functions and is very important to remember that you can do that
going into your exam.
So what my exam tips.
So my exam tips well you can have multiple versions of lambda functions.
You the latest version will always use the latest as at the end of the foreigns you'll be able to see
it.
Qualified use of versions will use Dala latest unqualified versions will not versions are immutable
so they cannot be changed.
If you do want to make a change you have to basically go in delete the version or republish it and then
you can split traffic using aliases to different versions.
You cannot split traffic with the dollar later.
Instead you need to create an alias to the latest and then basically go in and split the traffic from
them.
So the most important thing to remember is the traffic splitting is definitely an exam topic and you
just basically need to know that it is possible we will use versioning or you should use versioning
in the next lap.
I use versioning for my creating my Lexis skills all the time is definitely worth doing so that way
if you make any mistake in the code and your Aleck's functions doesn't work anymore you can always just
roll back.
So that is it.
But this is like guys if you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move on to the next lecture.
Think.