Hello loggers and welcome to this lecture.
This is one of my favorite lectures and in this lecture we're gonna go ahead and create our own Alexis
skill.
Well we're going to use the AWB as polished service to go in and basically transcribe our notes into
MP 3 files.
We're going to host these empty three files in S. three and then we're going to use Alexa to stream
our MP three files and we'll be using the service application repository.
Now this is all very hands on.
So it's going to teach you how to use the service application repository and how easy it is to build
out Alexis skills so hopefully have an awful lot of fun.
Before we go on to the lecture let's just have a look at how Alexa works.
So this is an Amazon Echo.
Amazon Echo is the name of the hardware for Alexa and essentially you just go in and you say to your
echo Alexa turn on welcome home or Alexa turn on my chill music or Alexa turn on the TV et cetera.
Now in terms of the way it works I'd like to use the example of an iPhone and an iPhone as the hardware.
Siri is the voice service.
So with your Amazon Echo that is the actual physical hardware and Alexa is the voice service.
So that is the way it works.
So sometimes people use echo and Alexa interchangeably but technically speaking Echo is the hardware
and Amazon Alexa is the voice service and you can also change the hardware up so you can use Raspberry
Pi as you can use here at Amazon Echo.
You can use Amazon Fire TV we've got echo dots we've got echo shows and basically the hardware is becoming
more and more prevalent so you can have multiple different devices but they're all using the same voice
service they're all sending information to the aid of U.S. cloud and NWS uses automatic speech recognition
and natural lung language understanding to translate what you're saying in to text.
So it's doing a text to speak translation and essentially what this is then going on is to do is to
go on and trigger a lambda function so literally every single time you use the Amazon Echo in your home
you are speaking directly to lambda and lambda is talking back to you.
So in terms of how we actually go and build out our skills we always start with Lambda.
So we go in and create our lambda function so going to be using the surplus application repository.
And sometimes this is referred to as the skills service.
So this is one half of our of creating our skill.
Then we have to go in and configure the skill interface and this is where we can figure things like
invocation names intent schemas slot types utterances et cetera.
Now we're only going to do this once and it's beyond the scope of this course in order to learn how
to do all this.
And we do have some Alexa courses on the a cloud guru platform and we will have a certification course
coming out on the a cloud platform because there is a new Alexa specialty cert.
So let's go ahead and get started and log into the adobe s console.
Okay.
So here we are in the adobe asset management console.
The first thing we want to do is just go ahead and create an S3 Buckets.
So we're gonna go ahead and create a bucket.
I'm going to call it a cloud guru.
Polly 2019 something like that and I'm gonna go ahead and hit create and that already exists.
So call it a cloud guru.
Polly assets 2019 and go ahead and hit create.
And that has now created my bucket in here I'm going to click in here I'm gonna go edit my public access
settings.
So we do want to make this bucket public.
So I'm gonna go ahead and just type confirm and then we're gonna go and give it a bucket policy making
everything inside it public.
So it's click in here go to our permissions and go to our bucket policy and this will be available in
the resources section of the course.
Just go ahead and copy that into your clipboard and then we're gonna paste it in here and then we're
just going to change the resource a r n.
And we're gonna grab our R and from here.
So just copy that into your clipboard and then go over to here and paste it in and go ahead and hit
save straight away you'll be able to see that the UI has changed saying hey everything in this bucket
is now public.
So going to use this bucket to store our MP three files and we're going to basically take some notes
and then generate MP three files using the poly service.
So go ahead and copy that into your clipboard.
This is the R N for the bucket.
Actually you just need the bucket name.
I don't think you need the IRS and so just copy the bucket name into your clipboard.
And then what we're gonna do I'm gonna go over to services and we're going to go down and find the poly
service so the poly service can be found on a machine learning and you'll see Amazon poly in here and
in here we can go and listen to this.
Now I don't know if you're gonna be able to hear this but I will read any text you typed here and put
in any text and will play it out.
So I'm going to because I'm Australian.
I'm gonna go over to Australia and I like Russell so I'm going to put Russell in here and then what
I want you to do is just paste some notes in here.
Among the easy to landing page you can write your own notes.
I'm just gonna copy this into my clipboard and go back over here in a paste this in here.
So we've basically is just saying Amazon's elastic compute cloud easy to as a web service that provides
I'm not going to read the whole thing too and then what I'm going to do is going to go down and clicked
synthesize to S S3 and in here I'm gonna type in my bucket name so it's a cloud guru Polly assets 2019
and I'm just going to maximise this and I'm gonna go ahead and hit synthesize and so that has now created
a task to synthesize this text into an MP 3 file and if we go down to our S3 synthesis tasks you'll
be able to see here that one is scheduled and this is one that I did earlier and that has had has now
completed.
So it does take a little bit of time can take a couple of minutes if you just hit refresh.
They actually took only a few seconds so that has now completed the task.
If we go back over to S3 we'll be able to see that MP 3 file which is sitting in our public bucket and
there it is there.
Now what we want to do is create an Alexis skill that will start playing these MP three files so you'll
be basically be able to say hey Alexa open study buddy or something like that and then it will read
you out a random AWP as fact.
So help you be able to study.
So let's go over to services and what we're gonna do is we're gonna go over to lambda and we're gonna
go and create a lambda function.
Now I would do this in Northern Virginia if I was you.
You need to do this in a region where the Alexa's triggers are enabled and they're only in certain regions
or around the world.
I think it's definitely Northern Virginia and Ireland.
I think there's one in Sydney but basically you need to do it in a region where the Alexa trigger is
enabled.
So I'm gonna do this in Northern Virginia.
I'm gonna go ahead and create my function.
Now you could go over to blueprints and type in Alexa but if you do that you'll see that they all say
please use the Alexa skills no James fax skill from the service application repository and just says
that for most of these skills.
So let's use the service application repository and these are basically service applications published
by AWB as well as Adobe as partners and other developers and you can just use them for free.
You don't need to know how to go ahead and program.
You can see this today.
Right now there's 434.
And what we're gonna do is we're gonna use the Alexa skills kit.
No J.S. fax skills.
We're gonna select this one.
And then what we're going to do is we're going to just leave everything as default.
And here we've got our permissions we don't need to really do anything here.
So we're just gonna go ahead and hit deploy and this will deploy our Alexis skill to lambda and then
that's it really what we need is the HRN and then we can go ahead and connect this up to the developer
dot Amazon.com.
So in here you can see your applications being deployed you go ahead and click on lambda.
Right now I've got zero lambda functions I would if I go back and just go back into lambda or you could
just refresh a page eventually you'll see that the service has been deployed and then we go that has
now been deployed and this is basically I think it's probably using cloud formation to deploy this out.
So let's go ahead and click in here and we'll be able to see our functions and you can see that we've
got the Alexis skills kit as a trigger so that's because this region supports the Alexis skills kit
as a trigger we scroll down to our IDC we'll be able to see our code.
Now you can go in and customize this.
Essentially this is the message that's going to read out.
So it's here's your fact and then it will this is your help message.
So if you get stuck it will say hey you can tell me a space fact et cetera et cetera.
This is a reprint.
So basically if you invoke the skill and then you just stay silent or say hey what can I help you with.
And then when you say stop it or say goodbye.
And these are your facts here.
So it's randomly going to choose one of these lines and it is completely random and you can add more.
Just make sure that you use these.
You basically use this exact format.
You can go in here and go copy and then you just add it to the very bottom.
You go paste and then let's just add my name as a random fact and we actually use this for all kinds
of purposes like if we have a raffle we just put people's names in.
So in fact in AWB this week we have competitions at the end of every week.
And basically if you answer a really hard question on our Facebook page you could win guru of the week
guru of the week is where you get a free sticker hand side card and T-shirt out to you on the post and
then you're in the draw to win a free ticket to reinvent and at the when we do the draw for reinvent
we use this exact skill and we just put every single person's name in here as different line.
And then we ask Alexa to pick one.
And that's how we draw the winner to reinvent.
So it is complete random.
So we use this skill personally as well.
So that is it.
I'm just gonna go ahead and hit save.
And so that has now saved our skill.
And the only thing you really need to take note of is our HRN.
We're going to need that.
So you just hit that icon and you're gonna need that to be able to create your skill so need you to
go over to developer dot Amazon dot com.
Now just sign up for a developer account.
If you do have an Alexa device make sure you use the same email that is registered to your Alexa device
because then you'll be able to literally use the skills straight away to go over to develop it at Amazon.com.
OK so I've signed into developer dot Amazon.com.
I'm gonna go ahead and hit on Amazon Alexa.
I got to click up here and go over to my skills.
I'm gonna go into my Alexa console and I'm gonna go go ahead and create a skill.
And what's really cool is we can get this skill a name so call it my study buddy something like that.
My study buddy the default language if you are in the UK or Australia or wherever.
Make sure you change this to match the default language on your Alexa device.
So if you are using the Australian one or the UK one change it if you want to keep everything simple.
Change your Alexa over to us.
English US.
I'm gonna leave this as default.
My Lexa is on English us and then we're just going to do custom and self hosted so that's already selected
so all you need to do is click up here and go create skill that will then go ahead and create our skill
and what's really cool is you can choose a template and we've already used the service application repository
for a fact skill and in here we just need to click on this.
That's it.
Go ahead and hit choose.
It is seriously that simple in here.
This is the Alexa development console.
Again if you want to learn more about this we do have an entire course on Alexa in here we've got the
invocation.
So what's the invocation name right now says space facts.
I'm gonna call a cloud layer less to cloud facts something like that.
That might be easy.
And then we're gonna go down and we're going to go ahead and save our model before we build our model.
The only other thing we need to do is go to our end point and inhere.
This is where we give our our skill the R in the lambda a R N so just pasted in there.
And so this is basically pointing our skill to our lambda function.
Once you've done that hits save endpoints then go back over to your get new fact intent.
You don't need to add anything in here but these are your sample utterances.
So you say hey Alexa ask cloud facts a fact or a space fact we might want to change this to a cloud
factor.
In fact let's add that in a cloud fact and gonna hit plus and that adds it to our utterances.
So an utterance is just a way of saying something is going to go ahead and save our model and then we're
gonna go ahead and build our model.
Now the build will take a little bit of time.
I'm just gonna pause the video because it takes a couple of minutes but as soon as it's built you will
see a little notification down here saying that it's done and you can see down here that the build is
now successful.
I could go over to test.
I should be able to test this and we're just going to turn the test on to development and that will
allow us to test and then what we can do is say open cloud facts.
I think it's cloud fact.
Let's have a look.
Here's your fact.
Jupiter has the shortest day of all the planet so it is definitely working.
And over here you can see this is the input and then this is the output.
This is our lambda function talking back to us.
And you can see that it has speak so sort of like h t Mellon that it's actually called SSA SS AML which
stands for synthesis speech markup language so to speak.
Here's your fact.
Jupiter has the shortest day of all the planets and it got that from our lambda function.
If we go back over here what we can do is we can just go through and delete all these other facts.
So if I just go in and delete that so I've only got one fact.
Now if I hit save and then I go back over to my developer console sorry it's over here and I say let's
open cloud fact again and should just read out my now.
Word.
Now we go it just read out my name.
So the last thing we want to do is we want to essentially point our fact to our S3 Buckets to our MP
3 file that Polly just generated so to do that let's go over to services and we'll go over to S3 and
then all you want to do is click on the bucket.
So a cloud guru.
Polly assets click in here and just grab this.
You are allowed to copy that into your clipboard.
Then we want to go back over to our lambda function and we're just gonna go in here and we're going
to add one little edit.
So in here if we scroll all the way down just scroll up so it's easy to see.
We've got we've got our data in here.
So instead of saying Ryan Kronenberg let's go ahead and paste our link in here now to make it talk.
You can see there's an example here.
So it's audio see and then the link.
This is a super useful reference guide to doing stuff with Alexis I'm gonna leave this in the resources
section of the course.
I've got our Euro in here or we now need to do is go audio and then source then equals and we're gonna
do our double quotations and then a forward slash sorry backslash and then we go all the way to the
end and then another backslash and then end quotations and then forward slash and then close it out.
And so then we're gonna go ahead and hit save and that is now save let's go ahead and test this.
So if we go over to here we can go in and just say open cloud fact and hit enter.
And that's there we go.
Russell's reading it out in a Australian accent.
I'm just going to mute it but it is now playing our facts so you can go and use police service to output
all your notes to your S3 bucket and then you can basically so long as you map back the empty threes
here as it as a individually New Line your Alexis skill then read this out to you and to open this up
in your developer account or you need to do is use the invocations you just need to say Alexa open cloud
fact.
So that is it for this lecture everyone.
I hope you had an awful lot of fun.
Like I said on the cloud guru platform we have heaps of different videos to show you how to build all
kinds of different Alexis skills so make sure you check it out in the next lecture early on to go ahead
and have a look at Adobe a step function.
So if you've got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.