Okay.
Hello clunkers and welcome to this lecture.
This lecture we're going to look at step function.
So what are step functions.
Well they basically allow you to visualize and test your surplus applications and they provide a graphical
console to arrange and visualize the components of your applications as a series of steps.
And this makes it easy to build and run multi-step applications step functions automatically trigger
and track each step and retry is when there are errors.
Your application executes in order and as expected.
Step functions logs the state of each step.
So when things do go wrong you can go in and diagnose and debug problems quickly.
There's various ways you can use it.
You can have sequential steps.
This might be where you upload a RAW file and then the next step is to go through and delete that raw
file.
You can be wondering why you do that but that could be one step or you could have a branches of steps.
So let's say you go in and your user selects an image converter and they want to convert that RAW file
to a JPEG or that RAW file to appear.
Or perhaps as an unsupported type if they do convert it to JPA or to PMG that will then load into a
dynamo DP database and then that's the end of your function.
So this is a basically a branching functions there's difference like a tree branch alias different choices
that you can do.
And then of course we've got parallel steps perhaps somebody uploads a photo to an S3 bucket that triggers
a lambda function and then actually goes and triggers three lambda functions one lambda function extracts
the metadata one lambda function resizing the image and one lambda function runs some facial recognition
to try and figure out who it is and then all those lambda functions store that information in your dynamo
DB database.
Now literally for the exam you just need to know what step functions in is what I'm going to do now
is just quickly give you a demo of it.
It's probably the easiest way to learn.
And then we will move on.
So let's go into the obvious console.
Okay.
So here I am in the adobe us console and to get to step functions we just go down to services.
Now it isn't under lambda which is under compute.
It's actually down here and it's under application integration.
You'll be able to see it here step functions.
So go ahead and click on that.
If you scroll down it will tell you a little bit about how it works the way step functions works is
you're using Jason based Amazon states language so it is its own language.
Again don't worry you won't need to learn the language in order to pass the sort of by developer associate
exam you would need to learn it when using step functions however.
So if you are going to go in a new step functions in production you're going to have to go ahead and
learn the language.
Very very simple to get started though.
Just go up here and get started automatically it will drop you into this run a hello world example if
we just go back to state machines you'll be able to see and here we can create our state machines.
So go ahead and hit create a state machine and we're going to do some sample projects and I'm going
to choose one that's a little bit more complicated which is the job polar and this is going to manage
an asynchronous job using a service polling loop.
So it's a combination of NWS lambda and AWOL batch if you click on there and scroll down you'll be able
to see the Jason in here the Amazon states Language ESL is what it's abbreviated to you can see it's
pretty straight forward.
So in here we've got our start and then we've got our different states.
So we've got our submit job state we've then got our wait x second state we've got our get job status
and as you go ahead and complete this it actually draws out this little graph for you as well.
So it's a really good way of visualizing it literally everything as default.
So what this actually does is we've got our start here we're going to submit a job we're going to wait
for 60 seconds we're then going to check the job status and see whether or not it's complete.
If it's not complete we've got our max attempts here.
So essentially it's going to go through and just check again and again.
And then if it's still not complete the job's going to be failed but if the job is completed then we're
going to do this get the final job status and then the whole thing ends.
So that's all essentially it does.
Again you don't need to understand the language in here in order to pass a certified developer associate
exam but you would need to learn your Amazon states language if you were to go on and use this in production.
So let's go ahead and head next in here we're going to go ahead and hit deploy resources and this is
basically just creating a NWS cloud formation stack and it's going to go out and deploy a couple of
lambda functions and set this environment all up for you.
Now this can take up to 10 minutes.
So I'm just gonna pause a video and wait for this to come live.
OK so it has now finished my cloud formation template has now finished you can see our wait time of
sixty seconds in here.
This is basically a new execution.
So we're going to go ahead and execute this if you want to do this multiple times you will need to copy
and paste this and save it somewhere else you might want to save it a text editor.
So I'm just going to call this my test execution and I'm just going to open this in a new browser tab
so I don't lose this code so I'm gonna go ahead and hit start execution that will now start my execution.
You'll be booked you'll be able to watch it in real time here in our visual flow and you can zoom in
zoom out et cetera.
So right now it's at the start submit job that has now successfully gone.
So my lambda function has now successfully submitted my job to actually go to services and go over to
batch.
I'm gonna open this up in a new tab.
We have to be pretty quick to catch it.
But if you click on jobs now I've already missed it.
You could see it in the dashboard anyway so it's in a job queue and it is currently running.
It hasn't failed or succeeded yet.
I'm actually back in my step functions we can see that it is waiting for the full 60 seconds so it is
in progress and then we're going to go through.
It's now just gotten the job status.
The job has now completed and now we're going to get the final job status and figure out whether or
not this has failed or has it passed.
So it's still in progress.
Just going to zoom out a bit so you can see it and just going to pause the video and wait for this to
update.
And there we go.
It has now succeeded so we can see that's all greens and we can actually go down here and have a look
at our execution event history so we can see that it's gone through.
The task has started.
We've got our lambda functions with then weighted with them triggered more lambda functions things all
logs log to club watch logs et cetera et cetera et cetera.
So that is it.
Four step functions.
I'll just quickly show you how to delete it.
So if you go in you can actually go into lambda and have a look at the functions that it's generated.
These step functions here.
There's two of them.
But let's go back over to.
We need to go up is cloud formation and inside cloud formation will be able to see this template.
So step functions go ahead and go to actions and just delete the stack that will then delete all the
associated resources and they will now clean up your w s environment.
So what are my exam tips.
So really you just need to know what step functions are.
They're a great way to visualize your service application.
Step functions automatically triggers and tracks each step and step functions logs.
The state of each step so if something goes wrong you can track what went wrong and where.
You literally just need to know what step functions are.
It's probably worth one or two questions in your exam.
So that is it for this lecture goes.
If you have any questions please let me know.
If not feel free to move onto the next lecture.
Thank you.