OK hello cloggers and welcome to the second last lecture in this section of the course it is going to
be the last lab we are going to learn all about AWOS x ray.
So what is x ray.
Basically it's a service that collects data about your requests that your application serves and it
provides you with tools you can use to view filter and gain insights into that data to identify issues
and opportunities for optimization.
So basically it's a way of visualizing your survivalist list application.
You can see where your performance bottlenecks.
What's causing it to run slow and how you could potentially go in and fix it all just generally what's
going wrong if it's not working for any trace requests to your application.
You can see detailed information not only about the request and the response but also about calls that
your application makes to downstream AWOS resources Micro's services databases as well as HTP web API.
So let's have a look at how it works.
Let's have a look at the architecture.
So you've got to have your application and you're going to have the AWOS X-Rite SDK stored inside your
application.
And basically this SDK sends bits of Jason to the X-ray daemon and this X-Rite daemon can be installed
on Linux PCs Windows PCs as well as OSX.
And essentially what it does is it's listening on UDP and it takes this Jason and then sends it over
to the x ray API and then the x ray API basically stores all this data and then creates the x rays sort
of visualization which you see off to the right.
So we can see here we've got our web app we've got our API So here's our API here.
And then here our our resources inside our applications.
So these are all his school keep a user and we'll go and have a look at this when we do the lab.
So this is one Dynamite's a big table.
This is another dynamo IDB table.
This is another dynamo D-B table.
Over here we've got an S and S Q et cetera and we can see when what's happening when our users are interacting
with the API.
We can see all the different micro services and we can see the actual time that it takes.
So we got 27 milliseconds here 25 milliseconds here.
This one is taking 20 and ninety nine milliseconds to write to the database.
So that's basically how it works.
We also then have our scripts and tools.
So this could be the normal process DKs as well as the CLIA and they communicate either with the date
daemon or with the X-ray API directly.
So in terms of the SDK it provides you with three things it provides you with interceptors to add to
your code to trace incoming Hastey to request client handlers to instrument A.W. SSD case clients that
your application uses to call other AWOS services and a database client to use to instrument calls to
other internal and external hate CTP Web services.
So in terms of integration it actually integrates with the following services so you can have it with
elastic load balances with Lamda with API gateway with easy to and with elastic beanstalk.
We're going to be using beanstalk to deploy our app in this part of the lab.
Just be aware of what languages are supported by X right.
Basically every language that supported by lambda.
So we've got Java go.
No gyrus Python Ruby and dot net.
Those are the current languages supported by X-ray.
OK so the easiest way to learn about X-rays to get our hands dirty so you'll need to go to this link
we have linked it in the resources section but just go to console AWOS to Amazon Dot com for special
lastic things stalk photo slash number and import slash new application.
And then we just want to you posit some data so that the application name is school cape and the solutions
Steck name is Java so you can click on that link.
We should be ready to go.
OK so here I am in the AWOS console I've clicked on the link going to deploy this into northern Virginia.
My application name is going to be school keep my environment in school keep environment one I'm going
to leave the domain blank so that it's automatically generated and we're going to use a preconfigured
platform of Java and we're going to use a sample application.
And what we need to do now is go ahead and hit create application.
Now this can take a little bit of time and I mean probably up to 10 or 15 minutes.
So just be patient.
I'm just going to pause the video while I wait for this location to deploy because that took about five
minutes or so but it has now deployed and it is healthy.
So what we can do is we click up here and that is going to go and open the x ray open up our little
web site and we can now start generating some sample traffic see this as many times as you want.
Then click on this link over the AWOS X-Rite console that will now open up our X-ray console and we
should hopefully see a couple so we can just see one thing at the moment which is our environment.
The reason is we have created an I am roll with that.
When we were using elastic beanstalk.
But the I am roll doesn't have the ability right now to S-3 talk to Dynamo D-B or to use the x ray service.
So in order for this to have more circles.
Oh to see more services what we need to do is just quickly go over to services go down to identity access
management and we just need to go to our roles and we'll be able to see our role in his search.
The AWOS elastic been still easy to grow.
Just go ahead and click on that.
I'm going to add some more policies so we want three more policies we're going to say X-ray X-ray full
access.
Click on that one.
And then we're going to also look for S-3.
So you want as three full access and then we also want Duyne D B and then full access.
So click on all three then go ahead and hit attach policy and that will now attach the S3 dynamo d b
and x ray full access.
If we go back over to x ray.
So let's go over to services.
X-ray is under development tools or find developer tools and go ahead and click on it.
Now if we click on our service map again let's go ahead and generate some more data by going back to
that little web page just clicking on a few times and let's see computing my map.
There we go we can now see that it's talking to S3.
Now this is just a static web site.
This is just a Web site on our easy to instance that's talking to us three.
Why don't we go ahead and upload some code to beanstalk.
And then what we'll do is we'll be able to play tic tac toe.
And every time we do that it's going to store information inside dynamo debate.
And it's also going to send us notifications 3 s and s so the code is in the resources section of the
course.
Once you've downloaded that code just go to upload and deploy.
So here's my file in here.
Eby Java scorekeeper can go ahead and click on deploy.
So that will now upload and deploy my code to the elastic beanstalk environment.
Now this is going to take a fair bit of time.
I'm talking probably 15 to 20 minutes depending on your environment.
So go ahead.
Pause a video.
Sorry I'm going to pause the video but go ahead make yourself a coffee.
Have a break.
And then in 15 minutes time this environment should hopefully be deployed.
OK so lastic big story has now finished and have a look at my logs.
We started it at about 12:12.
So it took all the way up to 12:23 So it took just about 10 minutes in order to do it.
If we click in here we'll be able to get our new you borrow and what we'll be able to do is go ahead
and create a.
Games are going to use user name as well.
All right.
Hello cloggers.
Hello.
Cloud girs out session is games.
I'm going to go ahead and hit create and that will now create our session and our game name will be
cloud Guerrier and the rules tic tac toe.
So go ahead and create.
So that has now created my game going to go ahead and hit play.
And here we go with tic tac toe.
So I'm going to start off here.
Now let's assume someone puts on there I'm going to go here.
They get to go there and I'm going to go here no matter what happens.
I'm going to win because they can't block it twice.
There we go.
I have now won.
Let's go ahead and click on this link here.
You Trace's for this game.
So here these are all our traces and traces are just events that have happened.
And if you want to visualize it you click on service map and it's now computing the map.
This map will have a lot more sort of circles to it because we have allowed I am We've added that I
am policy allowing full access to x ray S-3 Dunham IDB et cetera et cetera.
So we can see in here we've got our different know different tables so this school keep a user school
keep game.
We've got screwed Keep move.
I've got school cape and schools Cape session.
So it has definitely worked.
Now I'm just refreshed the map and you can see here that there has been an error as soon as has not
worked.
So there is an S and S component may take a little bit of time to see this.
So just refresh if you can't yet see as soon as we click in here we can see that we've had a 1 had a
100 percent error rate and the way we did but that is by going back and viewing our traces.
That's what we saw a little bit earlier.
And here we've got our trace list.
So let's go ahead and click on that.
So go to our timeline here.
We can see that scorekeepers had an error and we had 147 milliseconds it was riding to Dynamo d Bay
first it was riding to school Cape game and then to get high school K-8 game.
And then when it tried to do an Asinus publish something to asinus.
It didn't work.
And if you click in here you'll be able to see the actual error and it says use r n et cetera et cetera
is not authorized to perform as soon as publish on results USS And so we're actually having an issue
with our essence.
Q So the way we could troubleshoot this is it's actually in the configuration.
So if we go back over to elastic stalk some back in elastic bands I'm going to go over to configuration
and then I'm going to go over to my software go ahead and modify and it's this IMAO here.
This email address is incorrect.
So what we need to do is just go in here and change it to your email address and then go ahead and hit
apply.
So I want you to do that now a.
That is now updating my elastic beanstalk environment.
I'm just going to post the video and wait for this to finish.
OK that has now finished updating so we can go ahead and test it.
Click here.
I haven't actually subscribed to this topic because I'm actually just curious.
I haven't I haven't accepted the subscription to the Asinus topic because I'm actually curious as to
whether or not x ray will detect that.
So we go ahead and click in here and I'm going to go ahead and just create a game and then that game
I'm going to use the rules tic tac toe hit create then I'm going to go ahead and play it and we'll just
quickly play a game of tic tac toe just clicking randomly.
There we go.
And so that has now finished.
Let's go ahead and view the service map.
So the service map is now loading it can take a little bit of time.
If we just hit refresh it can also take a while for the entire map to update.
I still can't see an s so I'm going to hit refresh again and you might have to do this for a couple
of minutes.
So much just pulls the video on it.
And there we go and see S and S.
Now it's down here and it has gone off as Graines so I didn't need to even subscribe to that S and S
topic but it has triggered the s and s function.
So that is x ray in a nutshell Let's go over to my exam tips actually before we do that I'll just show
you how to terminate this environment.
So you just want to go back over to services and we want to go to a plastic bins which is under compute.
Go ahead and click on that and then here is your environment here.
In order to terminate your environment just go to actions and go to delete application.
Go ahead and delete that interestingly.
This went delete that identity access management role and it went to leaked the S3 bucket.
You will need to delete those yourselves.
But it will delete the easy to instance and the dynamo DB tables.
So what my exam tips around x ray.
So what of my exam tips will understand what x ray is.
Understand that it's a way of visualizing your soulless applications.
I understand what the x ray SDK provides.
So it comes to three things It comes with the interceptors to add to your code to tracing coming HTP
request comes with the client handlers instrument AWOS STK clients that your application uses to call
other AWOS services.
And it also comes with a HTP client to instrument calls to other internal and external TDP Web services.
Understand what it integrates with so integrates with elastic load balance Alamdar API gateway E.S.
to an elastic beanstalk.
And then finally just remember what language is supported.
It's basically all the languages that lambda supports are Java go O.J.'s Python Ruby and dot net.
So that is it for this lecture guys.
The next lecture we've got our very last theory lecture in the coals and then we're going to summarize
everything and then we are done with the civil section of the curve.
So if you got the time please join me in the next lecture.
Thank you.