OK.
Heller cloggers and welcome to this lecture.
This is the very last lecture before our summary lecture.
And we're going to cover off advents API gateway so we covered it off at a very sort of basic level.
There's a few more things you need to know about API Gateway before you go in and do your exams.
The very first one is that you can import API so you can use the API gateway import feature.
And basically you can import swagga to definition files and so you can either create a new API by submitting
a request that includes a swagga definition in the payload.
And in point configuration where you can update an existing API by using a put request that contains
a swagga definition file in the payload and you can update an API by overwriting it with a new definition
or merge a definition with an existing API.
And then you just specify the options using a mode query parameter in the request you Aro Let's have
a look at how he did this in the ABS console.
OK.
So here I am in the U.S. So just go over to services we want API gateway which is going to be and network
and content delivery.
And then if we want to go ahead and create a new API just create API and you can see here that we can
import from a swag of files so you could open up your swagga phone paste it in here or you can go ahead
and select it and then you basically just go forward and configure it as usual.
So if you do have a Swagel file go ahead and try that.
Most important thing too.
I'm not going to go through it in a lot of detail.
Most important thing going into your exam is just to remember that you can import existing API is using
swagga files.
Moving on to API rustlings So Amazon do throstle API gateway and they throttle it two different ways
so you can basically the API gateway limits the steady state requests limit to 10000 requests per second
or up.
Yes.
So you can only have 10000 requests per second on your API gateway.
The maximum number of concurrent requests is 5 0 0 0 0 requests.
And this is across all API is with it.
An AWOS account.
So you don't need to do 10000 over 1 second or 5000 concurrent requests so at the very same time I mean
if you go over the 10000 requests per second or 5000 concurrent requests then you're going to receive
a 8:56 to many requests for a response.
And so let's have a look at some examples.
So in example one we've got 10000 requests in one second but it's spread over the period evenly so 10
requests every millisecond an API Gateway will process all these requests without dropping any because
you are allowed ten thousand in one second if the caller sends 10000 requests in the first millisecond
API gateway is only going to serve 5000 that because you can only have 5000 concurrent requests if a
colos submits 5000 requests in the first millisecond and then evenly spread.
Another 5000 requests through the remaining 999 milliseconds then API Gateway will process all of the
10000 requests in the one second period without returning a 8:56.
So just remember 5000 concurrent requests or 10000 requests per second.
And then finally you can use API gateway as a soap web service passed through us if you do have a older
soap box now sort of API that you've created maybe with your legacy company.
You can definitely configure API gateway to communicate with that service.
The steps on how to do it there's a blog here I'll put it in the link below.
Again it's beyond the scope that this course you just need to understand.
The exam that yes it is possible and if you want to find out how to do it go check out that blog.
So what are my exam tips.
Well like I just said import API is using swagga to definition files API gateway can be throttled and
your default limits ten thousand requests for a second or 5000 concurrently and you can configure the
gateway as a soap web service passed three by the way if you want to lift those throttling limits you
can do that inside API gateway as well.
But you're obviously going to incur further charges so just be aware of that.
So that is it for the whole theory and Lap's for this section of the course in the very next lecture
we're just going to cover up everything we've learnt.
And then you're ready to move on.
So if you've got the time please join me in the next picture.
Thank you.